<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>BusinessDay</title>
	<atom:link href="http://businessdayonline.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://businessdayonline.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 09:42:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Nigeria should not and cannot be dumping ground for foreign imports – Emefiele</title>
		<link>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/nigeria-should-not-and-cannot-be-dumping-ground-for-foreign-imports-emefiele/</link>
		<comments>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/nigeria-should-not-and-cannot-be-dumping-ground-for-foreign-imports-emefiele/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 09:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[OLamiju]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Breaking News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[main story]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://businessdayonline.com/?p=101297</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Just over a year ago, Godwin Emefiele was appointed governor of the central bank of Nigeria, CBN. In a wide ranging interview with Frank Aigbogun, the governor looks back at the last one year and how the bank is responding to the changing global economic environment. How are you dealing with the pressures of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_43520" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://businessdayonline.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/emefiele-cbn.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-43520" src="http://businessdayonline.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/emefiele-cbn.jpg" alt="Emefiele" width="400" height="285" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Emefiele</p></div>
<p>Just over a year ago, Godwin Emefiele was appointed governor of the central bank of Nigeria, CBN. In a wide ranging interview with Frank Aigbogun, the governor looks back at the last one year and how the bank is responding to the changing global economic environment.</p>
<p><strong>How are you dealing with the pressures of the office?</strong></p>
<p>In the life of any man or institution, and as you take on challenges, there will be issues to deal with. These issues are meant to be solved. As managers we are in a situation where we sometimes have to manage crisis because we are also problem solvers. So I can say we are coping well.</p>
<p>The truth is that my two immediate predecessors did an excellent job. Prof. Soludo did a great job through consolidation.  Through Soludo’s efforts, we saw Nigerian banks reaching the very top in West Africa and ranking among the biggest in Africa. Today we see Nigerian banks being among the top 500 in the world by asset size and sometimes profitability depending on how strong the currency is. My immediate predecessor, Sanusi Lamido Sanusi, now the Emir of Kano, came on and in 2009 when we saw the global financial crisis, he did his best. He came up with the reforms that helped to stabilize the financial system and the banking industry. He helped to the extent that the Central Bank could beat its chest and say that during that period no bank depositor lost one naira, and this is because of the brilliant work done by the CBN under Sanusi’s leadership. The CBN naturally has a mandate for price and monetary stability, building reserves and making sure the exchange rate of the country remains very strong.</p>
<p>We are in an era where immediately I came in crude oil prices began to drop. By June 2014 when I took office, the oil price averaged about $114 a barrel and Nigeria’s reserves were around $37bn. By March 2015, however, oil price had dropped to below $50.</p>
<p><strong>What has been the Impact of steep oil price drop on the Naira?</strong></p>
<p>Once the oil price dropped, we saw a situation where people began to make their own prognosis as to what direction they think the country’s exchange rate should go. We have done our best in the circumstance. We saw depreciation in the value of the naira from about N155 to the dollar to about N197 at present, which is almost about 22 percent devaluation. We think that is just right, that it is just appropriate at this time. If you have devalued your currency by about 22 percent in the time period, then you need to begin to look at the question: what else is there to cause of all this, especially at a time or in an era in which you are not optimistic that supply will build because oil prices are still dropping? And if that is the case, that you have adjusted your currency by 22 percent, you have looked at your supply, then what you can only do is what we are trying to do right now, blocking leakages in the system, which is why we have seen our reserves at over $31bn right now.</p>
<p>The third aspect that you have to look at is the demand side because as you well know, price is a result of the interplay between demand and supply. We have depreciated the currency, so if demand remains high then you need to look at it. That is why we started to say: what are the items that we import into Nigeria at this time? Perhaps if the reserve level was as high as $60-80bn at this time, we would not need to look at the issue of currency adjustment. Or if there was the possibility that oil price would rise, you would not have had the need to begin to ask what items we are importing into the country.</p>
<p><strong>How is the importation of petrol feeding into forex demand?</strong></p>
<p>Today we have no choice but to ask: what are we as a nation spending our foreign exchange to import into Nigeria? And yes, our investigation has shown that the importation of petrol products constitutes a significant drag and that is why Mr. President has insisted the refineries must work. Luckily, the plants in Port Harcourt and Warri are beginning to produce and we are also hoping that this month, the one in Kaduna will also begin to work. As this happens, we will begin to refine our products locally and then we can see petroleum products being produced locally. Thus, we expect that from importing about 30-35 million litres daily, we can reduce our import requirement to, say, 15-20 million litres a day. I am also aware that the Federal Government is doing everything possible to see that we completely stop the importation of petroleum products. For instance, I am aware that the issue of 445,000 barrels per day is being addressed to ensure that if we actually do swap, the products going into the swap arrangement are credible and that petroleum products actually come into Nigeria. This will reduce the propensity for foreign exchange demand. If this propensity reduces, it helps our position by reducing demand pressures and helping reserves build up.</p>
<p>But it does not stop at that.</p>
<p><strong>How did the CBN get to the point of putting our a list of items banned from access to forex?</strong></p>
<p>Nigeria, in my view, is one country where, with over 160 million people, we depend entirely on importation. I cannot recall any other nation in the world with a population of over 100 million persons, which has to import everything. We have no food security and that is why the president has said we will focus on agriculture among others. We will focus on the economy.</p>
<p>For us at the CBN, the issue is this: if we are able to tackle importation of petroleum products, what are the other items? That is why the items we placed on foreign exchange exclusion list become potent at this time. Take rice, for instance. Why should we import rice when we know that we can grow it locally? Why should we import rice when we know that across the rice belt in the northern part of this country, hundreds of thousands of metric tonnes of paddy rice are piling up and cannot be sold? So why should we allow the importation of rice by people whose main interest is to plunder this economy, who, to all intents and purposes, are seeking to wreck this economy? Why should we allow the importation of palm oil? In the 1960s and up to the 70s, Nigeria was producing up to 40 percent of the total global volume of palm oil at the time. What happened? The palm trees are still there. Why should we allow palm oil to be dumped in our country?</p>
<p>We need to go back to the question: how do we create jobs? How do we build the entrepreneurial spirit of our people? Those days you had families that had 50 palm trees; there were some that had 100 and some had 200, and this was aside from those in Nigeria who took this as full time business. These 50 heads of palm trees were a source of livelihood to families in Nigeria. When the palm fruits became ripe, they harvested them, processed them and extracted the palm oil and palm kernel, which they sold. Men and children were gainfully engaged because we created jobs for our rural communities and empowered our villagers to feed themselves and send their children to school. Some of us benefitted from this. When the palm oil and palm kernel came to the cities, companies like UAC and PZ purchased them and created jobs and opportunities for the owners and ensured the young ones did not become street urchins. Today, all of that is gone.</p>
<p>So that is what we are saying. It is not just about exchange rate and reserves. It is about the reality that we have a growing rate of unemployment and so, what do we do as a nation? I spoke with the chief executive of a major company in Nigeria last week, who told me he has a younger brother working in one of the small banks in Nigeria. He asked his brother, “What are you doing in this bank? Let me give you some money.” And he advanced this younger brother N10 million. The younger brother went to Aba and bought N9 million worth of palm oil and transported it to Lagos. After selling the palm oil, the young man made a profit of N900,000. That is just one trip. If that young man can do even two trips in a month, that is N1.8m, and if he does two trips per month for one year, that will be a profit of about N22 million in one year. Now think of a profit of N22 million on an investment of N9 million! Can you imagine the way the wealth of this young man would have improved in just one year? That is the multiplier effect we are talking about.</p>
<p><strong>And we once were a textiles giant</strong></p>
<p>Yes, the textiles industry used to be the largest employer of labour in Nigeria. In Kano and Kaduna in the north, we had UNTL, Arewa Textile, Zamfara Textile. In Lagos, textiles giants dominated the entire stretch from Anthony to Oshodi and beyond heading to Apapa, to the right and left sides of the road. You had Afprint, NPEE, Ilupeju Textiles, Dalama Textiles, Aswani Textiles, and they adorned the landscape to our nation’s pride. At Iganmu we had President Textiles and they made the best Guinea brocade in the country in those days. In Ijora we had Sunflag and Spintext Mills. Go to those places today, they have been turned into warehouses for imported rice, imported textiles, imported palm oil, imported eggs, imported beef, imported tomatoes, and so on. Go to the countries where they import these items from and enter their supermarkets, you will not find made-in-Nigeria goods in their shops. It is only in Nigeria that you go to the shops and find made in China, made in South Africa, made in India. And as if that was not enough, they began to dump textiles on our country and we had no way to protect our own domestic industries. We lost those jobs and what did we create in their place? Miscreants on the streets of Nigeria. What you now see is that they not only import those textiles into Nigeria, those foreigners have now set up shops here. Go to Sabon Gari market, Balogun market, China Town market and you will find foreigners selling textiles. So Nigerians cannot even retail textiles anymore. Our young men get out of school and what they do is to become okada riders; university graduates are now Keke (tricycle) drivers. I have attacked and asked: what is toothpick? It is not just about toothpick. I want people to realize this: every item you import into this country from wherever, even if it is one dollar, has its impact on the reserves of the country. With the forests that abound in Nigeria, should we be importing toothpick? Why not bring in the machines they are using to produce this toothpick so we can produce it locally and create jobs? We need a total paradigm shift because we certainly cannot continue like this.</p>
<p><strong>Is is not the case that Nigeria is badly in need of better economic, monetary and fiscal policies in a co-ordinated approach?</strong></p>
<p>Yes there is a place for better economic, monetary and fiscal policies. It is exactly for this reason that Mr. President has said government will address power, mining, and agriculture. The government is doing its best to address power etc. The CBN and the deposit money banks have also had to intervene in the matter of power. We got into a situation where we have legacy debts and some banks had lent money to investors who acquired some of these power distribution companies (Discos) and generation companies (Gencos), and that was how our interest came in. We said we would not allow those loans go bad. We then began to ask questions and found that of the 23 generating plants in Nigeria, 20 were gas-fired plants. So we asked the reason for low generation and they said the gas suppliers were being owed. We stepped in, with the regulators and the banks and NNPC and agreed to resolve the debt issue so we could clear the legacy debt along the value chain, and improve on gas supply and pricing and tariff for electricity. The idea is to work around the tariff to ensure that whereas the indigent population is protected by having their electricity tariff pegged, the well-to-dos who live in highbrow and opulent areas, instead of using generators, they can be supplied power and they then pay market rates for the power they consume. When you use a generator, it costs you a minimum of N80 per kilowatt-hour but if you use public electricity today, it will cost you about N20 per kilowatt-hour. So what are we saying? If we can improve on supply, even if you have to pay say N45-50 per kilowatt-hour and you take away the noise and pollution, you will still be saving N35 while enjoying constant electricity. I am aware that power generation and supply to homes and offices has improved significantly recently. We want to see how we can continue to encourage more people to come in to produce power by investing. Eko and Ikeja Discos, for instance, are exploring the option of embedded generation to improve supply. So, to the issue of fiscal and monetary policy, yes, there is coordination today and we are working together and we will get there.</p>
<p><strong>Why has delay arisen in disbursing the power intervention fund?</strong></p>
<p>What happened is that some companies have received their payment. Yes, the fund has not been fully disbursed but we have paid out about 20 percent (N56bn) of the total to some Gencos and Discos out of almost N213bn. The disbursement was slowed down by the reversal in the tariff and we are working and discussing this matter so we can fully disburse. The regulators, NERC, has told us they did not backtrack on the issue of tariff, that they have sent messages to the Discos to send them what is called a cost-reflective tariff, and once the Discos send this cost-reflective tariff, they will give the approval. We will be meeting with NERC so we can work to remove some of the hiccups along that chain. In matter of three weeks we should see these efforts resulting in total disbursement.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Is the CBN itself setting off alarm by too many policies too soon?</p>
<p>The issue is not as people say. If you are in a plane and you are about to face turbulence, they tell you to belt up. We are in a period that we can say that as a result of the drop in oil prices and fall in reserves, we do not have any other choice but to do what we are doing right now. What I have said is this: if you think you have alternatives, give us your advice as to what we should be doing. The reserves are coming under pressure, people just sit down in their homes and offices and begin to plot how to mount speculative attacks on the currency. People sit down in their homes and say they prefer to store their value in foreign currency rather than the local currency. The CBN has a mandate to ensure that people store value in the Naira which is the legal tender. The truth is that when you find people engaging in round-tripping, rent-seeking and speculative activities, you will not have any choice but to do what we are doing because as you block one loophole, they are finding another one.</p>
<p><strong>The banks are no longer accepting foreign currency cash deposit. Is this another crisis?</strong></p>
<p>I really wonder why people will not have faith in their country; why people will want to take advantage of the situation we are in as a nation to begin to speculatively attack the currency. If you and I and all other Nigerians prefer to store our value in the dollar or pound, and 170 million people store up their value in dollars, pounds, Yuan, the Chinese currency, there will be chaos. It means you will have spiralling exchange rate, it means you will not have any reserves, and when you do not have reserves, you will have to come and do what we are doing today. In any case, if you go to the UK, you can keep your pound sterling account as a customer, but you cannot carry bags of euro or dollars and say you want to deposit it into your account in the UK; they will arrest you. You cannot go to China to open an account and you are carrying dollars in cash, not wired money into your bank account, because they will arrest you. Similarly, you cannot go to the United States and say you do not want to store your value in dollars and you begin to carry pound sterling in cash all over the place in the name of maintaining an account; they will arrest you. So why should Nigeria have or encourage a policy where people want to store their value in the country in currencies other than the naira? That is the question we need to ask and find answers to.</p>
<p>I am not so sure how the policy of domiciliary accounts came about in Nigeria, but I do know that this was meant to target exporters; it was meant to encourage exporters to receive and repatriate their foreign exchange proceeds. But today, we have seen people, everybody, go to their banks, open a naira account and at the same time open a domiciliary account. What is the purpose? It is for them to convert naira into dollar cash and begin to store them or to collect illicit money, and they think the best way to hide it is to open a domiciliary account.</p>
<p><strong>Will the CBN intervene?</strong></p>
<p>The Central Bank has no hand in whether or not a bank decides to receive cash into domiciliary accounts. The truth, however, is that we support it. In the past banks accepted dollar cash, but they handled small volumes; so they could manage this because it was what they could handle in their daily operations. But what we have started to see is that as a result of the speculative activities, as a result of round-tripping activities, people have resorted to just the business of converting their naira into dollar, this is what we call currency substitution. Today, there is a large volume of foreign currency sitting in the vaults of the banks and the banks cannot handle it. If a bank has a large volume of naira in its vault, what it is allowed to do legally is to bring it to the Central Bank and we credit their account. But if a Nigerian bank today is awash with dollar cash, it cannot bring it to the Central Bank because if it brings it to us, what are we going to do with piles of dollar cash? So the banks have reached the limit of what they can accept and handle and they have started to say they do not need dollar again because this is a non-earning asset; it is useless in their vaults. If they now say they do not want dollar cash, we support them.</p>
<p><strong>What should Nigerians who have to send small sums to children at school abroad now do?</strong></p>
<p>You do not need a domiciliary account to do this. First, it is a shame we got our educational system to the point where our children have to go abroad. If you do the numbers you will be shocked by the amount of money we spend on servicing school fees abroad. The number is obscene and we are working on putting data together. In those days when you wanted to travel and you applied for travel allowance, you got it. That is still in existence. What we are trying to encourage now is to have that money wired into your card instead of giving you traveller’s cheques so you can go and conduct your business.</p>
<p>For the point raised about sending small sums to children in school abroad, such parents are entitled under the current policies to send allowances to their children through the banks. We are not here talking about fees or allowance for a school student here and there; we are talking about those who are stealing or set out to steal and are looking for where to hide their loot. We are currently studying it and I know that today you have more than $1bn in cash sitting in the vaults of the banks, useless paper. I have spoken to some of the banks and what I encourage them to do is to return the money to whoever gave it to them in the first place because it is useless asset and the banks themselves know it. In finance language we call it non-earning asset.</p>
<p><strong>How do you to take out the panic in the banking system today?</strong></p>
<p>I do not think the banks need to panic. It may take them time to manage it, but they will gradually look for ways to empty their vaults of this useless asset. For some it could take up to a year, but in the end they will cope. It is not a general or systemic problem because there are quite a number of the banks that have been very good at treasury management that had a good way of determining the optimal level of foreign currency cash they need for their operations. However, maybe in an attempt to be seen to be receiving deposit from customers, some banks have overdone it and that is why they are going to feel the heat.</p>
<p>As I have already said, the banks have no business receiving foreign currency cash. The legal tender in the US is the dollar. The legal tender in the UK is the pound sterling. In Nigeria we all know we have one legal tender and that is the naira. Nigeria cannot be an exception. We must conduct our business in naira. In the spirit of cashless, the idea of carrying foreign currency cash must stop. It needs to stop. Let us carry out our transactions in a transparent and corrupt-free manner that can be monitored and tracked. I can assure you the CBN will do everything it has to do to very quickly bring about an era in which the dollar or pound sterling cash is no longer being hawked all around Nigeria.</p>
<p><strong>How do you respond to private sector concerns over CBN foreign exchange management?</strong></p>
<p>The Central Bank has a responsibility to do what it is doing. I do not have to seek their approval to do what we are doing simply because Nigeria has no business continuing in what we have been doing that has turned the country into a dumping ground rather than a production economy. I have read some of these concerns you alluded to. They have written to me and I am going to invite them for a meeting so we can engage. But will that engagement lead to a reversal so we can return to our old ways? My answer is no. To repeat, I cannot understand why someone will tell me that palm oil is an intermediate product and so we should allow it come in. I cannot understand why somebody will tell me that cold roll steel is an intermediate product when we know that there are firms in Nigeria producing and converting hot roll steel into cold roll steel, and people want us to continue to import cold roll steel? That will not happen because we will say no, let them go those companies in Nigeria which are already converting the hot roll steel, which they can import, into cold roll steel. Don’t tell me it is an intermediate product. What will it take to import a machine that can convert your hot roll steel into cold roll steel and you create jobs locally for our people? That is what we are saying.</p>
<p><strong>How is the CBN managing to build-up of reserves?</strong></p>
<p>Since President Buhari took office, the government has been saying all leakages must be blocked. Plugging these leakages has to do with the treasury single account. What we are saying is that if you are a revenue-collecting agency of government and you receive naira or dollars, that money should come to the centre, the single treasury account. If you have expenses to incur based on the budget that has been approved for you, the centre will pass on that back to you. It is no longer that you will receive the revenue, keep it, spend it as you wish, exceed your budgetary allocation, and then hand the small change or balance to the government. That is what the pronouncement by the president means and we have benefitted immensely from that. We are beginning to see a change in the way the issue of single treasury account is being handled. Our reserves today stand at $31.5bn and we are working to take them higher as we work to control the appetite of our people for frivolous imports. We see the reserves position improving as we work to turn our country from being so heavily import-dependent to a producing economy.</p>
<p><strong>How is the CBN resolving the issues with the JP Morgan index and the threat?</strong></p>
<p>We have substantially addressed the issues they raised with us but whether they agree with us or not is a different thing. We remain committed to remaining on the index. The twin issues they raised are liquidity and transparency. We have tried as much as possible to be transparent in our dealings in the foreign exchange market. Recall that we closed the official Central Bank foreign exchange window and all transactions that happen today on the foreign exchange window are reflected on Reuters for the whole world to see who is buying and who is selling. We have tried as much as possible within the limits of available resources to provide liquidity for the market. That is why sometime ago we encouraged our people who are doing export to bring in their exports proceeds to deepen the market so that it will not be just the Central Bank supplying the market. So when you ask, I can say to the best of our ability we have met their requirements but whether they agree with us not is the issue.</p>
<p><strong>Many say the situation today is encouraging the banks to engage in round-tripping .</strong></p>
<p>We are watching the banks very closely, conducting investigations, and if we catch any of them round-tripping, the hammer will fall heavily. No bank has been caught yet but our teams of examiners will be going to the banks without them knowing we are coming. We will overcome this and customers should report any banks involved.</p>
<p><strong>Will the lull in the economy result in impairment of bank loans?</strong></p>
<p>I am not happy that people say there is some slowdown in the economy but before responding, let me say that what is happening in Nigeria is not uncommon as most economies in the world are going through the same, except for the US economy and to some extent the UK economy with some fragile recoveries. So, be that as it may, Nigeria is not alone and we are doing our best to provide the condition for more economic activity that will lead to more economic growth. That is why we are saying, let us do things that create jobs here in Nigeria and not to export our jobs abroad.</p>
<p>Now about the banking system and the lull in the economy, we continue to examine the banks. The bank system is perhaps one of the most regulated industries in the world. I am not worried because of the kind of risk-mitigating measures that have been put in place here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/nigeria-should-not-and-cannot-be-dumping-ground-for-foreign-imports-emefiele/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buhari grants guarantee for Azura’s 500mw project</title>
		<link>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/buhari-grants-guarantee-for-azuras-500mw-project/</link>
		<comments>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/buhari-grants-guarantee-for-azuras-500mw-project/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 01:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Our reporter ]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Exclusive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[main story]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://businessdayonline.com/?p=101274</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Construction work on the widely acclaimed 500MW Azura thermal power plant in Edo state is expected to commence next month, after the intervention of President Muhammadu Buhari in what analysts say shows the new leader will have a central place for the private sector investment in pushing his economic agenda. Work on the site had [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><span class="s1">C</span><span class="s1">onstruction work on the widely acclaimed 500MW Azura thermal power plant in Edo state is expected to commence next month, after the intervention of President Muhammadu Buhari in what analysts say shows the new leader will have a central place for the private sector investment in pushing his economic agenda.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Work on the site had been stalled when former president Goodluck Jonathan failed to accede to a request by institutions funding the project, including the World Bank, for the waiver of Nigeria’s sovereign immunity to further de-risk the project. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Former finance minister, Ngozi Okonjo Iweala, who is chairman of the government backed Nigerian Bulk Electricity Trader, NBET, had sent the request to government, following the demand by the promoters of the project who have sought a guarantee that in the event of default in receiving payment for power generated and supplied to the national grid, they are able to put a claim on the Nigerian government. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">However, BusinessDay learnt that the senior government officials consistently declined to grant the request, arguing there was no ground for the government to leave open the window to a potential litigation in the future.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1"> However, BusinessDay learnt from a state governor last night, that one of the senior Federal Government officials involved, demanded a bribe of $20 million before treating the file. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">President Jonathan performed the ground breaking ceremony of the almost $1 billion Azura Power on October 11 last year, to signal the formal commencement of construction at the site of what promised to be Nigeria’s most modern power plant, but a surprise delay by his officials meant that the project and its hope of substantially resolving Nigeria’s power mess were deferred.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Our reporter learnt that following representations made to President Buhari once he took office, he called for the papers, and having reviewed them, the president directed the vice president and the solicitor-general to sign the documents.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><a href="http://businessdayonline.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Azura-power-plant.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-101279" src="http://businessdayonline.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Azura-power-plant.jpg" alt="Azura-power-plant" width="460" height="345" /></a></p>
<p class="p3">
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Governor Adams Oshiomhole of Edo state confirmed the resolution of the matter and described the development as a significant breakthrough worth celebrating. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Oshiomhole said, “those who claim that APC is not working are being put to shame daily. This is a mess created by the PDP government and<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>a president who could not call his own appointees to order. Now president Buhari has demonstrated that the days of impunity are over and change has truly come.” </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">It is unclear yet, how the new administration will handle a similar obstacle on the way of progress on the 1,000MW Mobil gas fired plant in Akwa Ibom. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">The Mobil power plant to be sited in Eket in Akwa Ibom state, has been on the drawing board for almost 20 years, having been first stalled during the Obasanjo administration, when the government failed to open an escrow account to be dedicated to meeting its own obligation. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Our reporter learnt that the team of Mobil officials working on the take-off of the project has since relocated to the United States. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Speaking to BusinesDay in May, the Finance Minister acknowledged the national significance of the projects and confirmed that she had already signed all papers required of her, saying she had nothing to do with the delays. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">According to Okojo Iweala, “Mr President has stepped into the matter and he has asked the vice president to meet the parties to work out a solution and we will be meeting on Monday, in the hope that<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>the parties involved will be able to reach an agreement acceptable to all.”</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Lawyers spoken to by our reporters say the globally acceptable norm is that when a government enters into a proper commercial transaction like that involving NBET, the government usually will accept to waive its sovereign immunity, to show good faith, especially in this particular case in which the government is the main backer and promoter of NBET.</span></p>
<p class="p3">
<p class="p1"><strong><span class="s1">By Our reporter </span></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/buhari-grants-guarantee-for-azuras-500mw-project/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Investors in Afren set to be wiped out</title>
		<link>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/investors-in-afren-set-to-be-wiped-out/</link>
		<comments>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/investors-in-afren-set-to-be-wiped-out/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guy Chazan, FT]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Exclusive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[main story]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://businessdayonline.com/?p=101276</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Nigerian and other investors expecting to retrieve any value from their holdings in Afren, the scandal-hit oil explorer that entered administration last week, are likely to be sorely disappointed. People familiar with the company are predicting its stakes in key assets such as the Ebok and Okoro oilfields in Nigeria will be taken over by [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><span class="s1">N</span><span class="s1">igerian and other investors expecting to retrieve any value from their holdings in Afren, the scandal-hit oil explorer that entered administration last week, are likely to be sorely disappointed.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">People familiar with the company are predicting its stakes in key assets such as the Ebok and Okoro oilfields in Nigeria will be taken over by either the Nigerian government or its local business partners.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">That pessimism is echoed in Afren’s bonds, which are currently trading as low as 2 cents on the dollar, compared with about 40 cents in June.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">“There is a material risk that there might not be much to share at the end of the day,” says Stephane Foucaud, an oil analyst at brokerage FirstEnergy Capital. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Afren’s announcement last Friday that it had begun insolvency proceedings was the denouement of a complex, protracted drama that brought a once promising oil explorer to its knees. The Nigeria-focused company found itself at the eye of a perfect storm, dragged down by a collapsing oil price, corporate governance abuses and a mountain of debt.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">The London-listed explorer had once looked like an African success story. Fields such as Ebok threw off cash, especially when oil was at $100, and retail investors piled into the stock. The company’s market capitalisation grew from $73m when it listed on AIM in 2005 to $2.6bn in March last year.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><a href="http://businessdayonline.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/oil-rig.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-101283" src="http://businessdayonline.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/oil-rig.jpg" alt="oil-rig" width="550" height="366" /></a>0000</p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">“It was seen as a highly credible producer which turned round the perception of Nigeria,” said one western energy banker.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Last year, the company’s prospects dramatically changed. In July the board suspended chief executive Osman Shahenshah and chief operating officer, Shahid Ullah over “unauthorised payments” that had come to light in an independent review.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">The timing was dire. Afren was heavily in debt, but was just days away from signing a refinancing deal with creditors to relieve some of the pressure on its balance sheet. When the suspicious payments came to light, the banks balked.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">In October, the company announced the results of an investigation by law firm Willkie, Farr &amp; Gallagher, which found that Messrs Shahenshah and Ullah had struck a secret financing deal in October 2013 with Oriental, one of Afren’s Nigerian partners. Oriental had agreed to pay 15 per cent of cash flows from the Ebok field over four years to an entity registered in the British Virgin Islands and controlled by Messrs Shahenshah and Ullah. WFG said the two men used the funds to pay “extraordinary bonuses” to themselves. Afren’s board fired them for gross misconduct.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">A new temporary chief executive, Toby Hayward, was appointed: but he lacked operational experience of the oil industry. “Afren went into a period where the business did not have clear leadership,” said a person familiar with the company.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Mr Hayward started searching for a saviour. Takeover talks were held with Seplat, a Nigerian oil group, but bondholders were reluctant to take the haircut that would have been needed to complete a deal and discussions were abandoned.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Afren’s string of bad news was becoming longer. In January, it admitted it had overstated its reserves in Barda Rash, an oilfield in Iraqi Kurdistan, reducing its highest estimate from 1.2bn barrels to just 250m.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">The share price went into freefall. Having reached 169.30p in late December 2013, by January this year it had fallen to 4.20p. The stock fell again in March when Afren defaulted on a $15m interest payment.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">But later that month, Afren’s fortunes briefly looked as if they might improve. The company agreed a recapitalisation plan with its lenders involving $300m of new funding by the end of June and hired Alan Linn, an oil industry veteran, as its new chief executive.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Boosted by $200m in emergency funding from bondholders, Mr Linn set about trying to right the ship. But he soon discovered Afren’s affairs were in an even worse state than previously thought. The cash crunch had led to project delays, so Afren’s near-term production was set to be much lower than assumed in the business plan that formed the basis of its bailout deal. Last month Afren came clean on the production issue and requested that trading in its shares be suspended.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Shareholders were due to vote in July on a rights issue and the issuance of new shares, key elements of the bailout plan. But Afren called off the vote, and told investors they would have to stump up another $250m to keep the company afloat. They refused.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">“The bondholders had thrown a lot of money at the problem, but just ran out of patience,” said one person familiar with the company.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">By last week, time had run out for Afren. On Friday it called in administrators.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">In a statement it said that discussions with lenders, bondholders and partners had “failed to deliver support for a revised refinancing and restructuring proposal that would result in Afren being able to pay its debts as they fall due”.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Now, investors could be wiped out, say people familiar with the company. Afren’s negotiating position is weak because, unlike its partners, it does not own its underlying assets, instead controlling them through technical service contracts or so-called “farm-in” agreements.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">“If you default in Nigeria, the assets go to the government or to the indigenous partners who have the licence,” said FirstEnergy Capital’s Mr Foucaud.</span></p>
<p class="p3">
<p class="p1"><strong><span class="s1">Guy Chazan, FT</span></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/investors-in-afren-set-to-be-wiped-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Asset managers favour money market mix in N11bn Balanced Funds</title>
		<link>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/asset-managers-favour-money-market-mix-in-n11bn-balanced-funds/</link>
		<comments>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/asset-managers-favour-money-market-mix-in-n11bn-balanced-funds/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Iheanyi Nwachukwu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Exclusive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[main story]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://businessdayonline.com/?p=101277</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Nigerian fund managers shifted focus away from equities in favour of money market instruments in their allocation of over N11billion in Balanced Funds assets, BusinessDay checks have shown. Balanced Fund is a class of Collective Investment Scheme (CIS) which combines a stock component, a bond component and, sometimes, a money market component, in a single [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><span class="s1">N</span><span class="s1">igerian fund managers shifted focus away from equities in favour of money market instruments in their allocation of over N11billion in Balanced Funds assets, BusinessDay checks have shown.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s2">Balanced Fund is a class of Collective Investment Scheme (CIS) which combines a stock component, a bond component and, sometimes, a money market component, in a single portfolio. The hybrid fund sticks to a relatively fixed mix of stocks and bonds that reflects either a moderate or conservative orientation.</span><span class="s3"> </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s4">Analysis of the fund managers’ monthly investment schedule breakdown for June 2015 showed that the recorded bearish nature of the market, along with the not too impressive outings of most quoted companies on the nation’s Stock Exchange in the second half results, may dampen investors confidence in the instruments and </span><span class="s1">consequently provide a haven for the investors in the money market instruments.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s2">The analysts said last night, that contrary to the natural rule of a balanced fund providing investors with a mixture of safety, income and modest capital appreciation, the current negative returns in excess of minus 9 percent returns from the equities. This is making them jittery in their investment in equities, with the attendant preference for mutual funds causing its asset value to rise to N207billion, an increase of N1billion from the preceding week N206 billion.</span></p>
<p class="p3">Some of the Balanced Funds currently under the regulation of the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) are Women Investment Fund, UBA Balanced Fund, Union Trustees Mixed Fund, FBN Heritage Fund, Nigeria Global Investment Fund, Stanbic IBTC Balanced Fund, Indo Nigeria Unit Trust Fund, DV Balanced Fund, Nigeria International Growth Fund, and Nigeria Energy Sector Fund.</p>
<p class="p3"><a href="http://businessdayonline.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Asset-Managers.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-101284" src="http://businessdayonline.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Asset-Managers.jpg" alt="Asset-Managers" width="581" height="386" /></a></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s3">BusinessDay checks on fund managers monthly investment schedule breakdown for June 2015 at the Securities and Exchange Commission revealed that 20.66% of Nigeria Energy Sector Fund was placed in equities, while 78.75% of the balanced fund assets were placed in money market instruments by its fund manager –Sterling Capital Market Limited.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s4">Further checks shows that 64.43% of Indo Nigeria Unit Trust Fund was placed in money market instruments, while 34.69% was in equities and none in fixed income instruments. The fund manager of this balanced fund is Sterling Capital Market Limited.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s5">Also, 16.56% of United Capital Balanced Fund was placed in equities, 18.15% in fixed income instruments, while 65.27% of the same fund was placed in money market instruments. United Capital Asset Management Limited is the fund managers to this fund.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s3">In addition, 46.63% of<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>the Women Investment Fund was placed in equities, 7.11% in fixed income instruments, and 35.40% of the fund’s asset was placed in money market instruments. The Women Investment Fund is managed by Chapel Hill Denham Management Limited.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s4"> CDL Asset Management Limited, the fund managers to Union Trustees Mixed Fund placed 45.33% of the fund in equities, 16.26% in fixed income instruments, while 31.90% was invested in money market instruments.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s3">Notable money market instruments consist of negotiable certificates of deposit (CDs), bankers’ acceptances, Treasury Bills, Commercial Papers, and repurchase agreements (repos).</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s3">Chapel Hill Denham Management Limited, fund managers to Nigeria Global Investment Fund invested 62.20% of the balanced fund asset in equities, 2.93% in fixed income, and 21.60% money market.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s3">Stanbic IBTC Asset Management Limited, the fund managers to Stanbic IBTC Balanced Fund, placed 39.84% of the balanced fund in equities, 2.90% in fixed income instruments, and 56.82% in money market securities.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s3">A balanced fund is geared toward investors who are looking for a mixture of safety, income and modest capital appreciation.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s3">FBN Capital Asset Management Limited, the fund managers to FBN Heritage Fund invested 31.54% of the balanced fund assets in equities, 26.24% in fixed income instruments, and 42.01% of the asset in money market.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s3">In addition, 35.21% of DV Balanced Fund asset was placed in equities, 20.89% in fixed income instruments, while 43.02% of the balanced fund asset was placed in money market by its fund manager –Vetiva Fund Managers.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s3">Analysts at Lagos-based Financial Derivatives Company Limited had noted that as the market remained bearish, investors sought shelter in alternative asset classes.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s3">Currently, at the Nigerian equities market, unimpressive second quarter (Q2) and half-year (H2) results have further helped dampen investor confidence at Customs Street.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s3">As returns from Nigerian equities routed further negative in excess of minus 9 percent, many investors who became jittery sought for haven in mutual funds, causing its asset value rise to N207billion, an increase of N1billion from the preceding week N206billion.</span></p>
<p class="p3">
<p class="p1"><strong><span class="s1">Iheanyi Nwachukwu</span></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/asset-managers-favour-money-market-mix-in-n11bn-balanced-funds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zenith Bank adopts new financial reporting style for half-year</title>
		<link>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/zenith-bank-adopts-new-financial-reporting-style-for-half-year/</link>
		<comments>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/zenith-bank-adopts-new-financial-reporting-style-for-half-year/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Exclusive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[main story]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://businessdayonline.com/?p=101275</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Zenith Bank’s half-year result will be prepared on the basis of  a new financial reporting style recently approved by the bank’s board of directors, according to a source at the Nigerian Stock Exchange (NSE). The board which met last week, is said to have approved a new financial reporting policy, whereby the half-year result would [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Zenith Bank’s half-year result will be prepared on the basis of<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>a new financial reporting style recently approved by the bank’s board of directors, according to a source at the Nigerian Stock Exchange (NSE).</p>
<p class="p3">The board which met last week, is said to have approved a new financial reporting policy, whereby the half-year result would be audited, contrary to past practices where only the full year result was audited before release.</p>
<p class="p3">It is believed that the new reporting style has already been forwarded to the Central Bank of Nigeria (CBN) for approval.</p>
<p class="p3">The market is already excited with the bank’s initiative, which some analysts describe as “a highly welcome development”.</p>
<p class="p3">Zenith Bank is reputed for consistent superior performance.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The bank had grossed N403.4bn in earnings for the financial year 2014, with profit before tax at N119.80bn, while profit after tax stood at N99.46bn, making it the most profitable bank in the country.</p>
<p class="p3">The bank’s total asset stood at N3.76tn, with total shareholders’ funds of N552.64bn, again ranking the bank as the largest money deposit bank in Nigeria and the sixth largest in Africa by shareholders funds. Zenith paid dividend of N1.65 per share for the financial year 2014.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The bank is noted for its strong asset quality with a non-performing loan ratio of 1.8%, which is one of the lowest in the industry.</p>
<p class="p3">The bank’s outstanding service delivery has won numerous international endorsements and awards, including Best Bank in Corporate Governance in Nigeria by Global Banking and Finance (2015), Best Customer Service Bank in Nigeria by Global Banking and Finance (2014) and the Most Customer-Focused Bank in Nigeria by KPMG (2014).</p>
<p class="p3"><a href="http://businessdayonline.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Zenith-Bank-.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-101281" src="http://businessdayonline.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Zenith-Bank-.jpg" alt="Zenith-Bank" width="550" height="344" /></a></p>
<p class="p3">Zenith Bank was recently certified by the British Standards Institution (BSI) on three key ISO (International Standards Organisation) standards namely; ISO22301(Business Continuity Management), 27001 (Information Security Management) and 20000 (IT Service Management).</p>
<p class="p3">By this feat, the bank joins a comity of other global brands with the highly-rated ISO certification; while remaining the first Nigerian organisation to have won the triple.</p>
<p class="p3">Peter Amangbo, Zenith’s group Managing Director/Chief Executive, said the honour stems from a resolve to deepen the customer experience through greater information security and an IT management system that emphasises the protection of the customer and his investments in an increasingly unpredictable business environment”.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/zenith-bank-adopts-new-financial-reporting-style-for-half-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Health sector threatened as pharmaceuticals fight over 20% import tariff</title>
		<link>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/health-sector-threatened-as-pharmaceuticals-fight-over-20-import-tariff/</link>
		<comments>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/health-sector-threatened-as-pharmaceuticals-fight-over-20-import-tariff/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ODINAKA ANUDU]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Exclusive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[main story]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://businessdayonline.com/?p=101278</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Nigeria’s health sector is currently being threatened by a disagreement within the pharmaceutical industry over the possible imposition of a 20 percent tariff on imported drugs. The conflict arises from the ongoing Common External Tariff (CET) which places zero tariff on imported finished drugs but imposes between five and 20 percent duty on imported raw [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><span class="s1">N</span><span class="s1">igeria’s health sector is currently being threatened by a disagreement within the pharmaceutical industry over the possible imposition of a 20 percent tariff on imported drugs.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">The conflict arises from the ongoing Common External Tariff (CET) which places zero tariff on imported finished drugs but imposes between five and 20 percent duty on imported raw and packaging materials.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Local manufacturers, consisting of members of the Pharmaceutical Group of the Manufacturers Association of Nigeria (PMG-MAN), say the five to 20 percent duty on raw and packaging materials is already threatening to destroy 150 local drug makers and an estimated N300 billion investment made so far, in the domestic sector, calling for a review of a the CET to include imposition of 20 percent tariff on imported finished drugs.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">But representatives of overseas pharmaceutical companies in the country, under the aegis of the Association of Nigerian Representatives of Overseas Pharmaceutical Manufacturers (NIROPHARM), disagree, saying that doing so would prevent Nigerians suffering from chronic diseases such as cancer, asthma, heart and kidney diseases, among others, from accessing essential medicines.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">“Whilst it is a development imperative<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>for the Nigerian government to support local manufacturing across all industrial sectors, we affirm that this PMGMAN position, albeit based on an unsubstantiated premise that any additional taxes on the products will be passed on to the patients, should be deemed invalid, as there are more benefits accruable to the wider Nigerian pharmaceutical industry<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>and most importantly Nigerians, if the CET is retained, supported and sustained,” said Lekan Asuni, president, NIROPHARM, at a press conference held yesterday<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>in Lagos.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><a href="http://businessdayonline.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/pharmaceutical-industry.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-101287" src="http://businessdayonline.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/pharmaceutical-industry.jpg" alt="pharmaceutical-industry" width="550" height="331" /></a></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s2">According to Asuni, who is also the managing director of GlaxoSmithKline (GSK) Pharmaceuticals Nigeria Limited, the HS Code 3003 and HS Code 3004 include essential drugs used in the treatment of chronic diseases, which are on the rise among Nigerians (current risk exposure is 10.4 percent), and are currently not produced locally and must then </span><span class="s1">be imported to save lives.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">“For instance, recent evidence-based guidelines for the management of Type 2 diabetes recommend early ‘insulinisation’ for those difficult to control with oral hypoglycaemic. The resultant effect of increasing the taxes is that the approximately over six million Nigerians that will qualify to receive insulin and other life-saving medicines under this guideline will needlessly be paying more for their medications,” he further said.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">While also calling for zero percent tariff on manufacturers’ raw materials, he said manufacturers involved in importation are also engaged in research and development which brings about technology transfer that will be beneficial to the local industry and the economy.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s3">“Let me point out that you do not jumpstart manufacturing by fiat or decree,” said Ike Onyechi, MD, Alfa Ph</span><span class="s1">armaceuticals and Stores.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">“While government must ensur</span><span class="s4">e that manufacturers get their raw materials, I will like to point out some of the drugs in question cannot be produced here for now, owing to low capacity of the local industry,” Onyechi said.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Okey Akpa, chairman, Pharmaceutical Manufacturers Group of the Manufacturers Association of Nigeria (PMG-MAN) said “the CET as it is currently, spells doom for the local industry and could lead to low demand for locally made drugs.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1"> “The lack of demand for locally manufactured medicines as a result of cheap imports, will lead to idle capacity and will negatively impact previous investments in the sector, worth over N300 billion,” Akpa said.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1"> Steve Onya, managing director/CEO, Chi Pharmaceuticals, said<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>the Federal Government should protect local industries by reversing the tariff structure and imposing tariff on imported products, to avoid closure of over 150 drug makers, stressing that there is no place in the world where inefficiency is rewarded.</span></p>
<p class="p3">
<p class="p1"><strong><span class="s1">ODINAKA ANUDU</span></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/health-sector-threatened-as-pharmaceuticals-fight-over-20-import-tariff/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Talking about corporate social responsibility (2)</title>
		<link>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/talking-about-corporate-social-responsibility-2/</link>
		<comments>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/talking-about-corporate-social-responsibility-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Keith Richards]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Columnists]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://businessdayonline.com/?p=101200</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week I reproduced my presentation to the Nigerian Institute of Public Relations on the topic of CSR. Continuing on, I reflected how building a credible CSR programme has its own challenges. I break these into: Selection and definition, Resource and management, Communication, Measurement, Integrity and interference, and CSR overload. Selection and definition. Choose areas [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week I reproduced my presentation to the Nigerian Institute of Public Relations on the topic of CSR. Continuing on, I reflected how building a credible CSR programme has its own challenges. I break these into: Selection and definition, Resource and management, Communication, Measurement, Integrity and interference, and CSR overload.</p>
<p>Selection and definition. Choose areas that meet the necessary criteria and consider when others are already in that space. Select those that are affordable and sustainable. Choose partners with integrity and credibility. Decide, is it marketing or CSR? Cowbell Mathematics Competition meets both criteria but does that reduce its effectiveness as a programme? Ultimately, consumers and communities will judge.</p>
<p>Resource and management. To be effective, senior management need to be engaged and committed. Do they have the time or are they willing to give it? Who is responsible and accountable? Where does the cost sit: in marketing or do you have a separate cost centre/budget? Is it in competition with brand marketing for funds? Does it have a place in the strategic plan or is it just an aside, an add-on?</p>
<p>Communication. Altruism is great – but will your shareholders be so happy unless they see a benefit? So, effective communication is key to engagement. There is no need to hide your light under a bushel. Create the halo effect for shareholders, managers and staff and other stakeholders. Create a sense of pride for all stakeholders. However, remember, credibility will not come from spending N10 million on communicating an event worth just N1 million!</p>
<p>Measurement. How do you know your programme is meeting your corporate objectives? Marketing research tools will test some measures like spontaneous and prompted recall, share of mind, etc. For listed companies NSE performance will also be an indicator. Recruitment and retention of talent will reflect how respected your company has become. There are some genuine awards such as Social Enterprise Report and Awards (www.sera-ng.com) but many are spurious money-making ventures; possibly an opportunity for an LBS and BusinessDay collaboration? Finally, do not discount the impact of word of mouth/anecdotal feedback.</p>
<p>Integrity and interference. It is vital for credibility to avoid internal or external political or other interference. Is donating to a minister’s favourite charity credible CSR? Is “planning gain”, building something to achieve a state’s approval, a legitimate use of CSR? Beware of shareholders who want to hijack for their own interests? Does the CEO have a personal agenda such as political ambition or just ‘big-manism’? A borehole for the chairman’s village might be a good thing to do but it is not credible or sustainable programme in itself.</p>
<p>CSR overload. Remember, you can’t do everything! As your reputation grows you become a magnet for requests and proposals. Many of these will be legitimate and some will be heartbreaking stories that can tempt a CEO into “play God syndrome”. Trying to do too much can ‘blow your budget’ and alienate shareholders. There is safety in sticking to your policy and your budget.</p>
<p>So, having made my point that CSR as an industry is in danger of becoming superficial and losing credibility, the PR industry, which advises client companies, needs to be professional in its approach. While I hope that the content of this presentation will help, it is important to impart on our clients that if their core business is not run responsibly and sustainably, then ultimately no matter what grammar is published, their reputation is at risk.</p>
<p>There were strong contributions following my presentation from the discussants, Prof Sidi Osho of Premier Legacy Foundation and Ken Egbas of SERA and from the floor. Egbas reported that he had visited 610 Nigerian companies in the last few years for SERA and agreed that CSR was beginning to have a credibility issue. He questioned whether many CEOs supported programmes because they wanted to ‘feel good rather than do good’. He noted a trend to spend more on publicizing than actually doing. Ken also cited transparency and adequate documentation as an issue. According to FIRS research, companies spent some N30bn in 2013 on CSR but where were the evidence and the clarity? He felt that Nigerian CEOs were gradually becoming aware of the commercial and not just the social importance of building a reputation as a respected organization but still lagged behind the West. In 1999, according to research, US companies’ reputation was predominantly defined by their brand marketing but by 2013 American consumers defined a company by its behaviour, including attitude towards gender and racial equality, social responsibility, etc.</p>
<p>Prof Osho made several points about the credibility of CEOs and their need to walk the talk. She thought a closer link between foundations and their sponsors should be made with more clarity and documentation. Foundations should be named directly to create a direct link with their founder or sponsor. She found that some CEOs were difficult to engage with and urged greater use of collaboration between private companies and arms of government to create a kind of CSR Public Private Partnership. The latter points triggered some discussion. There was a general consensus that dealing with government agencies proved a problem because of corruption and lack of transparency. Often, private sector CSR is undertaking programmes that should be the responsibility of government, especially in health and education areas. While it was recognized companies have a particular responsibility when investing in developing economies, they cannot be expected to take over the duties of government. The better CEOs become over-burdened by requests and pleas and then are criticised when turning others down.</p>
<p>The general outcome of the discussion could be summarized in the need for increased accountability and documentation and CEO engagement for CSR to attain true credibility in Nigeria. With enough transparency and ‘naming and shaming’ the poor performers who hide their lack of activity or poor core behaviour behind glossy brochures, eventually Nigerian investors and consumers will start voting with their naira and becoming a respected company for ethical and responsible behaviour will reap its just rewards. As of now, we still have a long way to go!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Keith Richards</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/talking-about-corporate-social-responsibility-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dollar republic, delinquent debtors and non-performing economy</title>
		<link>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/dollar-republic-delinquent-debtors-and-non-performing-economy/</link>
		<comments>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/dollar-republic-delinquent-debtors-and-non-performing-economy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Ayorinde]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Columnists]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://businessdayonline.com/?p=101266</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We are back to the infamous name-and-shame era, when Nigerian banks, prodded by the Central Bank of Nigeria, decide to shift the blame of non-performing loans to defaulters alone and resort to publishing their names in the newspapers with a view to shaming them into submission. Chronic defaulters, delinquent debtors and all sorts of names [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>We are back to the infamous name-and-shame era, when Nigerian banks, prodded by the Central Bank of Nigeria, decide to shift the blame of non-performing loans to defaulters alone and resort to publishing their names in the newspapers with a view to shaming them into submission.</div>
<div></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">Chronic defaulters, delinquent debtors and all sorts of names are used to describe the companies, institutions or social establishments whose names have appeared since Monday when deposit money banks started complying with the CBN directive to save the economy by publishing, from August 1, the list of debtors in at least three national newspapers. Banks, discount houses and the nebulous Asset Management Corporation of Nigeria (AMCON), which was created after the 2009 banking crisis with N5trn to buy off non-performing loans (NPLs) from banks, are expected to comply with this CBN directive.</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">It may not look like we are back to the infamous 2009 era when some banks caved in and several bank managing directors were sacked and tried for their complicity in what nearly brought the economy to its knees. But the ominous signs are already there, especially now that there is a huge drop in oil prices and the naira is being systematically devalued against the dollar to stay afloat.</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">The global rating agency, Fitch, had predicted in February that NPLs in Nigerian banks would rise above CBN’s 5 percent limit by the end this year but might not go beyond 10 percent. It was no rocket science since the devaluation of naira amid weak crude oil prices will certainly signal a rise in the volume of NPLs, more so that a huge chunk of the loans are oil and gas-related.</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">Compared to 2009, the figures this time around are lower but not less threatening. Take First Bank Plc, one of the first that published the names of its bad debtors, as case study: 92 companies owe a total of N43.72bn, already classified as non-performing. The first five on the list owe a combined N23bn. Two of those top five are oil and gas companies, with the highest debtor owing N6.883bn.</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">Unity Bank, which was in the news last month over the sacking or supposed resignation of its MD, Henry Semenitari, also released 260 names of debtors with a combined NPL figure of N45.52bn. This is almost twice the amount required for a bank to recapitalize. The situation is similar across the banks – the amount of loans that are not performing is staggering and poses grave danger not only to the banks but to the economy in general, given the gloom in crude oil prices that has resulted in many firms borrowing huge sums that later became bad loans after oil prices fell. </span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">Understandably, the aim of the CBN is to ensure that the industry NPL ratio does not exceed the prudential limit of 5 percent and, of course, to improve the credit culture in the banking industry. But the discussion that is trending all over the country now is the propriety of the name-and-shame method of dealing with loans that have gone bad. Did the similar approach work in 2009 before the government was forced to save the day through AMCON? Has AMCON delivered on its mandate or managed to create a behemoth open to all manner of influences and only managing to rescue a few privileged individuals? Indeed, can conniving credit officers in particular and the whole banking machinery that promotes unsustainable interest loan regime in general be free of complicity in this whole mess?</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">For sure, this is the season of media trials and legal entanglements. Smart lawyers will get juicy briefs. Already, a few of those embarrassed have started to kick, claiming not to owe at all or not to even have any relationship with the said companies. And even though almost N4trn is involved across board, those who know better say the real McCoy are not even listed, which probably explains why some companies with huge NPLs had only one director’s name listed. What happens to others and, in any case, why were the assets collaterals against the loans not published as well?</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">Ostensibly, we are faced with a peculiarly Nigerian factor here and it is clear that the whole truth is yet to be published. However, it is a bit befuddling that a country that seeks a thriving environment for Small and Medium Enterprises as panacea for economic growth is struggling with the management of its credit facility system. And like a friend quipped at the idea of naming-and-shaming: “I owe you, you have seized my collateral; stopped me from having further access to finance; denied me forex, you still shame me so that nobody can touch me and you want your loan repaid?&#8230; You need to share what you are drinking.”</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">But as persuasive as this argument might be, is it admissible in law? Can an emotive outburst withstand the reality of the quarterly publication of loan defaulters as directed by CBN, even if the CBN Act stipulates that banks should provide for bad loans after two years?</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">In all these, it is the astounding weakness of the naira against the dollar that is at the heart of this desperate measure and the man whose capacity is being tested in all these, Godwin Emefiele, the CBN governor, in <i>BusinessDay</i> <span class="aBn" tabindex="0" data-term="goog_932680513"><span class="aQJ">on Monday</span></span> said Nigerian banks are sitting on over $1bn they can’t use. It was an apparently burdened apex banker that expressed such perplexing thoughts, almost falling short of describing Nigeria as a ‘Dollar Republic’ where people have more faith in the dollar than in their own.</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">He is right, though; for just recently, at the height of the profligacy of the immediate past administration, a very wealthy businessman had expressed consternation that there were more dollar notes circulating in Nigeria than in the entire West African sub-region. The USD has become for us the tempting wads that open nearly every door. Whether it’s needed to curry favours from practically every strata of public sector, sent on private jets in dubious arms purchase deals or sprayed at parties, the dollar commands almighty attention.</span></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">Only a few would have suspected that the day of reckoning would come so soon!</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">Now, the dollar is becoming almost like an albatross. Banks are no longer accepting it as cash deposits purportedly to wade off speculative currency substitution. Many categories of importers are precluded from accessing forex and at least on paper, every delinquent debtor is banned from accessing forex and Government Securities markets, all these against the background of untold hardship for those who need forex transfer for genuine reasons, especially for educational causes. It might get worse: reading Emefiele’s lips, there may even be an amendment to how domiciliary accounts are henceforth opened or operated.</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">“Nigerian banks today are awash in dollar cash that they cannot bring to the CBN…. If we were dealing with cash in naira, the banks are allowed to bring excess naira cash and when they do this, we credit their account. We cannot do the same for foreign currencies. It is what we call non-earning asset in banking and it is up to the banks to manage it,” he said.</span></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">What is clear is that the naira is in a bad shape, the economy is in precarious times and Emefiele would have to separate desperate measures that are temporary from a well thought-out policy direction that can save the day. In other words, he would have to dispense with voodoo economics that hangs on the last straw. He must now demonstrate that he is his own man. The temporary gain of N25 that his policy recorded <span class="aBn" tabindex="0" data-term="goog_932680514"><span class="aQJ">on Monday</span></span> when naira rose to N209 at the parallel market had been dramatically lost by yesterday morning when it suddenly dropped to N235. The solution, frankly, can neither be hurried nor artificial.</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">If the economy, like the loans, is not performing, Emefiele must do more than pontificate on how to stabilize the naira. His fiscal policy and the overall economic direction of the government must synchronize and be seen to encourage industry; and, of course, accord the very many bad eggs in the banking system as much sanctions rather than make hapless entrepreneurs, particularly those outside the oil and gas entrapment, the only fall guys.</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><span lang="EN-GB">What must change, to borrow from another concerned gentleman, is the “current banking model that is based on a liability generation strategy, which generates retail deposits and lend to very few, thereby creating a loan portfolio in the hands of a few and in limited industry”.</span></div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Steve Ayorinde</strong></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/dollar-republic-delinquent-debtors-and-non-performing-economy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Strategic thinking about Nigeria’s future</title>
		<link>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/strategic-thinking-about-nigerias-future/</link>
		<comments>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/strategic-thinking-about-nigerias-future/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kingsley Moghalu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://businessdayonline.com/?p=101290</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Nigerians could be forgiven for believing (erroneously) that ours is an incredibly complex country and that governing and taking it to prosperity is nothing short of rocket science. Nothing could be further from the truth. I make these admittedly bold assertions based on a combination of personal experience in international and Nigerian institutions, empirically researched [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nigerians could be forgiven for believing (erroneously) that ours is an incredibly complex country and that governing and taking it to prosperity is nothing short of rocket science.</p>
<p>Nothing could be further from the truth. I make these admittedly bold assertions based on a combination of personal experience in international and Nigerian institutions, empirically researched and established facts, and some insight into the art and science of strategy.</p>
<p>Note that I make reference to “strategic thinking” rather than the more popular phrase “strategic planning”. It is no accident. Why? Because strategy, a constant in war and peace, and in the successful governance and economic management of nations, businesses and even personal affairs, is first and foremost about THINKING before it is about plans. Those who “plan” without thinking deeply will either fail or not succeed to the level of those who think seriously. Thought creates visions, which create possibilities, which in turn create goals. On the basis of these three things, a Big Hairy Audacious Goal (BHAG) can take shape. Plans are then made to achieve this goal, including plans to execute the plan. This should be backed up by the discipline of actual execution of strategy, including process integrity and goal achievement monitoring and measurement. This is how nations, corporations and individuals achieve genuine, sustainable success. The success and prosperity of nations are never accidents.</p>
<p>Let us bring the matter home and down to earth. Nigeria is at an important juncture in its evolution. President Muhammadu Buhari has a historic opportunity. But one senses a tension between two competing impulses in Nigeria today as we wait for PMB to fully unfold his agenda. That tension is between the past, the present and the future, but more between the first and the latter, with the present as a bridge between the two. It is not by accident that, in electing in a keenly contested vote a former military ruler who held office three decades ago, Nigeria had to return to its past in order to forge its future.</p>
<p>Buhari has zeroed in (so far) on combating corruption and recovering stolen funds, on the one hand, and preparing to give Boko Haram a bloody nose, on the other. There is no contention about the importance of security. Nor is there, even, any contention about the importance of combating corruption. But there is some dissonance on the matter of the balance between focusing heavily on probing and punishing past corruption and the task of constructing a future that can take us from being a poor country to a truly wealthy one, from a physical country to a real nation with a common goal and destiny. What is the balance between facing the past and building the future?</p>
<p>Some may view this as a false dichotomy, since in fact there is a link between corruption in Nigeria and the country’s poor economic performance, and the amounts of funds believed to have been stolen over the decades certainly have significance in economic terms beyond morality. But it is a valid question, for the reasons that follow. First of all, accountability, especially for egregious acts of corruption, is necessary as a deterrent against impunity. But beyond this, the truth is that corruption, in the case of Nigeria and horrendous as it is or has been, is only a symptom of two underlying problems. The first is the absence of a real worldview, in which a value system is proactively embedded, and which keeps corruption in check lest it prevents or undermines economic and social progress. The second is the reality that our country’s constitutional and political structure, which birthed the deformed federalism we have today, has blocked both Nigeria’s economic transformation and the emergence of a true national unity in diversity. That unity can be better attained through a manufacture of consent that breeds a sense of justice done and seen to be done. A country in which these two fundamental determinants of societal destiny are suppressed, faces a serious obstacle. That obstacle is more foundational and important than whatever symptoms the “original sin” breeds. This is precisely why politics in Nigeria are not a competition of ideas. Rather, it is a bitterly divisive struggle for power by ethnic nationalities, for the purpose not of a broad-based national progress but that of parochial patronage and client networks. This is the foundation of massive corruption in Nigeria.</p>
<p>For Nigeria to achieve true economic power and fulfill its destiny, we must re-imagine, redesign and reconstruct our country. PMB has enormous political capital, far more than perhaps any other politician in Nigeria that can be deployed to this strategic imperative. Strategic thinking about Nigeria’s future requires, beyond the humdrum yo-yo of daily governance, that we address the following questions. Is the Vision 2020 a real BHAG, and if so, where are we with it? What type of free market economy is best for Nigeria, and how can we move from mere economic growth to economic development? The latter two are not the same thing. Between neo liberalism and a developmental state, which approach will lead us there? How can industrial policy help Nigeria achieve economic complexity and how can we build the “productive knowledge” that is a sine qua non for complexity? How can the combination of a real industrial manufacturing economy, which is what determines the real value of a country’s exchange rate, combine with fiscal policy to incentivize a monetary policy that creates access to real capital at affordable prices? In other words, how can we put capital into our capitalism? At the political level, what type of federalism is best for Nigeria? How will a re-engineered division of powers and responsibilities between federating units and the central government, revenue allocation formula, and derivation principles (“resource control”) of oil and solid minerals bring about a sense of equity and act as incentive to unleash massive economic production and hence transformation? These are the real questions that will determine our future.</p>
<p>To demonstrate why it is important to think strategically about Nigeria’s future beyond the (necessary) fight against corruption, let us look at Rising Asia. In China, Deng Xiaoping began a period of stunning economic transformation in the late 1970s which fundamentally altered China’s communist state to a capitalist one, unleashing the latent productivity of over one billion Chinese. This was a fundamental redesign of the basics on which modern China was established in 1949 by Mao Zedung after a debilitating civil war. Today, China is the world’s second largest economy, set to overtake the United States as the largest in the next two decades. Corruption has risen, along with China’s meteoric ascent, but President Xi Jin Ping is fighting back, with success. But wide scale corruption has not stopped China’s rise, even as it is rightly considered a strategic threat. Why? Because 400 million Chinese have been lifted out of poverty in the past three decades.</p>
<p>Malaysia, with 27 million people is a rising emerging market that, in the early 1960s was well behind Nigeria in terms of economic prospects. Today it is a newly industrialized country with a GDP per capita of $11,000 (compared with Nigeria’s $3,000), foreign reserves of $100 billion, and a sovereign wealth fund with $41 billion in assets. In 1991, then Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir bin Mohammed set a Vision 2020 BHAG in which his country would achieve the status of a self-sufficient industrialized nation by that date. That target has since been met. Manufacturing accounts for 40 per cent of GDP, and Malaysia is the 14h most competitive economy in the world, ahead of Australia, UK, South Korea and Japan in competitiveness. Meanwhile, what about corruption in Malaysia? It hasn’t disappeared, but strong institutions confront the menace. As I write, a special task force is investigating allegations that Malaysia’s current Prime Minister Najib Razak received $700 million from a state investment fund into his personal bank account.</p>
<p>The point from these examples is that facing forward and building our future successfully will take more effort than facing the past. Justice is an irreducible but complex phenomenon. Once it deals with certain categories of past crimes (as opposed to present crimes) such as war crimes or governmental corruption, it all becomes political and prone (rightly or wrongly) to perceptions of selectivity.</p>
<p>The pursuit of accountability for past corruption in Nigeria should be carefully targeted and controlled, building anti-corruption systems and avoiding vendettas. It should be balanced with the need to avoid sapping the energy and focus required to build the future, breeding resentment, and interfering with the even more fundamental futuristic task of manufacturing consent. That is why the Japanese Emperor Hirohito was ultimately not prosecuted in the Tokyo war crimes trials after World War II, because the conquering Allied Powers needed a bridge between Japan’s past as an enemy Axis Power and its future as a new Western ally. As the American scholar-diplomat and statesman, Henry Kissinger so pithily put it: “It is the temptation of war to punish; it is the task of policy to construct. Power can sit in judgment, but statesmanship must look to the future.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Kingsley Moghalu</strong></p>
<p><em>Moghalu, former deputy governor of the Central Bank of Nigeria, is Professor of Practice in International Business and Public Policy at Tufts University’s Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy in Massachusetts, USA and the chairman of Sogato Strategies LLC.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/strategic-thinking-about-nigerias-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dangote Flourmills loses mount as Nigeria consumers retrench</title>
		<link>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/dangote-flourmills-loses-mount-as-nigeria-consumers-retrench/</link>
		<comments>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/dangote-flourmills-loses-mount-as-nigeria-consumers-retrench/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BALA AUGIE]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Company News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://businessdayonline.com/?p=101203</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The recurring loses of Dangote Flour Mills Plc, one the biggest millers in Africa’s largest economy calls for an urgent cost control mechanism, a strategy analysts say will revert the company to the path of profitability as consumers pull back on spending. This strategy is expedient given investors crave for a company that pays steady [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The recurring loses of Dangote Flour Mills Plc, one the biggest millers in Africa’s largest economy calls for an urgent cost control mechanism, a strategy analysts say will revert the company to the path of profitability as consumers pull back on spending.</p>
<p>This strategy is expedient given investors crave for a company that pays steady dividends from profits.</p>
<p>But Dangote Flour Mill may not pay dividends as it posted a loss after tax (PAT) of N9.11 billion in the first nine months through June 2015, from N4.32 billion the previous year, representing a 110.08 percent increase.</p>
<p>The Miller has been recording such losses since September 2012.</p>
<p>The last time it posted profit figure was in 2011 when it ended the year with a profit of N649.07 million.</p>
<p>Dangote Flour’s loss of 2012 coincided with the year Tiger Brand, South Africa largest Food Company bought majority stake in the Nigerian miller.</p>
<p>Due to Dangote Flour’s faltering performance and excess milling capacity, Tiger has impaired the Nigeria miller’s value by ($82 million) which translates to holding company losing half of its investments.</p>
<p>To further exacerbate the already anaemic position of the company is the devaluation of the naira that made imported raw material expensive, insurgency in the north part of the country that crimpled consumer in that region and weak consumer spending stoked by rising inflation and hike in the price of fuel.</p>
<p>Dangote Flour’s sales were down by 11.57 percent to N58.67 billion in 2015 from N66.28 billion the previous year.</p>
<p>The company’s cost to income ratio (CIR) was as high as 0.91 percent, which is higher than the 0.84 percent recorded last year.</p>
<p>This means the company spent 0.91 naira to produce N1 of its product.</p>
<p>Gross profits were also down by 44.47 percent in 2015.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>BALA AUGIE</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://businessdayonline.com/2015/08/dangote-flourmills-loses-mount-as-nigeria-consumers-retrench/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 1.232 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2015-08-06 09:42:55 -->

<!-- Compression = gzip -->