<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Channels Television &#187; Headlines</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.channelstv.com/category/headlines/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.channelstv.com</link>
	<description>Your Home for the News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 20:04:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.9.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Buhari U.S. Visit: Presidency Gives Breadkdown Of Cost And Gains</title>
		<link>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/buhari-u-s-visit-presidency-gives-breadkdown-of-cost-and-gains/</link>
		<comments>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/buhari-u-s-visit-presidency-gives-breadkdown-of-cost-and-gains/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 20:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Donyoh Donney]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2015]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[editorial published by a Nigerian newspaper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[editorial published in the Nigerian Pilot of August 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garba Shehu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nigerian pilot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigerian taxpayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Permanent secretaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the estimate of President Muhammadu Buhari's trip to the U.S.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Senior Special Assistant to the President on Media and Publicity]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.channelstv.com/?p=160125</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The Presidency in Nigeria has expressed dissatisfaction with the content of an editorial published by a Nigerian newspaper about the estimate of President Muhammadu Buhari&#8217;s trip to the U.S. saying the total amount expended on the trip was nothing near 10 per cent of the speculated figure. In a statement by the Senior Special Assistant [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/buhari-u-s-visit-presidency-gives-breadkdown-of-cost-and-gains/">Buhari U.S. Visit: Presidency Gives Breadkdown Of Cost And Gains</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong><a href="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Buhari-John-Kerry-U.S-Nigeria.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-158114 size-medium" src="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Buhari-John-Kerry-U.S-Nigeria-300x161.jpg" alt="buhari" width="300" height="161" /></a>The Presidency in Nigeria has <em><strong>expressed dissatisfaction</strong> with the content of an </em>editorial published by a Nigerian newspaper about the estimate of President Muhammadu Buhari&#8217;s trip to the U.S. <em><strong>saying the total amount expended on the trip was nothing near 10 per cent of the speculated figure.</strong></em></strong></em></p>
<p>In a statement by the Senior Special Assistant to the President on Media and Publicity, Garba Shehu, the Presidency also condemned the alleged claim of the newspaper that the trip achieved nothing.</p>
<p>&#8220;The total cost of the trip to the Nigerian taxpayer was at the most minimal, in line with the policy of this administration to cut waste and extravagance.</p>
<p>&#8220;The benefits of this symbiotic relationship will become more and more evident as the Buhari administration continues to tackle the challenges of corruption, security and the economy,&#8221; the statement read.</p>
<p>The newspaper had put the cost of the visit to the U.S. at 2.2 billion Naira, but the presidency said that it was a lie.</p>
<p>&#8220;Contrary to the newspaper&#8217;s assertions, the total cost of the trip to the Nigerian taxpayer was at the most minimal, in line with the policy of this administration to cut waste and extravagance.</p>
<p>&#8220;In point of fact, the total amount expended on the trip by the Office of the President amounted to nothing near ten per cent of the speculated figure.</p>
<p>&#8220;Owing to the free accommodation provided by the host government, all the personal staff who accompanied the President on the trip received reduced allowances.</p>
<p>&#8220;His son, Yusuf, received neither allowances nor estacode. The five Governors on the trip each paid his own way. Permanent Secretaries who traveled on the delegation did so in accordance with extant rules and none of them exceeded their estacode entitlements.</p>
<p>&#8220;Apart from the Nigerian Pilot&#8217;s mischievous mathematics, it is shortsighted and misleading of the newspaper to have claimed that President Buhari&#8217;s trip to the U.S. achieved nothing,&#8221; the Presidency further stated.</p>
<p><strong>Read the full statement below.</strong></p>
<p>Our attention has been drawn to an editorial published in the Nigerian Pilot of August 2, 2015 and an earlier report in which the total cost of President Muhammadu Buhari&#8217;s recent trip to the U.S. was estimated at N2.2 billion.</p>
<p>It is very sad that in this age of free-flowing information and in this era of CHANGE, a media organisation would make itself available as a vehicle to peddle a lie of such low and ignominious quality.</p>
<p>Contrary to the newspaper&#8217;s assertions, the total cost of the trip to the Nigerian taxpayer was at the most minimal, in line with the policy of this administration to cut waste and extravagance.</p>
<p>In point of fact, the total amount expended on the trip by the Office of the President amounted to nothing near ten per cent of the speculated figure.</p>
<p>Owing to the free accommodation provided by the host government, all the personal staff who accompanied the President on the trip received reduced allowances.</p>
<p>His son, Yusuf, received neither allowances nor estacode. The five Governors on the trip each paid his own way. Permanent Secretaries who traveled on the delegation did so in accordance with extant rules and none of them exceeded their estacode entitlements.</p>
<p>Apart from the Nigerian Pilot&#8217;s mischievous mathematics, it is shortsighted and misleading of the newspaper to have claimed that President Buhari&#8217;s trip to the U.S. achieved nothing.</p>
<p>Nigerian-US relations had suffered severely over the past few years. That relationship has now been reset.</p>
<p>The benefits of this symbiotic relationship will become more and more evident as the Buhari administration continues to tackle the challenges of corruption, security and the economy.</p>
<p>Some of the more immediate benefits of the President&#8217;s trip to the U.S include: the proposed $2.1 billion fund from the World Bank for the re-development of the northeast battered by Boko Haram; $5 billion from US investors in Nigeria&#8217;s agriculture sector; $1.5 billion investment in the Nigerian health sector; and another $5 billion investment from the U.S. in our country&#8217;s power sector.</p>
<p>Also, as things stand at the moment, the embargo on the sale of weapons sales to Nigeria is in the process of being removed.</p>
<p>The trip to the U.S by President Buhari was definitely very successful and beneficial to Nigeria.</p>
<p>Only those rabidly determined to find faults unnecessarily will cook up falsehood in a futile effort to rake up murk where none exists.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/buhari-u-s-visit-presidency-gives-breadkdown-of-cost-and-gains/">Buhari U.S. Visit: Presidency Gives Breadkdown Of Cost And Gains</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/buhari-u-s-visit-presidency-gives-breadkdown-of-cost-and-gains/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buhari Orders Action To Address Aviation Sector Debt Profile</title>
		<link>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/buhari-orders-action-to-address-aviation-sector-debt-profile/</link>
		<comments>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/buhari-orders-action-to-address-aviation-sector-debt-profile/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 18:47:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Williams Osewezina]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binta Bello]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Ministry of Aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Femi Adesina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[International Airport Terminal Buildings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Muhammadu Buhari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria's President]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Permanent Secretary of the Ministry]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.channelstv.com/?p=160120</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Nigeria&#8217;s President, Muhammadu Buhari, has expressed concern over the enormous debt profile of the aviation sector, saying his administration will act quickly to remedy the situation. President Buhari also directed the Ministry of Aviation to speed up all processes and projects relating to the safety and security of Nigeria&#8217;s air transport system. The President gave the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/buhari-orders-action-to-address-aviation-sector-debt-profile/">Buhari Orders Action To Address Aviation Sector Debt Profile</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong><a href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/06/29/buhari-sets-up-economic-council-pledges-to-be-transparent/muhammadu-buhari-president-of-nigeria-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-155447"><img class="alignleft wp-image-155447 size-medium" src="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Muhammadu-Buhari-President-of-Nigeria-300x161.jpg" alt="Buhari on Aviation Sector " width="300" height="161" /></a>Nigeria&#8217;s President, Muhammadu Buhari, has expressed concern over the enormous debt profile of the aviation sector, saying his administration will act quickly to remedy the situation.</strong></em></p>
<p>President Buhari also directed the Ministry of Aviation to speed up all processes and projects relating to the safety and security of Nigeria&#8217;s air transport system.</p>
<p>The President gave the order after a brief by the Federal Ministry of Aviation led by the Permanent Secretary of the Ministry, Mrs Binta Bello.</p>
<p>In a statement by a spokesman for the President, Femi Adesina, President Buhari stressed that the Federal Government had to do something quickly about the debt profile of the aviation sector, as the development had direct impact on safety, security and international respectability.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our airports are the windows through which people see our country. Anybody coming into the country will likely come through the airports.</p>
<p>&#8220;If we cannot secure and maintain our infrastructure, it will reflect very badly on us,&#8221; President Buhari said.</p>
<p>He further directed that counterpart funding for the upgrading of the international airports in Lagos, Abuja, Kano, Port Harcourt and Enugu, should be captured in the 2016 budget.</p>
<p>Mrs Bello told the President that the five new International Airport Terminal Buildings were designed to meet the best international standards.</p>
<p>The five international terminals, she said, could cater for 62 million passengers annually when completed in the first quarter of 2016, with Lagos moving from seven million passengers&#8217; capacity to 25 million, Abuja moving from five million to 16 million, while Kano, Port Harcourt and Enugu, would have the capacity for seven million passengers each.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/buhari-orders-action-to-address-aviation-sector-debt-profile/">Buhari Orders Action To Address Aviation Sector Debt Profile</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/buhari-orders-action-to-address-aviation-sector-debt-profile/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>NNPC Boss Sacks Group Executive Directors</title>
		<link>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/nnpc-boss-sacks-group-executive-directors/</link>
		<comments>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/nnpc-boss-sacks-group-executive-directors/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 17:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bankole Komolafe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[channels television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Channels TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denis Nnamdi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emmanuel Kachikwu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance Directorate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Isiaka Abdulrazak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation (NNPC)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President Muhammadu Buhari]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.channelstv.com/?p=160111</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The new Group Managing Director of the Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation (NNPC), Dr Emmanuel Kachikwu, has commenced a shake-up of the organisation. Dr Kachikwu on Wednesday, August 5, announced a restructuring of the NNPC by cutting down the size of the directorates of the NNPC from eight to four and has appointed new Group Executive [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/nnpc-boss-sacks-group-executive-directors/">NNPC Boss Sacks Group Executive Directors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_160005" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Emmanuel-Ibe-Kachikwu.jpg"><img class="wp-image-160005 size-medium" src="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Emmanuel-Ibe-Kachikwu-300x161.jpg" alt="Emmanuel-Ibe-Kachikwu head of the NNPC " width="300" height="161" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Group Managing Director of Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation (NNPC), Dr Emmanuel Kachikwu.</p></div>
<p><em><strong>The new Group Managing Director of the Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation (NNPC), Dr Emmanuel Kachikwu, has commenced a shake-up of the organisation.</strong></em></p>
<p>Dr Kachikwu on Wednesday, August 5, announced a restructuring of the NNPC by cutting down the size of the directorates of the NNPC from eight to four and has appointed new Group Executive Directors.</p>
<p>The new offices and their heads include, Directorate of Refining and Engineering to be headed by Dr M.K Baru, Mr Denis Nnamdi to take charge of the Directorate of Exploration and Production.</p>
<p>Mr Bankole Komolafe has been appointed Group Executive Director for the Directorate of Commercial and Investment, while Mr Isiaka Abdulrazak will now head the Finance Directorate.</p>
<p>The restructuring and the appointments come weeks after a strong stance from President Muhammadu Buhari to fix the oil sector, rid the sector of rot and probe monies stolen which are said to be flown abroad.</p>
<p>The sack of the GEDs is coming barely 24 hours after he was <a title="President Buhari Appoints New NNPC, NCC Heads" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/president-buhari-appoints-new-nnpc-ncc-heads/">appointed by President Buhari to head the Nation&#8217;s oil corporation</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/nnpc-boss-sacks-group-executive-directors/">NNPC Boss Sacks Group Executive Directors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/nnpc-boss-sacks-group-executive-directors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hundreds Displaced As Flood Destroys 180 Houses In Sokoto, Kaduna</title>
		<link>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/hundreds-displaced-as-flood-destroys-180-houses-in-sokoto-kaduna/</link>
		<comments>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/hundreds-displaced-as-flood-destroys-180-houses-in-sokoto-kaduna/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 17:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amina Ibrahim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chimezie Enyiocha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gonin Gora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gwadabawa Local Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kaduna State]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Karatudu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musa Illalah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Emergency Management Agency (NEMA)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sokoto state]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tudun wada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ungwar Rimi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yobe State]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.channelstv.com/?p=160100</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Reports says hundreds of people in Gwadabawa Local Government Area of Sokoto State in Nigeria&#8217;s North West region have been rendered homeless by flood after a heavy downpour. About 150 houses in several villages are said to have been hit by flood, including the headquarters of Gwadabawa Local Council, but authorities say no life was [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/hundreds-displaced-as-flood-destroys-180-houses-in-sokoto-kaduna/">Hundreds Displaced As Flood Destroys 180 Houses In Sokoto, Kaduna</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_160101" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Sokoto_Flood.jpg"><img class="wp-image-160101 size-medium" src="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Sokoto_Flood-300x161.jpg" alt="Sokoto_Flood" width="300" height="161" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">File photo</p></div>
<p><em><strong>Reports says hundreds of people in Gwadabawa Local Government Area of Sokoto State in Nigeria&#8217;s North West region have been rendered homeless by flood after a heavy downpour.</strong></em></p>
<p>About 150 houses in several villages are said to have been hit by flood, including the headquarters of Gwadabawa Local Council, but authorities say no life was lost in the disaster.</p>
<p>Some of the residents in the areas affected by the flood say their storage for farm produce were also destroyed. They lament how flood waters washed their harvested crops away.</p>
<p>The National Emergency Agency (NEMA) said there have been heavy rains in Sokoto and Yobe States since the early hours of Wednesday, August 5.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, authorities are said to be making efforts at providing relief materials for victims of the disaster as some of them are left to squat with relatives and friends pending when help would come for them.</p>
<p>Similarly in Kaduna State, also in Nigeria&#8217;s north -west region, residents of Kaduna metropolis on Wednesday morning, witnessed an unusual heavy downpour that lasted for over seven hours.</p>
<p>The rainfall also caused massive floods in some parts of the city.</p>
<p>Channels Television&#8217;s correspondent in Kaduna State, Chimezie Enyiocha, reports that the rainfall, which started as early as six O&#8217;clock in the morning and lasted till One O&#8217;Clock in the afternoon, flooded Abubakar Kigo Road New Extension, with over 30 houses submerged.</p>
<p>Some of the affected residents attributed the flood to lack of adequate drainage system, but, however, blamed the State government for their woes.</p>
<p>The area is very close to the popular Kaduna River. It also has a swampy topography, which makes it very easy for water to penetrate people&#8217;s houses whenever there is a heavy downpour.</p>
<p>Although NEMA had advised residents in flood-prone areas, particularly in Abubakar Kigo Road New Extension, Gonin-Gora, Karatudu, Ungwar Rimi and Tudun Wada areas, to relocate before the rains started. The residents have refused to move out due to claims of inability to secure an alternative home without cash back up.</p>
<p>Some residents, whose houses were submerged by flood, have started moving out their property to safer places and it is not certain when they will return.</p>
<p>At a stakeholder&#8217;s sensitisation workshop on flood mitigation on Wednesday, August 5, the North West Zonal Coordinator of NEMA, Musa Illalah, warned of likely water surplus and increase in stream flows that may consequently affect dam storage.</p>
<p>The NEMA Coordinator, who was represented by an official in the agency, Mrs Amina Ibrahim, also warned residents on the negative impact of poor liquid and solid waste management system during the rainy season.</p>
<p>Kaduna is one of the states in Nigeria that were affected by the 2013 flood disaster, with over 500 houses and property worth millions of Naira destroyed during the incident.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/hundreds-displaced-as-flood-destroys-180-houses-in-sokoto-kaduna/">Hundreds Displaced As Flood Destroys 180 Houses In Sokoto, Kaduna</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/hundreds-displaced-as-flood-destroys-180-houses-in-sokoto-kaduna/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Military Reaffirms Commitment To Ending Insurgency In North-east</title>
		<link>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/military-reaffirms-commitment-to-ending-insurgency-in-north-east/</link>
		<comments>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/military-reaffirms-commitment-to-ending-insurgency-in-north-east/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 15:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Williams Osewezina]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boko Haram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colonel Rabe Abubakar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[counter terrorism operations in Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Director of Defence Information (DDI) of the Nigerian Armed Forces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigerian military]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.channelstv.com/?p=160067</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The Nigerian military has reaffirmed its commitment to ending insurgency and other insecurity plaguing the north-east and other parts of the country. The Director of Defence Information of the Nigerian Armed Forces, Colonel Rabe Abubakar, made this reassurance during an interview with a cross section of Defence correspondents who paid him a visit to congratulate [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/military-reaffirms-commitment-to-ending-insurgency-in-north-east/">Military Reaffirms Commitment To Ending Insurgency In North-east</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong><a href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/military-reaffirms-commitment-to-ending-insurgency-in-north-east/rabe-abubakar/" rel="attachment wp-att-160069"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-160069" src="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Rabe-Abubakar-300x161.jpg" alt="Rabe-Abubakar" width="300" height="161" /></a>The Nigerian military has reaffirmed its commitment to ending insurgency and other insecurity plaguing the north-east and other parts of the country.</strong></em></p>
<p>The Director of Defence Information of the Nigerian Armed Forces, Colonel Rabe Abubakar, made this reassurance during an interview with a cross section of Defence correspondents who paid him a visit to congratulate him on his appointment as the new Defence Spokesman.</p>
<p>Colonel Abubakar said that the military was always ready to carry out its constitutional responsibility, as enshrined in the constitution.<br />
He appreciated the media and other well-wishers who have been commending troops in the north east, sacrificing day and night to stamp out terrorism in the area.</p>
<p>The Defence Spokesman also appealed to the general public to be security conscious, stressing that security was everyone’s business and should be treated as such.</p>
<p>Colonel Abubakar solicited public cooperation with the military and other security agencies through volunteering of needed information that would help in the operations against terror, emphasising that “terrorists are anti-human, anti-development and act in desperation and callous manner.</p>
<p>&#8220;They must be identified, pursued and annihilated in line without Rules of Engagement,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>For over five years, counter-terrorism operations have been on in the north-east to end attacks on communities by the Boko Haram militants, who are seeking an end to western education and the establishment of an Islamic State in the region.</p>
<p>Heightened onslaught against the terrorist group yielded results few weeks before Nigeria&#8217;s general  elections, with the military reclaiming some territories that the Boko Haram had taken.</p>
<p>They have resorted to suicide bombing in the region and have killed over 1,000 persons since the new government of Muhammadu Buhari came into office on May 29.</p>
<p>States worst hit are Adamawa, Borno and Yobe in the north-east region.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/military-reaffirms-commitment-to-ending-insurgency-in-north-east/">Military Reaffirms Commitment To Ending Insurgency In North-east</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/05/military-reaffirms-commitment-to-ending-insurgency-in-north-east/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Says Boko Haram May Have Benefitted From Oil Theft Spoils</title>
		<link>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/u-s-says-boko-haram-may-have-benefitted-from-oil-theft-spoils/</link>
		<comments>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/u-s-says-boko-haram-may-have-benefitted-from-oil-theft-spoils/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 14:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Williams Osewezina]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boko Haram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bring Back our Girls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[counter terrorism operations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issa Darrel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judicial Committee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.s Embassy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Congress]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.channelstv.com/?p=159975</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The Boko Haram terrorist group could be beneficiaries of the money made from crude oil theft in Nigeria, members of the United States Congress said on Tuesday. At a meeting with the Bring Back Our Girls group at the U.S. Embassy in Abuja, the Congressmen urged the Nigerian government to curb the flow of the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/u-s-says-boko-haram-may-have-benefitted-from-oil-theft-spoils/">U.S. Says Boko Haram May Have Benefitted From Oil Theft Spoils</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong><a href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/u-s-says-boko-haram-may-have-benefited-from-oil-theft-spoils/issa-darrel/" rel="attachment wp-att-159976"><img class="alignleft wp-image-159976 size-medium" src="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Issa-Darrel-300x161.jpg" alt="Issa-Darrel of U.S. Congress" width="300" height="161" /></a>The Boko Haram terrorist group could be beneficiaries of the money made from crude oil theft in Nigeria, members of the United States Congress said on Tuesday.</strong></em></p>
<p>At a meeting with the Bring Back Our Girls group at the U.S. Embassy in Abuja, the Congressmen urged the Nigerian government to curb the flow of the movement of such monies.</p>
<p>They also stressed the need for the National Assembly to heighten talks on the Boko Haram insurgency and rescue of the Chibok girls.</p>
<p>The dogged Bring Back Our Girls group articulated their stance, backed with a renewed solidarity by the U.S. Congress at the Embassy, something they were hopeful would yield result.</p>
<p>As they sang their usual chant, they called for more efforts to rescue the over 200 girls abducted on April 14, 2014 by members of the Boko Haram sect terrorising communities in Nigeria&#8217;s north-east.</p>
<p>The Congressmen had held talks with President Muhammadu Buhari, the Nigerian military and other government officials on regional security, counter-terrorism efforts and the Boko Haram terrorist group.</p>
<p>At the end of their visit, a press conference was held and the Head of Delegation and a member of the Judicial Committee, U.S. Congress, Issa Darrel, clearly spelt out their thoughts on funding of the Hoko Haram activities, saying that the terrorist group could have benefited from the spoils of crude oil theft in Nigeria&#8217;s south-south region.</p>
<p>The U.S. pledged greater technical support towards curbing insurgency as well as rescuing the Chibok girls.</p>
<p>They also encouraged the National Assembly to heighten talks on security issues.</p>
<p>The visit was another defining moment for the Bring Back Our Girls group who now pin their hopes on the renewed collaboration between the two countries.</p>
<p>A co-convener of the group, Hadiza Bala-Usman, expressed optimism that the support from the U.S. would help in securing the girls&#8217; rescue.</p>
<p>Nigeria has reached the critical point of her insecurity challenge and now looks forward to interventions like this to carve out a new sense of direction in the battle.</p>
<p>On Monday,<a title="U.S. Considers Lifting Arms Ban On Nigeria" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/03/us-considers-lifting-arms-ban-on-nigeria/"> the Congressmen told the Nigerian military that the U.S. had started consideration of the Leahy law</a> to ease restrictions on arms deal with Nigeria, raising hopes that talks between President Muhammadu Buhari and Barack Obama during the Nigerian President&#8217;s visit to the U.S. would yield results.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/u-s-says-boko-haram-may-have-benefitted-from-oil-theft-spoils/">U.S. Says Boko Haram May Have Benefitted From Oil Theft Spoils</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/u-s-says-boko-haram-may-have-benefitted-from-oil-theft-spoils/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Buhari Appoints New NNPC, NCC Heads</title>
		<link>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/president-buhari-appoints-new-nnpc-ncc-heads/</link>
		<comments>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/president-buhari-appoints-new-nnpc-ncc-heads/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 14:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Williams Osewezina]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chief Executive of the Nigerian Communications Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dr. Joseph Thlama Dawha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Executive Vice Chairman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Executive Vice Chairman and General Counsel of Exxon-Mobil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Group Managing Director of the Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Muhammadu Buhari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Muhammadu Buhari has appointed Dr. Emmanuel Ibe Kachikwu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria President]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Professor Umaru Garba Danbatta]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.channelstv.com/?p=159964</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>President Muhammadu Buhari has appointed Dr. Emmanuel Ibe Kachikwu as the Group Managing Director of the Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation (NNPC). After the announcement of his appointment, Dr. Kachikwu said that the work ahead would be very intense. Addressing some other top staff of the corporation, he stressed the need for them to motivate others [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/president-buhari-appoints-new-nnpc-ncc-heads/">President Buhari Appoints New NNPC, NCC Heads</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong><a href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/president-buhari-appoints-new-nnpc-ncc-heads/emmanuel-ibe-kachikwu/" rel="attachment wp-att-160005"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-160005" src="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Emmanuel-Ibe-Kachikwu-300x161.jpg" alt="Emmanuel-Ibe-Kachikwu" width="300" height="161" /></a>President Muhammadu Buhari has appointed Dr. Emmanuel Ibe Kachikwu as the Group Managing Director of the Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation (NNPC).</strong></em></p>
<p>After the announcement of his appointment, Dr. Kachikwu said that the work ahead would be very intense.</p>
<p>Addressing some other top staff of the corporation, he stressed the need for them to motivate others to ensure they give their best to Nigeria.</p>
<p>Dr. Kachikwu, who was the Executive Vice Chairman and General Counsel of Exxon-Mobil (Africa), is to take over from Dr. Joseph Thlama Dawha.</p>
<p>He hails from Onicha-Ugbo in Delta State.</p>
<p>He is a First Class Graduate of Law from the University of Nigeria, Nsukka and the Nigerian Law School.</p>
<p>The new NNPC Chief Executive also has Masters and Doctorate Degrees in Law from the Harvard Law School.</p>
<p>He started his working career with the Nigerian/American Merchant Bank before moving on to Texaco Nigeria Limited from where he joined Exxon-Mobil.</p>
<p>President Buhari has also approved the appointment of Professor Umaru Garba Danbatta as the new Executive Vice Chairman and Chief Executive of the Nigerian Communications Commission.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/president-buhari-appoints-new-nnpc-ncc-heads/">President Buhari Appoints New NNPC, NCC Heads</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/president-buhari-appoints-new-nnpc-ncc-heads/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buhari Seeks Approval of $75 Million World Bank Loan For Edo</title>
		<link>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/buhari-seeks-approval-of-75-million-world-bank-loan-for-edo/</link>
		<comments>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/buhari-seeks-approval-of-75-million-world-bank-loan-for-edo/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 13:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adams Oshiomhole]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[channels television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edo State]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Muhammadu Buhari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria news]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.channelstv.com/?p=159992</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>President Muhammadu Buhari has written to the Senate seeking approval of a $75 million World Bank loan on behalf of the Edo State. &#8220;I am writing to seek the consideration of the national assembly of Nigeria on approval of a request by the Edo state government‎ to obtain a $75 million credit facility from the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/buhari-seeks-approval-of-75-million-world-bank-loan-for-edo/">Buhari Seeks Approval of $75 Million World Bank Loan For Edo</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong><a href="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Adams-Oshiomhole.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-158929" src="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Adams-Oshiomhole-300x161.jpg" alt="Adams-Oshiomhole" width="300" height="161" /></a>President Muhammadu Buhari has written to the Senate seeking approval of a $75 million World Bank loan on behalf of the Edo State.</strong></em></p>
<p>&#8220;I am writing to seek the consideration of the national assembly of Nigeria on approval of a request by the Edo state government‎ to obtain a $75 million credit facility from the World Bank,&#8221; the president wrote in a letter read on the floor of the upper chamber by Bukola Saraki, Senate President, on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&#8220;You may wish to know that the World Bank had approved a Development Policy Programme (DPO) loan budget support for the total sum of $225 million to the Edo State government in 2012 to be implemented in three tranches of $75 million per annum.</p>
<p>&#8220;The first tranche was approved by the National Assembly in the 2012-2014 Federal Government&#8217;s external borrowing plan.</p>
<p>&#8220;The programme has since been successfully implemented by the state in 2014. After the successful implementation, the bank&#8217;s Board of Executive Directors approved the second tranche, which is the DPO 2, on April 29, 2015.</p>
<p>&#8220;The DPO 2 was captured in the Federal Government&#8217;s external ruling borrowing plan of 2014-2017, which is pending with the National Assembly.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is for the above reason that I seek your favour to facilitate the consideration and approval of the Development Policy Operation 2 (DPO2) loan of $75 million to enable the state to consolidate on the first tranche of the operation,&#8221; the letter further read.</p>
<p>The money when converted at 196 Naira to a dollar is 14.7 billion Naira.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/buhari-seeks-approval-of-75-million-world-bank-loan-for-edo/">Buhari Seeks Approval of $75 Million World Bank Loan For Edo</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/04/buhari-seeks-approval-of-75-million-world-bank-loan-for-edo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>We Have Identified Banks Where Stolen Funds Are Deposited – Buhari</title>
		<link>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/03/we-have-identified-banks-where-stolen-funds-are-deposited-buhari/</link>
		<comments>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/03/we-have-identified-banks-where-stolen-funds-are-deposited-buhari/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 19:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Donyoh Donney]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boko Haram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Channels News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Channels TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gulf of Guinea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insurgency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[led by Rep. Darrel Issa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Muhammadu Buhari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria-United States Bi-National Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigerian president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Congressmen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.channelstv.com/?p=159869</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Nigeria&#8217;s President, Muhammadu Buhari, says his administration has taken further efforts to recover Nigeria&#8217;s stolen funds, by identifying some banks and other financial institutions where the money has been deposited. The President made the disclosure on Monday in Abuja during an audience with visiting U.S. Congressmen, led by Representative Darrel Issa. According to a statement [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/03/we-have-identified-banks-where-stolen-funds-are-deposited-buhari/">We Have Identified Banks Where Stolen Funds Are Deposited – Buhari</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong><a href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/03/we-have-identified-banks-where-stolen-funds-are-deposited-buhari/muhammadu-buhari-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-159892"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-159892" src="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Muhammadu-Buhari-300x161.jpg" alt="Muhammadu-Buhari" width="300" height="161" /></a>Nigeria&#8217;s President, Muhammadu Buhari, says his administration has taken further efforts to recover Nigeria&#8217;s stolen funds, by identifying some banks and other financial institutions where the money has been deposited.</strong></em></p>
<p>The President made the disclosure on Monday in Abuja during an audience with visiting U.S. Congressmen, led by Representative Darrel Issa.</p>
<p>According to a statement by the Special Adviser to the President on Media and Publicity, Femi Adesina, President Buhari told the Congressmen that his administration would welcome more regular meetings of the Nigeria-United States Bi-National Commission.</p>
<p>The statement further said the administration had also identified countries in which payments for stolen Nigerian crude oil have been deposited.</p>
<p>At the meeting with the U.S. Congressmen, President Buhari acknowledged the support and cooperation his administration was getting from the international community in gathering required intelligence for tracing and recovering stolen national resources.</p>
<div id="attachment_159895" style="width: 660px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/03/we-have-identified-banks-where-stolen-funds-are-deposited-buhari/us-congressmen-meet-with-muhammadu-buhari/" rel="attachment wp-att-159895"><img class="wp-image-159895 size-full" src="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/US-Congressmen-meet-with-Muhammadu-Buhari.jpg" alt="US-Congressmen-meet-with-Muhammadu-Buhari" width="650" height="350" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Some officials of the U.S. government and members of the Congress at a meeting with President Muhammadu Buhari</p></div>
<p>&#8220;We are getting cooperation from the international community, including information on ships that take crude oil from Nigeria and change direction, or pour their contents into other ships mid-stream.</p>
<p>&#8220;Some monies were paid to individual accounts. We are identifying the financial institutions and countries that are involved.</p>
<p>&#8220;I have been assured that when we get all our documents together, the United States and other countries will treat our case with sympathy,&#8221; the President told the Congressmen.</p>
<p><strong>&#8216;End Boko Haram Insurgency&#8217;</strong></p>
<p>He further stated that his administration would welcome more regular meetings of the Nigeria-United States Bi-National Commission, stressing that the Commission could serve as a more useful platform for the promotion of bilateral trade, economic relations and joint cooperation in the war against terrorism.</p>
<p>Mr Darrel assured President Buhari that the United States would support Nigeria against Boko Haram by providing training, intelligence and military platforms.</p>
<p>&#8220;We look forward to helping you in many ways to end the Boko Haram insurgency and the theft of crude oil in the Gulf of Guinea,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>After his inauguration on May 29 President Buhari promised to recover funds that had been stolen by government officials who had abused their offices in the recent past, insisting that he would only probe that past administration.</p>
<p>He also promised special assistance to the three north eastern states &#8211; Adamawa, Borno  and Yobe &#8211; badly affected by the Boko Haram insurgency.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/03/we-have-identified-banks-where-stolen-funds-are-deposited-buhari/">We Have Identified Banks Where Stolen Funds Are Deposited – Buhari</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/03/we-have-identified-banks-where-stolen-funds-are-deposited-buhari/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Considers Lifting Arms Ban On Nigeria</title>
		<link>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/03/us-considers-lifting-arms-ban-on-nigeria/</link>
		<comments>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/03/us-considers-lifting-arms-ban-on-nigeria/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 16:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Donyoh Donney]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boko Haram insurgency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Channels News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Channels TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief of air staff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chiefs of Army]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[defence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Defence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issah Darrel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judicial Committee of the US Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leahy law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military assistance to foreign countries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Naval]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigerian military]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President Muhammadu Buhari’s visit to the US]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sale of arms by the US to Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US Department of State]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.channelstv.com/?p=159848</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The United States is considering lifting restrictions on sales of arms to Nigeria, officials of the U.S. Congress have said. A delegation from the U.S. Congress told military authorities in Abuja, Nigeria&#8217;s capital on Monday, that the decision was part of efforts by the U.S. to enhance cooperation between both countries in tackling the Boko Haram [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/03/us-considers-lifting-arms-ban-on-nigeria/">U.S. Considers Lifting Arms Ban On Nigeria</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong><a href="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/arms-in-the-us.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-159849 size-medium" src="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/arms-in-the-us-300x161.jpg" alt="U.S. Arms" width="300" height="161" /></a>The United States is considering lifting restrictions on sales of arms to Nigeria, officials of the U.S. Congress have said.</strong></em></p>
<p>A delegation from the U.S. Congress told military authorities in Abuja, Nigeria&#8217;s capital on Monday, that the decision was part of efforts by the U.S. to enhance cooperation between both countries in tackling the Boko Haram insurgents in Nigeria&#8217;s north-east.</p>
<p>The delegation, which was led by Issah Darrel, who is also part of the Judicial Committee of the U.S. Congress, met with the Chiefs of Army, Naval, Defence and Air Staff in a closed door meeting.</p>
<p><strong>The Leahy Law</strong></p>
<p>The U.S. Congress deligation&#8217;s visit is coming almost two weeks after President Muhammadu Buhari&#8217;s visited the U.S. and had talks with President Barack Obama on the war on terror ongoing in north-eastern Nigeria, economic development and other issues of interest to both countries.</p>
<p>Addressing a gathering at the United States Institute of Peace during his visit, President Buhari stressed the need for the U.S. Congress to <a title="Fixing Nigeria’s Problems Is A Responsibility Of Nigerians – Buhari" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/07/22/fixing-nigerias-problems-is-a-responsibility-of-nigerians-buhari/">examine how the U.S. Government could provide Nigeria with far more substantial counter-terrorism assistance</a> with minimal strings.</p>
<div id="attachment_158212" style="width: 660px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/07/22/fixing-nigerias-problems-is-a-responsibility-of-nigerians-buhari/muhammadu-buhari-n-institute-of-peace/" rel="attachment wp-att-158212"><img class="wp-image-158212 size-full" src="http://www.channelstv.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Muhammadu-Buhari-n-Institute-of-Peace.jpg" alt="Muhammadu-Buhari--n-Institute-of-Peace" width="650" height="350" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">President Buhari delivering a speech at the United States Institute of Peace in July 2015</p></div>
<p>At that meeting, President Buhari said: &#8220;Regrettably, the blanket application of the Leahy law by the United States on the grounds of unproven allegations of human rights violations levelled against our forces has denied us access to appropriate strategic weapons to prosecute the war against the insurgents. In the face of abduction of innocent school girls from their hostels, indiscriminate bombings of civilians in markets and places of worship, our forces have remained largely impotent because they do not possess the appropriate weapons and technology which they could have had, had the so called human rights violations not been an obstacle.</p>
<p>&#8220;Unwittingly, and I dare say, unintentionally, the application of the Leahy law amendment by the U. S. Government has aided and abated the Boko Haram terrorist group in the prosecution of its extremist ideology and hate, the indiscriminate killings and maiming of civilians, in raping of women and girls, and in their other heinous crimes. I believe this is not the spirit of the Leahy Laws. I know the American people cannot support any group engaged in these crimes.</p>
<p>&#8220;I therefore strongly appeal to both the Executive Arm and the U.S. Congress to examine how the U.S. Government can provide us with far more substantial counter-terrorism assistance with minimal strings. The longer we delay, the deadlier the Boko Haram gets. At all events, we have re-written the rules of engagement protecting the rights of combatants and in particular safeguarding civilians in theatres of conflict&#8221;.</p>
<p>The Nigerian military had maintained that<a title="Nigerian Military Says Amnesty International Report Is A Blackmail" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/06/03/nigerian-military-says-amnesty-international-report-is-a-blackmail/"> it had put into consideration the rights of citizens in its counter-terrorism operations, stressing that it would continue to uphold that commitment</a>.</p>
<p>The restrictions on sales of arms by the U.S. to Nigeria is embedded in the Leahy law which prohibited the U.S. Department of State and Department of Defence from providing military assistance to foreign countries that violate human rights with impunity.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/03/us-considers-lifting-arms-ban-on-nigeria/">U.S. Considers Lifting Arms Ban On Nigeria</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.channelstv.com">Channels Television</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.channelstv.com/2015/08/03/us-considers-lifting-arms-ban-on-nigeria/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
