<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Complete Sports Nigeria</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com</link>
	<description>Nigeria’s No.1 Sports website. Get latest sports news on Complete Sports Nigeria</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 07:18:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.2.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Nigeria Chase Ibe, Oliseh Meets With Liverpool Star</title>
		<link>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/nigeria-intensify-ibe-chase-meet-with-liverpool-star/</link>
		<comments>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/nigeria-intensify-ibe-chase-meet-with-liverpool-star/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 07:18:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nurudeen Obalola]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jordon Ibe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liverpool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/?p=26264</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Nigerian officials have met with Liverpool starlet Jordon Ibe in a bid to make him ditch England and play for the Super Eagles, claims the Mirror. Ibe, 19, has played for England at U-18, U-19 and U-20 levels but he is eligible for the Super Eagles through his Nigerian father, David. Jordon is in line ... <a class="read-more" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/nigeria-intensify-ibe-chase-meet-with-liverpool-star/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/nigeria-intensify-ibe-chase-meet-with-liverpool-star/">Nigeria Chase Ibe, Oliseh Meets With Liverpool Star</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nigerian officials have met with Liverpool starlet Jordon Ibe in a bid to make him ditch England and play for the Super Eagles, claims the Mirror.</p>
<p>Ibe, 19, has played for England at U-18, U-19 and U-20 levels but he is eligible for the Super Eagles through his Nigerian father, David.<br />
Jordon is in line to start at Stoke this weekend after impressing Brandon Rodgers in pre-season and he could get an England U-21 call-up.</p>
<p>But Nigeria have made a move to prevent Ibe from becoming a full England international as the Mirror reveals that representatives from the African nation were at Liverpool’s Melwood training ground on Wednesday to sound out the player over a switch of allegiances.</p>
<p>That could persuade England boss Roy Hodgson to accelerate his progress into the full England squad — especially after Rodgers offered a glowing reference about the youngster’s progress.</p>
<p>Ibe has been a star of Liverpool’s pre-season and that has put him at the forefront of his club manager’s plans, with Rodgers explaining the winger will be given the chance to shine this season.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/nigeria-intensify-ibe-chase-meet-with-liverpool-star/">Nigeria Chase Ibe, Oliseh Meets With Liverpool Star</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/nigeria-intensify-ibe-chase-meet-with-liverpool-star/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Uche Proud Despite Libertadores Defeat</title>
		<link>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/uche-proud-despite-libertadores-defeat/</link>
		<comments>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/uche-proud-despite-libertadores-defeat/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 06:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Prince Imerhion]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ikechukwu Uche]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Super Eagles]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/?p=26272</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>By Izuchukwu Okosi: Super Eagles striker Ikechukwu Uche is proud of his Mexican side Tigres UANL despite their 3-0 defeat in the wee hours of Thursday against Argentina&#8217;s River Plate in the second leg final of the 2015 Copa Libertadores. The 0-0 stalemate in the first leg gave Los Millonarios a slight edge, but the ... <a class="read-more" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/uche-proud-despite-libertadores-defeat/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/uche-proud-despite-libertadores-defeat/">Uche Proud Despite Libertadores Defeat</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Izuchukwu Okosi:</p>
<p>Super Eagles striker Ikechukwu Uche is proud of his Mexican side Tigres UANL despite their 3-0 defeat in the wee hours of Thursday against Argentina&#8217;s River Plate in the second leg final of the 2015 Copa Libertadores.</p>
<p>The 0-0 stalemate in the first leg gave Los Millonarios a slight edge, but the Mexicans fancied their chances of silencing the fans at the Estadio Monumental Antonio Vespucio Liberti in Buenos Aires.</p>
<p>Tigres were looking to become the first Mexican side to win the Copa Libertadores Championship but could not actualise that dream losing 3-0 to their rivals in the second leg after that drab goalless draw in the first leg.</p>
<p>Uche who is recovering from a knee injury tweeted after the game:</p>
<p>&#8220;Despite the loss, I&#8217;m proud to be part of this team.&#8221;</p>
<p>Alario headed in at the near post in the 45th minute to send River on their way to a third Copa title and first since 1996.</p>
<p>Sanchez was fouled in the penalty area in the 75th minute, he dusted himself up and converted his spot-kick and Mori headed in a corner in-between the keeper&#8217;s legs in the 79th minute.</p>
<p>The final monitored by completesportsnigeria.com saw nine yellow cards in a feisty encounter.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/uche-proud-despite-libertadores-defeat/">Uche Proud Despite Libertadores Defeat</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/uche-proud-despite-libertadores-defeat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Man City Confirm Iheanacho Promotion To First Team</title>
		<link>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/man-city-confirm-iheanacho-promotion-to-first-team/</link>
		<comments>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/man-city-confirm-iheanacho-promotion-to-first-team/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 06:41:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Prince Imerhion]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kelec​h​i Iheanacho]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manchester City]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/?p=26257</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>By Johnny Edward: Manchester City have confirmed that Kelec​h​i Iheanacho has been promoted to the first team for the 2015/2016 season. The Nigerian forward featured in five pre-season games, scoring twice and was heavily tipped to be included in the senior squad following his sparkling form. It was then confirmed on Wednesday night when he ... <a class="read-more" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/man-city-confirm-iheanacho-promotion-to-first-team/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/man-city-confirm-iheanacho-promotion-to-first-team/">Man City Confirm Iheanacho Promotion To First Team</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Johnny Edward:</p>
<p>Manchester City have confirmed that Kelec​h​i Iheanacho has been promoted to the first team for the 2015/2016 season.</p>
<p>The Nigerian forward featured in five pre-season games, scoring twice and was heavily tipped to be included in the senior squad following his sparkling form.</p>
<p>It was then confirmed on Wednesday night when he was presented alongside two other academy graduates Jason Denayer and Marcos Lopes to the club&#8217;s fans during City&#8217;s annual award ceremony that usually precedes the season opener​.</p>
<p>“@Jasondenayer, @Rony10Lopes &#038; @67Kelechi are the three academy graduates promoted to the first team,” the club&#8217;s official Twitter handle confirmed.<br />
​<br />
Iheanacho is expected to play a part in Monday night’s away clash against West Brom at the Hawthorns.</p>
<p>Also at the awards night, Toni Duggan emerged winner of the Nissan Goal of the Season Award for her stunning strike against Chelsea.</p>
<p>While Sergio Aguero won the Etihad Airways Player of the Season award.​</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/man-city-confirm-iheanacho-promotion-to-first-team/">Man City Confirm Iheanacho Promotion To First Team</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/man-city-confirm-iheanacho-promotion-to-first-team/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moses Limps Off, Mikel Starts As Chelsea Lose Again</title>
		<link>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/moses-limps-off-mikel-starts-as-chelsea-lose-again/</link>
		<comments>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/moses-limps-off-mikel-starts-as-chelsea-lose-again/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 21:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nurudeen Obalola]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chelsea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mikel Obi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Victor Moses]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/?p=26260</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>&#8212;Mourinho Allays Nigeria Star&#8217;s Injury Fears By James Agberebi: Nigeria internationals, John Mikel Obi and Victor Moses, were in action for Chelsea in their 1-0 loss to Fiorentina, in the International Champions Cup.  It was Chelsea&#8217;s second straight defeat after their loss to Arsenal on Sunday. Both started the match, but Moses was taken off ... <a class="read-more" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/moses-limps-off-mikel-starts-as-chelsea-lose-again/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/moses-limps-off-mikel-starts-as-chelsea-lose-again/">Moses Limps Off, Mikel Starts As Chelsea Lose Again</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8212;Mourinho Allays Nigeria Star&#8217;s Injury Fears</p>
<p>By James Agberebi:</p>
<p>Nigeria internationals, John Mikel Obi and Victor Moses, were in action for Chelsea in their 1-0 loss to Fiorentina, in the International Champions Cup. </p>
<p>It was Chelsea&#8217;s second straight defeat after their loss to Arsenal on Sunday.</p>
<p>Both started the match, but Moses was taken off early in the second half after appearing to have picked a knock.</p>
<p>However, moments after the match, when asked about Moses, Mourinho was quoted by the Chelsea Twitter handle saying: &#8220;He has no problem.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Super Eagles winger has been one of Chelsea&#8217;s best player in pre-season, in which they have not won any match in regular time.</p>
<p>The only goal of Wednesday night&#8217;s match was scored by Rodriguez on 34 minutes after Asmir Begovic spilled a shot.</p>
<p>Moses was the liveliest Chelsea players in action, while Mikel had a quiet game. Moses was a contant threat to the Fiorentina defence and he suffered from several rough tackles.</p>
<p>The duo were eventually substituted as Moses came off for Ramirez in the 54th minute, while Mikel was replaced at half time by Nemanja Matic.</p>
<p>Also in action was youngster Ola Aina, who came off before the start of the second half.</p>
<p>In Sunday&#8217;s Community Shield against Arsenal, Moses came in towards the end of the match while Mikel was an unused substitute.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Chelsea will begin the defence of their EPL title against Swansea.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/moses-limps-off-mikel-starts-as-chelsea-lose-again/">Moses Limps Off, Mikel Starts As Chelsea Lose Again</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/moses-limps-off-mikel-starts-as-chelsea-lose-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>LMC Give El-Kanemi 60 Days To Pay Salaries</title>
		<link>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/lmc-give-el-kanemi-60-days-to-salaries/</link>
		<comments>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/lmc-give-el-kanemi-60-days-to-salaries/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 20:54:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Prince Imerhion]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Nigeria League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[El-Kanemi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LMC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/?p=26255</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>&#8212;League Body Fine Bayelsa Utd By Adeboye Amosu: Glo Premier League side, El-kanemi Warriors, have become the third club to be issued sixty days ultimatum to pay all amounts due to their players and officials or risk being thrown out of the Nigeria Professional Football League by the League Management Company. The warning issued through ... <a class="read-more" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/lmc-give-el-kanemi-60-days-to-salaries/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/lmc-give-el-kanemi-60-days-to-salaries/">LMC Give El-Kanemi 60 Days To Pay Salaries</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8212;League Body Fine Bayelsa Utd</p>
<p>By Adeboye Amosu:</p>
<p>Glo Premier League side, El-kanemi Warriors, have become the third club to be issued sixty days ultimatum to pay all amounts due to their players and officials or risk being thrown out of the Nigeria Professional Football League by the League Management Company.</p>
<p>The warning issued through a letter by the LMC  Chief Operating Officer, Salihu Abubakar, is one of the three decisions announced by the league body in a sweeping enforcement of regulations on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Other decisions include the fining of Bayelsa United the sum of N700,000  for not providing adequate security during their match day 20 fixture against Akwa United at the Oghara Township Stadium.</p>
<p>The LMC also issued a warning to the Plateau FA Chairman for his unsporting conduct during the match day 20  fixture between Giwa FC and Kwara United at the Rwang Pam Stadium, Jos.</p>
<p>It would be recalled that Dolphins were the first club to receive such notice after the LMC received and investigated a formal complaint from one of the players.</p>
<p>Last week the LMC drew the lines for FC Taraba and placed the club on a 60 days probation to pay all outstanding salaries to the players and officials failing  which it will be deducted six points from already accumulated points this season.</p>
<p>The sanction is one of the safety measures put in place to check indebtness to players by clubs.</p>
<p>It has recently organized an executive training programme for club chairmen on utilizing the commercial potentials of clubs to create additional revenue streams.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/lmc-give-el-kanemi-60-days-to-salaries/">LMC Give El-Kanemi 60 Days To Pay Salaries</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/lmc-give-el-kanemi-60-days-to-salaries/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Musa Bags Brace, Fatai Scores In UCL Thriller</title>
		<link>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/musa-bags-brace-fatai-scores-in-ucl-thriller/</link>
		<comments>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/musa-bags-brace-fatai-scores-in-ucl-thriller/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 19:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nurudeen Obalola]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ahmed Musa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Champions League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kehinda Fatai]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/?p=26252</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>CSKA, Ambrose&#8217;s Celtic Through To Play-Offs By Johnny Edward: Ahmed Musa scored twice as his Russian side CSKA Moscow sailed through to the play-offs the UEFA Champions League on Wednesday night. CSKA fought back to defeat Sparta Prague 3-2 to advance 5-4 on aggregate. Sparta&#8217;s Nigerian striker Kehinde scored one of their goals. Musa scored ... <a class="read-more" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/musa-bags-brace-fatai-scores-in-ucl-thriller/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/musa-bags-brace-fatai-scores-in-ucl-thriller/">Musa Bags Brace, Fatai Scores In UCL Thriller</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>CSKA, Ambrose&#8217;s Celtic Through To Play-Offs</p>
<p>By Johnny Edward:</p>
<p>Ahmed Musa scored twice as his Russian side CSKA Moscow sailed through to the play-offs the UEFA Champions League on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>CSKA fought back to defeat Sparta Prague 3-2 to advance 5-4 on aggregate. Sparta&#8217;s Nigerian striker Kehinde scored one of their goals.</p>
<p>Musa scored in the 34th and 51st minutes as CSKA won the thriller in Prague and advanced to the round that precedes the group stages.</p>
<p>Ladislav Krejci shot the hosts into the lead in the sixth minute and Fatai made it 2-0 ten minutes later.</p>
<p>Fatai who was on target in the first leg in Russia was replaced by David Lafata in the 56th minute of the encounter.</p>
<p>Dzagoev grabbed the winner in the 76th minute to send his side into Friday’s play-off draw.</p>
<p>In Azerbaijan, Efe Ambrose was an unused substitute in Celtic’s goalless draw to Qarabag FK. The Scottish champions are also through to the play-offs with a 1-0 aggregate win.​</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/musa-bags-brace-fatai-scores-in-ucl-thriller/">Musa Bags Brace, Fatai Scores In UCL Thriller</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/musa-bags-brace-fatai-scores-in-ucl-thriller/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enyimba Stay On Top As 3SC, Pillars Win</title>
		<link>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/enyimba-stay-on-top-as-3sc-pillars-win/</link>
		<comments>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/enyimba-stay-on-top-as-3sc-pillars-win/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 17:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nurudeen Obalola]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3sc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enyimba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kano Pillars]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/?p=26247</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>By Adeboye Amosu: Enyimba maintained top position in the Nigeria Professional Football League courtesy of a 2-2 draw against Akwa United on Wednesday in Uyo. The hosts took the  lead in the third minute through Aniekpeno Udoh and dominated the game afterwards but failed to extend their lead as they wasted the numerous chances that ... <a class="read-more" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/enyimba-stay-on-top-as-3sc-pillars-win/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/enyimba-stay-on-top-as-3sc-pillars-win/">Enyimba Stay On Top As 3SC, Pillars Win</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Adeboye Amosu:<br />
Enyimba maintained top position in the Nigeria Professional Football League courtesy of a 2-2 draw against Akwa United on Wednesday in Uyo.<br />
The hosts took the  lead in the third minute through Aniekpeno Udoh and dominated the game afterwards but failed to extend their lead as they wasted the numerous chances that came their way.<br />
They were however punished for their profligacy in the closing moments of the first half when Musa Najare equalised for the visitors.<br />
The Promise Keepers regained the lead through Aniekan Ekpe who converted from the spot in the 57th minute, but parity was restored six minutes later when Enyimba&#8217;s Liberian import, Alloy Brown, scored on his debut for the People&#8217;s Elephant.<br />
The draw increased Enyimba&#8217;s lead over second-placed Sunshine Stars to two points but the Akure Gunners will displace Kadiri Ikhana&#8217;s side at the top should they beat Sharks at home on Thursday.<br />
In Kano, champions Kano Pillars continued their resurgence under Mohammed Babaganaru with a hard earned 2-1 against Heartland.<br />
The Pyramid City side rallied back from a goal down to secure the win with Rabiu Ali scoring a late penalty to seal victory for his side.<br />
Warri Wolves were in ruthless form as they mauled Ifeanyi Ubah 3-0  at the Warri City Stadium.<br />
Their top striker, Gbolahan Salami, hit a brace, while Ikechukwu Ibenegbu scored the other.<br />
A brace by  Chisom Chikatara helped Abia Warriors beat Giwa FC 2-0  in Umuahia, while Kwara United managed a 2-1 win against Dolphins at the Ilorin Township Stadium.<br />
Lobi Stars also enjoyed a beautiful evening with a comfortable 3-0 win against Bayelsa United at the Aper Aku Stadium.<br />
Wikki Tourists continued their free fall as they lost 2-1 to 3SC in Ibadan.<br />
In the last game of the day, Nasarawa United defeated El-kanemi Warriors 4-2 in Lafia.</p>
<p>      ALL THE RESULTS<br />
Akwa United     2 -2  Enyimba<br />
Nasarawa Utd   4 -2  El-kanemi Warriors<br />
Kwara Utd         2-1   Dolphins<br />
Pillars                2-1   Heartland<br />
Lobi Stars          3-0   Bayelsa Utd<br />
Warri Wolves     3-0   Ifeanyi Ubah<br />
Abia Warriors     2-0   Giwa FC<br />
3SC                    2-1   Wikki Tourists</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/enyimba-stay-on-top-as-3sc-pillars-win/">Enyimba Stay On Top As 3SC, Pillars Win</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/enyimba-stay-on-top-as-3sc-pillars-win/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eaglets Know World Cup Foes Thursday</title>
		<link>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/eaglets-know-world-cup-foes-thursday/</link>
		<comments>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/eaglets-know-world-cup-foes-thursday/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 15:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nurudeen Obalola]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eaglets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Cup]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/?p=26241</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Nigeria&#8217;s Golden Eaglets and big countries like Brazil, Argentina and Germany will on Thursday know their group opponents as the draw for the FIFA U-17 World Cup will hold in Santiago, Chile. The Eaglets are defending champions having won the championship two years ago in the United Arab Emirates. The 24 teams that qualified for ... <a class="read-more" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/eaglets-know-world-cup-foes-thursday/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/eaglets-know-world-cup-foes-thursday/">Eaglets Know World Cup Foes Thursday</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nigeria&#8217;s Golden Eaglets and big countries like Brazil, Argentina and Germany will on Thursday know their group opponents as the draw for the FIFA U-17 World Cup will hold in Santiago, Chile.<br />
The Eaglets are defending champions having won the championship two years ago in the United Arab Emirates.<br />
The 24 teams that qualified for the World Cup  will be drawn into six groups of four teams each.<br />
Defending champions Nigeria and host Chile would most likely be the seeded teams in their respective groups of this year&#8217;s FIFA U-17 World Cup.<br />
Speaking ahead of the draw, Golden Eaglets coach Emmanuel Amuneke said he was not expecting an easy draw since all the qualified teams have the same ambition of winning the FIFA U-17 trophy, adding that the Nigerian youngsters would be at the ready to defend their title.<br />
“We are waiting to see who and who we are going to meet after the draw on Thursday,” the former African Footballer of the Year told the Nigeria Football Federation website. “Though we don’t have the luxury of choosing the teams we want, we are preparing well for the tournament and we would be ready to give a good account of ourselves.”<br />
Meanwhile, the 24 teams that will be in Chile are: Belgium, France, Germany, Russia, Croatia and England (Europe); Australia, Korea Republic, Syria and  Korea DPR(Asia); Mexico, Honduras, Costa Rica and USA (North America); Brazil, Argentina, Ecuador, Paraguay and host Chile (South America); New Zealand(Oceania) and Mali, Guinea, South Africa and Nigeria (Africa).<br />
The 2015 FIFA U-17 World Cup would be held between October 17 and November 8 across eight Chilean cities, namely La Serena, Coquimbo, Vina Del Mar, Chillan, Talca, Santiago De Chile, Concepcion and  Puerto Montt.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/eaglets-know-world-cup-foes-thursday/">Eaglets Know World Cup Foes Thursday</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/eaglets-know-world-cup-foes-thursday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigeria Stock Exchange Honours Oliseh</title>
		<link>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/nigeria-stock-exchange-honours-oliseh/</link>
		<comments>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/nigeria-stock-exchange-honours-oliseh/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 15:38:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Prince Imerhion]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Headlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oliseh]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/?p=26242</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>&#8212;Super Eagles Coach To Ring Symbolic Bell Super Eagles head coach, Sunday Oliseh, will be honoured on Monday, 17 August when he will perform the significant ringing of the bell at the closing of business at the Nigeria Stock Exchange. The NFF official website reports that Oliseh will attend the symbolic event at the Nigeria ... <a class="read-more" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/nigeria-stock-exchange-honours-oliseh/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/nigeria-stock-exchange-honours-oliseh/">Nigeria Stock Exchange Honours Oliseh</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8212;Super Eagles Coach To Ring Symbolic Bell</p>
<p> Super Eagles head coach, Sunday Oliseh, will be honoured on Monday, 17 August when he will perform the significant ringing of the bell at the closing of business at the Nigeria Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The NFF official website reports that Oliseh will attend the symbolic event at the Nigeria Stock Exchange house in Lagos in company with Nigeria Football Federation President, Amaju Pinnick, and vice-presidents Seyi Akinwunmi and Shehu Dikko.</p>
<p>“The ringing of the bell at the closing of business at the Nigeria Stock Exchange floor is a very significant event. It means that Corporate Nigeria is warming up to Nigeria football as a result of extensive consultations that we have been making over the past months,” Pinnick said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>It is the first time in history that the Nigeria Stock Exchange would offer a Nigeria football figure such a gesture, and Pinnick says it is the beginning of what would turn out to be a wonderful relationship between Corporate Nigeria and Nigeria football.</p>
<p>“We are looking at taking this to a level where even clubs in the Nigeria League will be quoted on the Nigeria Stock Exchange. It is a gradual process but we will get there.”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/nigeria-stock-exchange-honours-oliseh/">Nigeria Stock Exchange Honours Oliseh</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/nigeria-stock-exchange-honours-oliseh/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>U-23 Eagles Star Expects Tough African Tourney</title>
		<link>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/u-23-eagles-star-expects-tough-african-tourney/</link>
		<comments>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/u-23-eagles-star-expects-tough-african-tourney/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 14:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Prince Imerhion]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News Update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oghenekaro Etebo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/?p=26238</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>By Adeboye Amosu: U-23 Eagles forward, Oghenekaro Etebo, insists the team is firmly focused on securing a place in the football event of the 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro, even as he insists that it is a tough task. The Nigerians booked their passage to the African U-23 Championship which serves as the ... <a class="read-more" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/u-23-eagles-star-expects-tough-african-tourney/">Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/u-23-eagles-star-expects-tough-african-tourney/">U-23 Eagles Star Expects Tough African Tourney</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Adeboye Amosu:</p>
<p>U-23 Eagles forward, Oghenekaro Etebo, insists the team is firmly focused on securing a place in the football event of the 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro, even as he insists that it is a tough task.</p>
<p>The Nigerians booked their passage to the African U-23 Championship which serves as the qualifier for the global event following a hard fought  2-1 aggregate win against Congo.</p>
<p>The Warri Wolves hitman told completesportsnigeria.com that they are keen on picking a ticket as one of Africa&#8217;s representatives at the games.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have only crossed the first hurdle by qualifying for the African Championship, but there is still a long way to go,&#8221; he told completesportsnigeria.com.</p>
<p>&#8220;The next target is to qualify for the games, after that we can talk about our objectives at the Games proper.</p>
<p>&#8220;The competition in Senegal will be tough as the other teams will be out to do well, but we are confident of emerging as the best.&#8221;<br />
Eight teams will participate at the African Championship from November 28 to December 12 in Senegal</p>
<p>The top three teams at the competition  will qualify for the Olympic Games, while the fourth placed side will face an Asian side in a play-off.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/u-23-eagles-star-expects-tough-african-tourney/">U-23 Eagles Star Expects Tough African Tourney</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.completesportsnigeria.com">Complete Sports Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.completesportsnigeria.com/u-23-eagles-star-expects-tough-african-tourney/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Page Caching using xcache

 Served from: www.completesportsnigeria.com @ 2015-08-06 10:21:31 by W3 Total Cache -->