<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Nigerian News from Leadership News</title>
	<atom:link href="http://leadership.ng/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://leadership.ng</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 04:28:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.2.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Oil Spills: Reps Investigate Oil Coys’ Equipment In Niger Delta</title>
		<link>http://leadership.ng/news/452065/oil-spills-reps-investigate-oil-coys-equipment-in-niger-delta</link>
		<comments>http://leadership.ng/news/452065/oil-spills-reps-investigate-oil-coys-equipment-in-niger-delta#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 04:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kelvin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontpage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://leadership.ng/?p=452065</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="225" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/nigeria-house-of-reps-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="nigeria house of reps" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div>The House of Representatives yesterday resolved to investigate the state and age of operational equipment used by oil exploration companies in the country. This followed a motion sponsored by Hon. Goodluck Opiah (Imo/PDP) on the need to investigate oil pollution in Ohaji-Egbema and Oguta local government areas of Imo State and adopted by the lawmakers....]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="225" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/nigeria-house-of-reps-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="nigeria house of reps" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div><p>The House of Representatives yesterday resolved to investigate the state and age of operational equipment used by oil exploration companies in the country.</p>
<p>This followed a motion sponsored by Hon. Goodluck Opiah (Imo/PDP) on the need to investigate oil pollution in Ohaji-Egbema and Oguta local government areas of Imo State and adopted by the lawmakers.</p>
<p>Opiah, who described the affected areas as operational base of Agip Oil Company, said that the areas suffered oil spillage and fire explosions that were avoidable.</p>
<p>Leading debates, Opiah pointed out the need to investigate the state of equipment used by Agip Oil Company in its 50 years of operations in the communities.</p>
<p>“The recent one (oil spill) at Ebocha-Egbema led to a stoppage of exploration of crude oil, and consequent loss of over 20,000 barrels of crude oil per day,’’ Opiah told lawmakers.</p>
<p>He alleged that virtually all oil companies operating in the Niger Delta use substandard and outdated equipment that are unsafe and pollute the environment.</p>
<p>“They (oil companies) have little regard for the safety of lives and property of the host communities,’’ the lawmaker alleged.</p>
<p>Speaking in support of the motion, Hon. Aliyu Magaji (Jigawa/APC) said there was need to regularly monitor the activities of the oil companies to ensure they complied with the extant laws regulating their operations.</p>
<p>“There is need to find out if these oil companies are actually doing what they are supposed to do. There is also need to ensure their facilities are monitored to guarantee they are up to standard and this is crucial in averting poor maintenance services,’’ Magaji stated.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://leadership.ng/news/452065/oil-spills-reps-investigate-oil-coys-equipment-in-niger-delta/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kogi Guber: Between Wada And The Rest</title>
		<link>http://leadership.ng/news/452061/kogi-guber-between-wada-and-the-rest</link>
		<comments>http://leadership.ng/news/452061/kogi-guber-between-wada-and-the-rest#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 04:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kelvin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontpage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://leadership.ng/?p=452061</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="225" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/Gov-Idris-Wada-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="Gov-Idris-Wada" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div>Ahead of the forthcoming governorship election in Kogi State, MUYIWA OYINLOLA in this report, examines the wit of the gladiators against the incumbent Governor Idris Wada, who is also seeking a second term in office.  The volatile Kogi State politics has suddenly reverberated since the release of the timetable for the governorship election in the...]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="225" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/Gov-Idris-Wada-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="Gov-Idris-Wada" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div><p><em>Ahead of the forthcoming governorship election in Kogi State, MUYIWA OYINLOLA in this report, examines the wit of the gladiators against the incumbent Governor Idris Wada, who is also seeking a second term in office. </em></p>
<p>The volatile Kogi State politics has suddenly reverberated since the release of the timetable for the governorship election in the state by the Independent National Electoral Commission (INEC).</p>
<p>When the electoral body announced that it would conduct governorship election in the state on November 21, this year, political activities in the state have assumed accentuated dynamism.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>The Contenders</strong></p>
<p>At the last count, over 30 aspirants have indicated interest in the governorship position in the state on the platform of the opposition All Progressives Congress (APC).</p>
<p>Within the ruling Peoples Democratic Party (PDP), the incumbent governor, Capt. Idris Wada and three others including Jibrin Isah- Echocho, one of those who challenged Wada’s victory in 2011.</p>
<p>Echocho rose to political relevance upon his controversial win in the January 2011 PDP primaries, a claim he lost to Wada at the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>In the last general elections, PDP scored a paltry 34 votes at his polling unit.</p>
<p>Other factors against him include religious fanaticism, having allegedly banned Christian students from a school he established.</p>
<p>It was even alleged that the negative perceptions of the administration and PDP in particular in some quarters are mainly due to the media hype by the Echocho group.</p>
<p>Echocho has since the announcement of the date allegedly embarked on subtle campaign against Wada ahead of the poll.</p>
<p>In fact, a recent campaign against the possible return of Wada as PDP candidate has been allegedly traced to him.</p>
<p>For instance, in May this year, a group, PDP Concerned Group, told the national leadership of the party and the PDP Governors’ Forum to prevail on Wada, not to run in the forthcoming governorship election in the state.</p>
<p>The group, in a nine-page petition to the PDP national secretariat and the party’s governors’ forum, said Wada’s candidature would bring defeat on the party at the election.</p>
<p>In the petition, the group said Wada has performed woefully so far and that Kogi people would definitely be wary about rewarding him with another tenure.</p>
<p>The statement signed by five members of the group; Husseni Idris, Mohammed Bello, Taiye Oshadare, Emanuel Sani and Ishaya Yusuf, said: “If PDP loses in the forthcoming gubernatorial polls, the morale of many party faithful in this state will drop, and many might decamp to other parties.”</p>
<p>But in a swift reaction to the allegations by the group, Jacob Edi, the special adviser to the Kogi Governor on media and strategy, said the group has no right to speak for the people of Kogi state.</p>
<p>Edi said “First of all, the group in question has no monopoly to speak for the people of Kogi state.</p>
<p>“Also, just as they are saying the PDP will lose if Governor Wada contests; there are other groups that have also said that the only alternative for the PDP will be the emergence of Wada as the party’s flag-bearer.</p>
<p>“They include: the Kogi State Elders Forum, students, market women, okada riders and others.”</p>
<p>He added that the only possible reason for the group’s statement is malice, but noted that “In politics you can’t have everyone on your side”.</p>
<p>There are however, insinuations that Ochocho may be subtly working for the rival APC, having been said to be an in-law to former Governor Abubakar Audu, who is a major contender for the APC ticket.</p>
<p>Other contenders include Senator Alex Kadiri, a former PDP chieftain who is now in the APC. He hails from the same ward as Wada and had been defeated by Wada in a previous election.</p>
<p>Suleiman Baba Ali, is also said to be a nephew to Abubakar Audu and may be working in Audu’s interest. Another aspirant is young and dynamic Yahaya Bello (Fairplus), a forrmer civil servant. Nicholas Ugbane, a two-time senator, is also in the race but he is said to have a long way to go in convincing Kogites he can deliver.</p>
<p>Plus old George Famoroti, an ex-PENGASSAN chairman is also in the race. Famoroti is said to have instituted a number of projects in a section of the state and in some other areas outside the state but but some other parts of the state feel he is sectional.</p>
<p>Usman Jibrin, the immediate past chief of naval staff is said to have contributed to the success of the APC in the last elections; the people of he state are watching to see on which platform he will run. Col. Ahmed Usman rtd., a former military administrator of Oyo state, is also in the race.</p>
<p>AVM Salihu Atawodi decamped from PDP recently. Former head of PICOMMS, under the office of former NSA, Sambo Dasuki who has just been indicted in a multi-million naira fraud under the immediate past administration of Dr. Goodluck Jonathan.</p>
<p>Other aspirants in the race include Honorable Positive Ihiabe, former House of Representatives member, who until a few weeks ago was a member of the ruling PDP in the state.</p>
<p>Mohammed Ali, former chairman of Dekina local government is also in the race but his reach is said to be limited to that particular local government.</p>
<p>Moreover, Alh Isa Kutepa was also a member of the PDP just like Senator Nurudeen Abatemi Usman.</p>
<p>Other aspirants include Abdul Adama, Lanre Ipinmisho, Dr Yakeen Habeeb and Hussein Idris Lasham.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Wada’s’ giant strides</strong></p>
<p>In spite of the unending list of the aspirants, Wada seems unperturbed, expressing optimism that the PDP will win the next governorship election in the state in view of its high-level preparations for the polls.</p>
<p>Speaking with newsmen last month at the Lokoja Township Stadium, venue of the state congress of the party, he said he was very positive and optimistic that everything would go well.</p>
<p>He explained that the congress was a prelude to the main exercise as it created the platform for election of leaders to lead the party and prepare grounds for a successful outing in the November guber polls.</p>
<p>“Yes, today is a very special day. We’ve been without a state working committee or state Executive Council for some time, so, I’m very happy that we have finally come round to elect the people to lead our party for the next four years.</p>
<p>“Because of the various stakeholders meetings we’ve had, consultations and interactions between our leaders, our expectation is that the congress will be smooth and the outcome will be election of popular candidates”, he said.</p>
<p>The governor added that the executive council to be elected would be saddled with organizing primaries “for the common purpose of organizing our party to win the next election.”</p>
<p>He stated that the last local government congresses of the party went well and even though there was an appeal committee in place, there were no complaints, petitions or rancour.</p>
<p>Speaking in another forum, Wada noted that despite the challenges that his government has been through, “we will say we started on a very solid foundation, as we come up with a blueprint agenda to transform our state. We have done a lot in trying to implement that agenda, starting with the completion of projects that were ongoing. The essence of that is because all those projects were being executed for public good. Public money had been invested in the project. We thought it was only proper that we complete the projects as any decision to leave them partly done after some money has been spent will be a waste of money.”</p>
<p>“But later, especially after the completion of the majority of those projects, we came to another informed decision to split available resources between completing some of the remaining projects and also starting new projects. That is the path we have continued to tread. So far so good, we have done a lot of work in terms of creating peaceful environment, enhanced security for our people. Enterprise will now thrive and people will move in peace and tranquility with each other. We try to unify our people for a common purpose of development and transformation of Kogi state by being fair in the distribution of amenities and projects across the three senatorial zones of the state. We try to attend to the needs of our people in an equitable manner.</p>
<p>“This has helped to propel our agenda for unity and transformation of Kogi state. We have done a lot of infrastructural projects, a lot of rural development projects; water, electricity, roads, and hospitals. We have focused on agriculture because we believe it is a job creation area. Anybody can go into agriculture. So, we create an opportunity to improve the wealth of our people through agriculture. The message has got across and that is the way to the future.”</p>
<p>To other critics who are of the opinion that Wada has not done enough to secure another term, he stated in a recent interview that “In politics, you can expect all kinds of accusations from your opponents. But let’s start from Abuja here. Abuja belongs to all of us, go to Kogi House, go to Kogi Liaison Office in Asokoro, we have completely rehabilitated and upgraded the House. At the Central Business District, I am building an eleven storey building. It’s at the fourth floor. In Kogi state, I am building a tertiary hospital. We are building an ultra modern motor park in Lokoja, which hopefully, should be commissioned in three months’ time.”</p>
<p>“There is a very modern vocational training centre which we are building in partnership with Korea Corporation Industry, a development agency which is at the verge of commissioning next month. We are building a dualised road, like a bye pass , a sixteen kilometer road to reduce traffic congestion. We are building about 500 houses in Lokoja and about 282 are almost completed. We have built 272 housing units in Lokoja for those who were displaced by the flood. We are building several township roads across the state. We are building four zonal hospitals across the state. There are several health clinics we have built. We have dug more than 300 motorized boreholes across various parts the state. We have electrified more than 400 villages across the state. We have built and renovated countless schools.We are going to build more.”</p>
<p>“These are practical projects which people can see so if my critics say we are not doing anything. You can come and see them. But you should not expect our opponents to praise me. When you talk of development, it must be measured along with the resources available to the state. Kogi is not a failed state. We have paid salary every last week of the month since I came into office until May 2015 when we had challenges of payment. The money that came in was N2.7 billion. We need about N3.1 billion to run our affairs. There was a shortage. Ordinarily, when we have such challenges, we take over draft and pay. But at a point, we had to face the reality. We were challenged and we couldn’t pay salaries for one month. Ws we speak, Kogi state owes one month salary. So, anybody who says we are a failed state, that person is not being factual.It is the prudence with which we have managed resources of the state that has enabled us to pay our salaries between 25th and 27th day of every month since I came into office in January 2012. We have paid salaries. Nobody has complained about not receiving salary, especially the civil servants before then. We are one of the states that have been paying salaries regularly since we came into office.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://leadership.ng/news/452061/kogi-guber-between-wada-and-the-rest/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boko Haram: Danjuma Committee Releases N140m To 7 North-East Hospitals</title>
		<link>http://leadership.ng/news/452057/boko-haram-danjuma-committee-releases-n140m-to-7-north-east-hospitals</link>
		<comments>http://leadership.ng/news/452057/boko-haram-danjuma-committee-releases-n140m-to-7-north-east-hospitals#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 04:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kelvin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontpage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://leadership.ng/?p=452057</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="200" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/general-ty-danjuma-rtd-former-chief-of-army-staff-300x200.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="general-ty-danjuma-rtd-former-chief-of-army-staff" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div>Seven major hospitals in NorthEast Nigeria were yesterday issued cheques worth N140 million by the Gen Theophilus Danjuma-led Victims Support Fund (VSF) Committee to enable them carry on with the medical treatment of all injured victims of Boko Haram terrorism. Each of the issued cheques worth N20 million were handed to heads of various hospitals...]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="200" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/general-ty-danjuma-rtd-former-chief-of-army-staff-300x200.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="general-ty-danjuma-rtd-former-chief-of-army-staff" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div><p>Seven major hospitals in NorthEast Nigeria were yesterday issued cheques worth N140 million by the Gen Theophilus Danjuma-led Victims Support Fund (VSF) Committee to enable them carry on with the medical treatment of all injured victims of Boko Haram terrorism.</p>
<p>Each of the issued cheques worth N20 million were handed to heads of various hospitals after a memorandum of understanding was signed between the officials of the VSF and the benefitting health facilities.</p>
<p>In Borno State, two hospitals, the University of Maiduguri Teaching Hospital (UMTH) and the State Specialists Hospital were selected for the grant, while other hospitals in Yobe, Adamawa and Gombe states were also said to have benefitted.</p>
<p>Presenting the cheques to the benefitting health facilities at different grant award ceremonies, a top official of the VSF, Prof Sunday Ochoche, who represented the chairman of the committee, General Danjuma, said the idea behind the support and the signed memoranda of understanding was to assist the hospitals to continue caring for the victims.</p>
<p>He said their action was in line with the mandates given to them by Nigerians as well as to encourage the hospitals in the good works they have been doing, with the believe that whatever little financial support they are given would add to the hospitals’ capacity and ability to cater for the victims of the violent armed conflict.</p>
<p>Professor Ochoche said the signed MOU would open a working relationship with the hospitals management in such a manner that the target victims of the insurgency will continue to have the right medical treatment without recourse to the problems of lack of resources by the hospitals.</p>
<p>He noted that the N20 million grant was a first phase of the support from the VSF even as he quickly noted that the given amount cannot be enough to cater for the expenses the hospitals suffer daily in managing persons brought in with injuries from scenes of blasts or attacks.</p>
<p>He lamented that the VSF committee is yet to get most of the pledges made during the launching of the fund last year and promised that with more redemption of promises, the hospitals would be getting more of such support.</p>
<p>The Chief Medical Director (CMD) of the University of Maiduguri Teaching Hospital, Dr Abdurrahman Muhammed Tahir who expressed delight with the coming of the VSF grant said apart from the huge personnel loss that his tertiary health facility had suffered from 2010 to date, the hospital had also incurred debt of over N150 million through free treatment of persons.   Brought to the hospital as victim of Boko Haram insurgency.</p>
<p>He further lamented that until recently that the hospital was assisted with the sum of N30 million by the National Emergency Management (NEMA), the hospital was barely functioning due to overstretched facilities and piled debt.</p>
<p>He also mentioned that the Radiology Department of the hospital,which is one of the most crucial area of the teaching hospital had been grounded for months and could not be fixed because the engineers concerned could not make it to Maiduguri as they fear for their lives.</p>
<p>He however said he has set up a special committee, tagged UMTH-VSF, which is led by the hospital’s Chairman Medical Advisory Council (CMAC) to handle the administration of the grant in the most transparent and credible manner ever, even as he listed a seven-point terms of reference to ensure transparency.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://leadership.ng/news/452057/boko-haram-danjuma-committee-releases-n140m-to-7-north-east-hospitals/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Prepare For Drought, NEMA Warns Nigerians</title>
		<link>http://leadership.ng/news/452055/prepare-for-drought-nema-warns-nigerians</link>
		<comments>http://leadership.ng/news/452055/prepare-for-drought-nema-warns-nigerians#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 04:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kelvin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontpage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://leadership.ng/?p=452055</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="225" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/nema_logo-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="nema_logo" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div>The National Emergency Management Agency (NEMA) yesterday advised Nigerians to prepare for possible drought in the country. NEMA’s warning followed the prediction of heavy rainfall by the Nigeria Meteorological Agency (NIMET). The North West coordinator of NEMA, Musa Illalah, gave the advice in Kaduna during a workshop on liquid and solid waste management in the...]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="225" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/nema_logo-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="nema_logo" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div><p>The National Emergency Management Agency (NEMA) yesterday advised Nigerians to prepare for possible drought in the country.</p>
<p>NEMA’s warning followed the prediction of heavy rainfall by the Nigeria Meteorological Agency (NIMET).</p>
<p>The North West coordinator of NEMA, Musa Illalah, gave the advice in Kaduna during a workshop on liquid and solid waste management in the context of flood mitigation.</p>
<p>Represented by the director, Administration of the agency, Amina Ahman, Illalah said the implication of the NIMET alert was that the rain may exceed the normal rate and states in the North ought to anticipate drought.</p>
<p>&#8220;The implication is that there might be water surplus and increase in stream flow which will affect dams storage for municipal water supply, may affect hydro power generation and irrigation.</p>
<p>&#8220;Therefore, the development and regular maintenance of dams for dry season irrigation and water supply must be accorded high priority during this time.</p>
<p>&#8220;In the same vein, there may be shortage of rainfall; we must also be prepared for drought and the mitigation of its impact.’’</p>
<p>He said that the workshop was to articulate the problem of solid waste management which exacerbate negative impact of flooding in the country.</p>
<p>The coordinator urged the participants to develop effective and efficient management model through collaboration with all stakeholders.</p>
<p>in order to address the problem.</p>
<p>Also speaking, Mahmood Shehu, Director, Disaster Management, Kaduna State Emergency Management Agency said that the state government had embarked on the enforcement of public health and environmental laws.</p>
<p>He said that ensuring adequate risk assessment, planning, early warning, information management and communication systems were basis of curbing disasters.</p>
<p>Shehu advised residents to stop developing houses on water ways and to always maintain their drains to avert flooding.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://leadership.ng/news/452055/prepare-for-drought-nema-warns-nigerians/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boko Haram: Saraki Seeks Foreign Assistance To Rebuild North-East</title>
		<link>http://leadership.ng/news/452053/boko-haram-saraki-seeks-foreign-assistance-to-rebuild-north-east</link>
		<comments>http://leadership.ng/news/452053/boko-haram-saraki-seeks-foreign-assistance-to-rebuild-north-east#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 04:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kelvin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontpage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://leadership.ng/?p=452053</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="225" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/senate-president-bukola-saraki-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="senate president bukola saraki" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div>The President of the Nigerian Senate, Senator Abubakar Bukola Saraki, yesterday solicited the assistance of the international community for the on-going efforts by the Federal Government to end insurgency in the North-eastern part of the country and, thereafter, rebuild the region and rehabilitate its people. Saraki made the call at separate sessions he had with...]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="225" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/senate-president-bukola-saraki-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="senate president bukola saraki" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div><p>The President of the Nigerian Senate, Senator Abubakar Bukola Saraki, yesterday solicited the assistance of the international community for the on-going efforts by the Federal Government to end insurgency in the North-eastern part of the country and, thereafter, rebuild the region and rehabilitate its people.</p>
<p>Saraki made the call at separate sessions he had with the German Ambassador to Nigeria, Michael Zenner and his Spanish counterpart, Alfonso Barnudo Sabastian De Erice, who paid courtesy visits to him in Abuja.</p>
<p>In a press statement issued by his media office, Saraki pointed out that alleviating the humanitarian situation and level of destruction in the region would require urgent and global support across the world.</p>
<p>Saraki said, having led a delegation of the Senate to visit the IDPs camps in Maiduguri on Monday for an on-the-spot assessment, it had become clear that the Federal Government alone can hardly foot the bills for total rehabilitation of the people and rebuilding of infrastructure damaged as a result of the activities of the insurgents.</p>
<p>“As you talked about insecurity, particularly the insurgency in the North-east, it is a problem that we alone cannot tackle. A couple of days ago, some of us were there in the region, in Borno State, to see the effects on the entire community, particularly the internally displaced persons. I think that it is clear that a large part of the North-east is in need of reconstruction and rehabilitation from long-term funding,” Saraki said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile the Deputy Senate President, Senator Ike Ekweremadu, has reassured Nigerians that the Senate will take all necessary legislative steps to moblise resources for the reconstruction of the Northeastern region of the country and the resettlement of internally displaced persons, IDPs, in the region.</p>
<p>Senator Ekweremadu gave the assurances when he led a delegation of the Senate to visit IDPs’ camps in Adamawa State yesterday.</p>
<p>Ekweremadu stressed that the region’s problems had wider negative impacts on every part of Nigeria and, therefore, must be collectively addressed as a Nigerian problem.</p>
<p>According to a statement issued by his Ekweremadu’s special adviser on media, Uche Anichukwu, the delegation was in Adamawa to see the saddening living conditions of the people they represent, stressing that the delegation had “gone round and have noted with deep sadness the magnitude of destruction and human suffering engendered by insurgency in the North East part of our country”.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://leadership.ng/news/452053/boko-haram-saraki-seeks-foreign-assistance-to-rebuild-north-east/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revisiting Lawmakers’ Jumbo Pay, Expenditure</title>
		<link>http://leadership.ng/news/452051/revisiting-lawmakers-jumbo-pay-expenditure</link>
		<comments>http://leadership.ng/news/452051/revisiting-lawmakers-jumbo-pay-expenditure#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 04:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kelvin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontpage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://leadership.ng/?p=452051</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="223" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/National-Assembly-logo-300x223.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="National Assembly logo" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div>The National Assembly has lent its support to a review of its expenditure and the official publication of the breakdown of all salaries and allowances received by federal lawmakers to correct the conflicting figures in public domain. EDEGBE ODEMWINGIE writes.  Monitors rank Nigerian federal lawmakers as the highest paid in the world. In budget allocation,...]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="223" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/National-Assembly-logo-300x223.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="National Assembly logo" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div><p><em>The National Assembly has lent its support to a review of its expenditure and the official publication of the breakdown of all salaries and allowances received by federal lawmakers to correct the conflicting figures in public domain. EDEGBE ODEMWINGIE writes. </em></p>
<p>Monitors rank Nigerian federal lawmakers as the highest paid in the world. In budget allocation, between 2005 and 2015 the National Assembly has received thus: 2005 (N54.79Billion); 2006 (N54.79Billion); 2007 (N66.4Billion); 2008   (N114.39Billion) 2009 (N158.92Billion); 2010 (N 150Billion); 2011 (N 150Billion); 2012 (N150Billion); 2013 (N150Billion); 2014 (N150Billion) and N120billion for 2015.</p>
<p>A widespread perception is that despite Nigeria’s dwindling resources and economic challenges, federal lawmakers continue to collect “jumbo” salaries and allowances. With criticisms mounting over frequent recess and huge cost of maintaining the country’s bi-cameral legislature, Nigerian lawmakers have come under heavy attack for taking huge chunks of the national budget, prompting calls in some quarters for a part-time or uni-cameral legislature.</p>
<p>The harsher critic have demanded a pay cut for federal lawmakers.</p>
<p>August 2013, former Vice-President of the World Bank (Africa) and former Minister of Education, Mrs. Obiageli Ezekwesili while delivering a keynote address at a Civil Society Roundtable on “Cost of Governance” hosted by the Civil Society Legislative advocacy Centre (CISLAC), called attention to what she termed the fundamentally unsustainable economic structure that has caused Nigeria’s development over the last 53 years to lag behind those of countries with similar political history resulting in high poverty level of 69 per cent of our citizens according to the National Bureau of Statistics.</p>
<p>Executive director, Conscience Nigeria, Comrade Tosin Adeyanju submits that in terms of lawmakers’ salary as ratio GDP per capital, the salary of the Nigerian federal lawmaker is 116 times the country’s GDP per person.</p>
<p>Adeyanju demanded that the Nigerian legislature be made a part-time one, in view of the high cost of maintaining the National Assembly and frequent recess embarked on by federal lawmakers.</p>
<p>Section 63 of the 1999 Constitution (as amended) states: “The Senate and the House of Representatives shall each sit for a period of not less than one hundred and eighty-one days in a year” – allowing the lawmakers one hundred and eighty-four days in a year (half a year basically) to engage in other business.</p>
<p>The lawmakers in defence of their work, have insisted that even when they are on recess, legislative work at committee level has always continued. But this is debatable.</p>
<p>Again, federal lawmakers in defence of their budgetary allocations say monies received annually service it’s legislative institute, the bureaucracy and 469 National Assembly members &#8211; 109 Senators and 360 House of Representatives members.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>‘Open books’</p>
<p>The Majority Leader of the House of Representatives, Femi Gbajabiamila has called on the National Assembly to publish the breakdown of all salaries and allowances received by federal lawmakers to correct conflicting figures being paraded by the public.</p>
<p>Gbajabiamila said the official disclosure was necessary and in line with the current campaign to ensure full disclosure into the activities or funding in all tiers and arms of government.</p>
<p>“Until you open up your books to the public, let them look at how much you earn, and break that payment down into sub-heads, and what that payment is for, it is after you open that up, that the debate on whether it is too much or too little, can now begin. For instance, if you bring it down, say for transportation, this is how much a lawmaker gets, the public can determine whether that X amount is too much for transportation or not.</p>
<p>“But to roll everything up in a ball park&#8230;there are a lot of conflicting figures, you leave yourself vulnerable to speculation as a legislator, if you are not transparent and you don’t open up your books. So I am for the National Assembly to open up its book to the public, publish it,” Gbajabiamila said.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Official figures</p>
<p>According to the Revenue Mobilisation Allocation and Fiscal Commission (RMAFC) which fixes salaries and allowances for officials of the three arms of government, allowances that accrue to federal lawmakers include accommodation, under which each Senator gets N 4 million while each House of Reps member gets N3.97 million. As vehicle loan, each Senator takes N8 million, while Reps collect N7.94 million. The furniture allowance for each Senator is N6 million, while Reps’ furniture allowance stands at N5.956 million for each member. Severance gratuity for each Senator N6.09 million, for Reps, it is N5.956 million. Like the vehicle loan, severance gratuities are paid only once in 4 years.</p>
<p>Other annual allowances include those for motor vehicle fuelling and maintenance, for which Senators are entitled to N1.52 million each and their House of Reps counterparts pocket N1.489 million. Constituency, Senators get N5 million, Reps N1.985 million, domestic staff allowance for Senators amounts to N1.519 million while each Rep takes N1.488million.</p>
<p>Federal lawmakers are also given allowance for personal assistants, for each Senator, the figure is N506,600 while for Reps it is N496,303, for entertainment, Senators take home N607,920 and Reps N595,563, recess allowance for Senators stands at N202,640 and N198,521 for Reps.</p>
<p>Senators get N607,920 for utilities as against N397,042 for Reps. For newspaper/periodicals, N303,960 accrues to each Senator and N297,781 to each Rep, house maintenance for Senators, N101,320 and for Reps,N99,260 while wardrobe allowance for Senators is N506,600 and Reps are given N496,303 for the same purpose.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Senate President, Bukola Saraki, has promised to setup an adhoc committee to reappraise the structure of the National Assembly budget in line with current economic realities. Saraki decried the unsustainable cost of governance in the country and the rising cost of doing business, insisting that since Nigerians voted for change, they expect an improvement in the quality of governance.</p>
<p>House Speaker, Yakubu Dogara insists that federal legislators do not collect jumbo pay as insinuated by the public, urging whoever is in doubt to request for the amount through the Freedom of Information Act. He however said the House is already discussing the allowances being paid to the legislators, assuring that the matter will be put on the front burner soon.</p>
<p>Already, the House has commissioned civil society organisations and international development organisations to conduct a “needs assessment” to determine priority areas as well as needs and gaps of the 8th National Assembly.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://leadership.ng/news/452051/revisiting-lawmakers-jumbo-pay-expenditure/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Court Transfers Suit Against Saraki, Ekweremadu’s Election</title>
		<link>http://leadership.ng/news/452049/court-transfers-suit-against-saraki-ekweremadus-election</link>
		<comments>http://leadership.ng/news/452049/court-transfers-suit-against-saraki-ekweremadus-election#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 04:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kelvin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontpage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://leadership.ng/?p=452049</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="225" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/bukola-saraki-and-ike-ekweremadu-senate-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="bukola-saraki-and-ike-ekweremadu-senate" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div>Justice Gabriel Kolawole of a Federal High Court has transferred the suit filed by five senators of the All Progressives Congress [APC], seeking the removal of Senate President, Bukola Saraki from office. The senators, Abu Ibrahim, Kabiru Marafa, Ajayi Boroffice, Gbenga Ashafa, and Suleiman Othman Hunyuki, in the suit are seeking the nullification of the...]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="225" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/bukola-saraki-and-ike-ekweremadu-senate-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="bukola-saraki-and-ike-ekweremadu-senate" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div><p>Justice Gabriel Kolawole of a Federal High Court has transferred the suit filed by five senators of the All Progressives Congress [APC], seeking the removal of Senate President, Bukola Saraki from office.</p>
<p>The senators, Abu Ibrahim, Kabiru Marafa, Ajayi Boroffice, Gbenga Ashafa, and Suleiman Othman Hunyuki, in the suit are seeking the nullification of the elections of Bukola Saraki and his deputy, Ike Ekweremadu, over allegation of forgery.</p>
<p>The judge took the decision based on the fact that he will not have sufficient time to hear the matter as his tenure as a vacation judge expires Friday this week.</p>
<p>Accordingly, he directed counsel to the plaintiffs to serve fresh hearing notices on all respondents and adjourned case to August 13, 2015 to be heard by Justice Adeniyi Ademola of court six.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the Senate President, Abubakar Saraki [1st defendant] is contesting that he was not properly served with the originating summons and other processes relating to the case.</p>
<p>Saraki, through his lawyer, Malam Yusuf Ali [SAN] told the court that the court processes were served on the Office of the Senate President by the bailiff of the court as against personal service required by order 6 Rule 12 of the Federal High Court Rules.</p>
<p>Mr. Sikiru Oke, who announced his appearance for Saraki on behalf of Yusuf Ali yesterday protested the mode of service in court.</p>
<p>But he was swiftly overruled by the court following opposition by counsel to plaintiff’s team headed by Mamman Mike Osuman [SAN] and Dele Adesina [SAN].</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://leadership.ng/news/452049/court-transfers-suit-against-saraki-ekweremadus-election/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>RCCG Convention: 38 Babies Born At Redemption Camp In 2 Days</title>
		<link>http://leadership.ng/news/452047/rccg-convention-38-babies-born-at-redemption-camp-in-2-days</link>
		<comments>http://leadership.ng/news/452047/rccg-convention-38-babies-born-at-redemption-camp-in-2-days#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 04:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kelvin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontpage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://leadership.ng/?p=452047</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Redeemed Christian Church of God (RCCG) commenced its 63rd convention on Monday, August 3, 2015, with 17 boys and 21 girls said to have been delivered during the programme as at 8p.m. on Tuesday. This was disclosed by the General Overseer of RCCG, Pastor Enoch Adeboye shortly before he gave a sermon, titled, &#8220;As...]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Redeemed Christian Church of God (RCCG) commenced its 63rd convention on Monday, August 3, 2015, with 17 boys and 21 girls said to have been delivered during the programme as at 8p.m. on Tuesday.</p>
<p>This was disclosed by the General Overseer of RCCG, Pastor Enoch Adeboye shortly before he gave a sermon, titled, &#8220;As Pure As Light&#8221;.</p>
<p>The convention with the theme, &#8220;The All Sufficient God&#8221; drew people from all over the world to the Redemption Camp situated at Km. 46, Lagos/Ibadan Expressway. At the opening of the programme, children from various parishes were given opportunity to sing and stage drama that depicted the theme of the programme.</p>
<p>Teachers and students of both private and public schools stormed the camp to pray to the all sufficient God for their various needs.</p>
<p>It is expected that traffic would be heavy along Lagos/Ibadan Expressway from Friday to Sunday this week as people from all walks of life would troop to the camp for the programmes slated for the days, especially the Friday Holy Ghost Service.</p>
<p>Pastor Adeboye had earlier warned that this year&#8217;s convention is not business as usual, saying that anyone that is not serious about praying should not venture to come to the camp.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://leadership.ng/news/452047/rccg-convention-38-babies-born-at-redemption-camp-in-2-days/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Keyamo, CSOs Petition COAS Over Killing Of Vigilante Head</title>
		<link>http://leadership.ng/news/452046/keyamo-csos-petition-coas-over-killing-of-vigilante-head</link>
		<comments>http://leadership.ng/news/452046/keyamo-csos-petition-coas-over-killing-of-vigilante-head#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 04:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kelvin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontpage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://leadership.ng/?p=452046</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="160" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/keyamo-300x160.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="keyamo" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div>Following the alleged extra-judicial killing of head of vigilante group in Edo State, Benson Ogedegbe, who was allegedly shot dead by soldiers, civil society groups through Festus Keyamo Chambers have petitioned the Chief of Army Staff (COAS), Gen Tukur Buratai, over the matter. The groups called for a “comprehensive investigation into the activities of officers...]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="160" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/keyamo-300x160.jpg" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="keyamo" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div><p>Following the alleged extra-judicial killing of head of vigilante group in Edo State, Benson Ogedegbe, who was allegedly shot dead by soldiers, civil society groups through Festus Keyamo Chambers have petitioned the Chief of Army Staff (COAS), Gen Tukur Buratai, over the matter.</p>
<p>The groups called for a “comprehensive investigation into the activities of officers and men of the 19 Battalion, Koko, Delta State with a view to prosecuting culpable offenders and prevent breakdown of law and order in the community”</p>
<p>Meanwhile, civil society groups in the state yesterday agreed to set up a task force on extra judicial killings. They also urged the state government to set up similar body to carry out comprehensive data gathering of such cases in the state and beyond.</p>
<p>The CSOs called on Governor Adams Oshiomhole to fulfil his promise to set up a Public Defenders Agency to give legal aid to persons who have been victimised, but lack financial resources for legal fees.</p>
<p>This suggestion was made by the Executive Director, African Network for Environment and Economic Justice (ANEEJ) Rev David Ugolor when leaders and members of the Network of Civil Societies of Nigeria (NOCSON) paid a congratulatory visit to him on his recent appointment by the African Bar Association (AFBA) as its Senior Advisor on Corruption and Governance.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://leadership.ng/news/452046/keyamo-csos-petition-coas-over-killing-of-vigilante-head/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Malaria: Sultan Urges Communities To Facilitate Use Of Treated Nets</title>
		<link>http://leadership.ng/news/452043/malaria-sultan-urges-communities-to-facilitate-use-of-treated-nets</link>
		<comments>http://leadership.ng/news/452043/malaria-sultan-urges-communities-to-facilitate-use-of-treated-nets#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 04:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kelvin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontpage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://leadership.ng/?p=452043</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="273" height="300" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/sultan-of-sokoto_41-273x300.gif" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="sultan-of-sokoto_41" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div>His eminence, the Sultan of Sokoto, Alhaji Sa’ad Abubakar III, has tasked communities to assist in behavioral change regarding adequate use of the long lasting insecticide treated net (LLIN) to help in the fight against malaria in Sokoto State. He made the call during a one day workshop organised by AMSAS Development and Public Health...]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="273" height="300" src="http://leadership.ng/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/sultan-of-sokoto_41-273x300.gif" class="attachment-medium wp-post-image" alt="sultan-of-sokoto_41" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" /></div><p>His eminence, the Sultan of Sokoto, Alhaji Sa’ad Abubakar III, has tasked communities to assist in behavioral change regarding adequate use of the long lasting insecticide treated net (LLIN) to help in the fight against malaria in Sokoto State.</p>
<p>He made the call during a one day workshop organised by AMSAS Development and Public Health Consultant, in collaboration with National Malaria Elimination Programme and the Federal Ministry of Health held at the auditorium of the Sultan Muhammadu Institute Sokoto.</p>
<p>The sultan who was represented by the <em>Uban Doman gari,</em> Alhaji Muhammad Bello, urged the participants to ensure adequate usage of the treated net and also endeavor to change attitude within their respective communities.</p>
<p>In his speech during the workshop, the Project Director and Programme consultant, Amsag Development &amp; Public Health Consultant, Dr. Abdullah Mai Wada said, from the commencement of the project six months ago, over 230 communities have been reached with over 2.3million of long lasting insecticides nets distributed across the 23 local government areas in the state.</p>
<p>He stressed the roles of AMASAG Development and Public Health Consulting as an organisation that secured contract at very comparative charges to go round all the 230 communities to educate, and enlighten the public across the three senatorial zones on proper use and hanging of LLIN.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://leadership.ng/news/452043/malaria-sultan-urges-communities-to-facilitate-use-of-treated-nets/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
