<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Guardian Nigeria &#187; Policy &amp; Politics</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/features/policy-a-politics/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com</link>
	<description>Breaking News and In depth News Analysis of Issues from Nigeria, Africa and around the world.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 09:37:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.2.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Dickson, Alamieyeseigha not sent out of Bayelsa peace meeting- PDP</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/dickson-alamieyeseigha-not-sent-out-of-bayelsa-peace-meeting-pdp/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/dickson-alamieyeseigha-not-sent-out-of-bayelsa-peace-meeting-pdp/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 08:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NAN]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy & Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=41180</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Peoples Democratic Party (PDP), said Bayelsa governor, Seriake Dickson and former governor of the state, Diepreye Alamieyeseigha, were never sent out of PDP Fact Finding Committee meeting in Bayelsa. This is contained in a statement signed by the PDP National Vice Chairman, South-South and Secretary, Dr Cairo Ojougboh, in Abuja on Wednesday. It stated that [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/dickson-alamieyeseigha-not-sent-out-of-bayelsa-peace-meeting-pdp/">Dickson, Alamieyeseigha not sent out of Bayelsa peace meeting- PDP</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/pdp-logo1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2995 alignleft" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/pdp-logo1-300x225.jpg" alt="pdp-logo1" width="300" height="225" /></a>Peoples Democratic Party (PDP), said Bayelsa governor, Seriake Dickson and former governor of the state, Diepreye Alamieyeseigha, were never sent out of PDP Fact Finding Committee meeting in Bayelsa.</p>
<p>This is contained in a statement signed by the PDP National Vice Chairman, South-South and Secretary, Dr Cairo Ojougboh, in Abuja on Wednesday.</p>
<p>It stated that the clarification was necessary following false media reports that the two politicians were sent out of the party&#8217;s peace meeting at Otueke, Bayelsa, on Aug. 1.</p>
<p>&#8220;I, Ojougboh on the instruction of Dr Haliru Bello, the Chairman Board of Trustee (BOT), who is also the Chairman of the committee, hereby affirm that at no time were these two great party men asked out of the meeting.</p>
<p>&#8220;The committee met with the governor and State Exco on one hand, the former President Dr Goodluck Jonathan and the aggrieved party members on the other hand separately,&#8221; Ojogboh said.</p>
<p>It stated that the committee had a very good outing which resulted in the recall of the suspended and expelled party members in Bayelsa.</p>
<p>&#8220;The recalled members were pleased to return to the party.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The party wishes to state that this misinformation is the hand work of the All Progressives Congress (APC), as they are afraid of the outcome of the reconciliation in the party.</p>
<p>&#8220;We, therefore, urge the PDP Bayelsa, to discountenance these mischief makers, bind and bond properly as we move to retain Bayelsa in the forthcoming gubernatorial election,&#8221; it stated.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/dickson-alamieyeseigha-not-sent-out-of-bayelsa-peace-meeting-pdp/">Dickson, Alamieyeseigha not sent out of Bayelsa peace meeting- PDP</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/dickson-alamieyeseigha-not-sent-out-of-bayelsa-peace-meeting-pdp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aregbesola tasks professionals on building collapse</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/aregbesola-tasks-professionals-on-building-collapse/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/aregbesola-tasks-professionals-on-building-collapse/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 06:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tunji Omofoye, Osogbo]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy & Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=41159</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Osun State Governor, Rauf Aregbesola has called on the Nigerian Institute of Building [NIB} to check the menace of building collapse, which has become a common feature in the society.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/aregbesola-tasks-professionals-on-building-collapse/">Aregbesola tasks professionals on building collapse</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_32183" style="width: 400px;" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Gov.-Aregbesola.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-32183" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Gov.-Aregbesola.jpg" alt="Gov. Aregbesola" width="400" height="300" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Gov. Aregbesola</figcaption></figure>
<p>Osun State Governor, Rauf Aregbesola has called on the Nigerian Institute of Building [NIB} to check the menace of building collapse, which has become a common feature in the society.</p>
<p>Aregbesola gave the charge at the University of Ibadan Conference Centre, Oyo State, where he was honoured by the Institute during its 45th annual conference.</p>
<p>He reiterated his administration commitment not to allow the economic recess which has hit many states in the country to hinder its efforts to give Osun a facelift through its carefully planned urbanisation programme He said urbanisation and other efforts aimed at transforming communities in the state would be pursued vigorously despite the limited resources n realisation that the built environment is the crowning glory of all civilisation.</p>
<p>A statement by the Director,Bureau of Communications and Strategy, Office of the Governor, Semiu Okalawon said Aregbesola was deemed fit for the award because of his several landmark achievements which include massive construction of roads, mega schools, hospitals, new markets, security, school feeding programme and others Aregbesola commended the institute for identifying with the successes of his administration in Osun despite what he called targeted and sustained attacks and criticisms from opposition ‎of his government over inability to pay salaries promptly. ‎</p>
<p>Dignitaries present at the event included Oyo State Governor, Abiola Ajimobi, President, Nigerian Institute of Building, Builder Tunde Lasabi, former Head of Service of the Federation, Prof. Oladapo Afolabi, Vice Chancellor, University of Ibadan, Prof Isaac Adewole and others.</p>
<p>The governor also lauded the institute for its efforts at improving the environment and for imposing standard on building construction tasked members of the institute to tackle the challenge of building collapse in the country.</p>
<p>He said, ‘‘an accompanying problem of regulation failure is building collapse, which has become a scourge of the cities. Buildings, even those still under construction, have been in free-fall, sometimes killing people and causing grievous bodily harm. I have no doubt that these are of serious concerns to your body and you are seriously addressing it”. ‎</p>
<p>Aregbesola stressed that his administration has returned sanity to the built environment with the need to make buildings in Osun safe and create a beautiful environment at the same time.</p>
<p>The governor while describing the built environment in Osun as challenging stressed that most of the cities in the state that would qualify as urban centres are historical places, existing for more than 500 years. ‎</p>
<p>According to him, “When our administration came into office, we did an assessment of the condition of urban centres in the state and discovered that the cities were built with wealth realised from exported cash crops.</p>
<p>But when this economy collapsed, the houses built from this wealth suffered neglect and were collapsing too. ‎ “By our assessment, we discovered that 38,000 buildings have become dilapidated and deteriorating and will need urgent separation and consequently rebuilding. “The urgent task before us is to renew the urban centres, upgrade the slums and build future cities.‎ Through the renewal programme, we are transforming the urban centres into modern ones. ‎</p>
<p>He noted that nine cities of Osogbo, Ilesa, Ile-Ife, Ikire, Ejigbo, Ede, Iwo, Ikirun and Ila-Orangun are under the renewal exercise covering a kilometre radius from the Oba’s palace, regarded as the centre of town in each city.</p>
<p>Aregbesola pointed out that his administration has renewed negotiation with the UN-Habitat by paying counterpart fund of N100 million.</p>
<p>Other cities, besides the initial nine, will receive similar attention in due course. He emphasised that plans for the towns and cities are long-range plans, which will cover a radius of 25 kilometres.</p>
<p>He held that such plans are meant to lay a solid foundation for the development of the towns and cities for the next 20 years, as well as help assuage the problems of urbanisation in the state.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/aregbesola-tasks-professionals-on-building-collapse/">Aregbesola tasks professionals on building collapse</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/aregbesola-tasks-professionals-on-building-collapse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mimiko sacks aides</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/mimiko-sacks-aides/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/mimiko-sacks-aides/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 06:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwaseun Akingboye, Akure]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy & Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=41157</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Ondo State Governor, Dr Olusegun Mimiko has announced the disengagement of his Special Assistants (SAs) and Senior Special Assistants (SSAs).</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/mimiko-sacks-aides/">Mimiko sacks aides</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Mimiko.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-41158" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Mimiko.jpg" alt="Mimiko" width="400" height="300" /></a>Ondo State Governor, Dr Olusegun Mimiko has announced the disengagement of his Special Assistants (SAs) and Senior Special Assistants (SSAs).</p>
<p>The Governor relieved his aides of their appointments shortly after 16 new local government caretaker chairmen were sworn into office.</p>
<p>Mimiko, at a meeting with the outgoing aides yesterday at the Babafunke Ajasin Auditorium, Alagbaka, Akure thanked all the outgoing aides for their selfless services to his government and the state at large.</p>
<p>He solicited their continued support for his administration saying that the disengagement has become necessary in view of the restructuring and repositioning efforts of government for better service delivery.</p>
<p>I can only thank you for your services to the government and people of this State who elected us for the delivery of sundry democratic dividends.</p>
<p>I appreciate your selflessness and dedication and wish you well in your future endeavours,” Mimiko said. The Governor therefore prayed that the good Lord reward the outgoing aides as they have contributed immensely to his government and the state during their period in office.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/mimiko-sacks-aides/">Mimiko sacks aides</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/mimiko-sacks-aides/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adebule dissociates self from cyber fraudsters</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/adebule-dissociates-self-from-cyber-fraudsters/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/adebule-dissociates-self-from-cyber-fraudsters/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 05:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Seye Olumide]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy & Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=41097</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>LAGOS State Deputy-Governor, Dr. Idiat Oluranti Adebule yesterday alerted the general public that some unscrupulous elements have been using her name and other particulars on the social media, notably the Facebook to dupe innocent members of the public.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/adebule-dissociates-self-from-cyber-fraudsters/">Adebule dissociates self from cyber fraudsters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_41098" style="width: 400px;" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Adebule.jpg"><img class="wp-image-41098 size-full" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Adebule.jpg" alt="Adebule" width="400" height="300" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Adebule</figcaption></figure>
<p>LAGOS State Deputy-Governor, Dr. Idiat Oluranti Adebule yesterday alerted the general public that some unscrupulous elements have been using her name and other particulars on the social media, notably the Facebook to dupe innocent members of the public.</p>
<p>She urged the general public to be wary of such cyber fraudsters in order not to fall victim of the practice in her name.</p>
<p>In a statement by the Public Relations Officer in the office of the Deputy Governor, Desoye Oyelami, Dr. Adebule expressed concerns over this fraudulent practice, disclosing that one of such fraudsters recently linked her with one deceptive “Federal Government Empowerment Scheme, which was advertised on Facebook account using the details of the deputy governor in the ploy to dupe the public.</p>
<p>The statement reads in part: “We wish to bring to your attention, the activities of Cyber Fraudsters and some impostors, impersonating Her Excellency, Dr. Idiat Oluranti Adebule, the Deputy Governor of Lagos State, via social media platforms (Facebook) with the intention of defrauding unsuspecting citizens.</p>
<p>They are attempting to capitalize on her good will to dupe members of the public particularly her associates and members of her religious organization.”</p>
<p>The statement added that efforts are on the top gear to apprehend those behind this mischievous act in due course. She therefore urged Nigerians to disregard any form of financial appeal via social media be it for her own personal use or government as may be directed by the cyber fraudsters, warning that she has not at any time made such appeal either in person or through any agent on social media platform or other channels.</p>
<p>She also charged members of the public who may come across such fraudulent messages to disregard them and report such account or site to the appropriate law enforcement agencies so as to stop this criminal act and ensure that those behind such notorious acts are brought to book to serve as a deterrent to others.</p>
<p>The Deputy Governor disclosed further that she has suspended all her social media activities, while the public will be duly informed on the platforms to use in sharing ideas and opinions on government policies and programmes in the near future.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/adebule-dissociates-self-from-cyber-fraudsters/">Adebule dissociates self from cyber fraudsters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/adebule-dissociates-self-from-cyber-fraudsters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>‘No matter where  their votes went, the Igbo deserve positions in APC government’ </title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/no-matter-where-their-votes-went-the-igbo-deserve-positions-in-apc-government/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/no-matter-where-their-votes-went-the-igbo-deserve-positions-in-apc-government/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 02:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NKECHI ONYEDIKA-UGOEZE]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy & Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=41095</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Controversy over pace of government It depends on the area you have in mind; one area everybody is anxiously watching out for is the area of setting up the Federal Executive Council (FEC), which is the body with which the President will run the country</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/no-matter-where-their-votes-went-the-igbo-deserve-positions-in-apc-government/">‘No matter where  their votes went, the Igbo deserve positions in APC government’ </a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_41096" style="width: 400px;" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Nwala.jpg"><img class="wp-image-41096 size-full" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Nwala.jpg" alt="Nwala" width="400" height="300" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Nwala</figcaption></figure>
<p><em>Timothy Uzodinma Nwala, a professor of Philosophy at the University of Abuja and President, Ala Igbo Development Foundation (ADF) spoke to NKECHI ONYEDIKA-UGOEZE about the Buhari presidency, the leadership crisis at the National Assembly and the place of Ndigbo in the current arrangement. Excerpts: </em></p>
<p>Controversy over pace of government It depends on the area you have in mind; one area everybody is anxiously watching out for is the area of setting up the Federal Executive Council (FEC), which is the body with which the President will run the country.</p>
<p>FEC is in the constitution and there are things the President cannot do without FEC otherwise he becomes a sole administrator. I wish he has constituted his cabinet by now.</p>
<p>Anyway, he came from the military and military people are said to be very militaristic, they don’t look for any gaps. I think he wants the government to keep running, that is why he is doing some of the things he is doing but a critic may take him on and say indeed he is behaving like a sole administrator of the country but giving the Nigerian situation and the fact that the National Assembly that is going to confirm his ministers is still in turbulent state.</p>
<p>I don’t even know what would happen if he had submitted the list of his ministers whether they would have been in the mood or they would be fighting while considering it.</p>
<p>Those are the things one has to consider in making a judgment as to what it going on now but I think everybody is getting a bit worried.</p>
<p>But on the other hand, one would also like to know what is happening in the states, have the governors set up their own executive councils or is it part of the general malaise of the Nigerian society? Because everybody is an executive, executive president, executive governor, that culture is one thing all of us should be fighting against.</p>
<p>If President Buhari is serious about change that is one thing himself should also stand up and make sure the constitution is respected and that governors don’t run the states as their private property. He should set the pace and ensure that he govern in accordance to the constitution.</p>
<p>Possibility of the promised change   I remember that when Buhari was the Head of State in the early eighties, many of us were very enthusiastic about the things he did. We supported it and we were not sorry about the people who suffered under the War Against Indiscipline (WAI) except that the people are saying there was some discrimination and favoritism in the way those who committed various ills were taken on.</p>
<p>That some had soft landing while others were seriously dealt with. But I remember again in the area of economy, Buhari as the Head of State then, took some bold steps in trying to get rid of this country having an apron string tied to World Bank and the International Monetary Fund (IMF).</p>
<p>He wanted to end Nigeria taking loan from the World Bank and the IMF for obvious implications, some even said that was part of the reasons he was overthrown.</p>
<p>I do know now we still have the problem of running an independent economy, an economy that is not a victim of both international and local looters because when you start talking of the looting of this country, all these billions they are accusing former governors and others of stealing, where are they keeping the money? Is it within our country or outside the country? If it is outside the country, there must be some form of collusion with outside forces.</p>
<p>So we used to be very enthusiastic about his nationalistic posture then, I don’t know what is going to happen now, many people are saying that by the way he came into power now, there is no way he can stand boldly against some external forces some of which may have been interested in his coming into power.</p>
<p>I know that age is one problem but as a person I believe that if Buhari was the same Buhari of yesterday, he will be very firm in protecting the interest of the country.</p>
<p>But I know that aspect of geo-ethnic problem, there is no way the forces from his zone will not stand between him and the interest of other people because I know the nature of Nigerian politics that those who hold power now, will want others to feel that they hold power and allow others to get whatever they get as gratis.</p>
<p>That is where we are going to have problem. Everybody is watching to see whether Buhari is going to stand tall against these interests from around him and from outside.</p>
<p>South East zone in the current arrangement    Resource and power sharing is not among political parties. It is among the zones. Whether the South East voted for Buhari or not, when they are sharing resources they have their own right.</p>
<p>When they are sharing ministerial positions they have their own right, the same thing with Board appointments. Even if there is no APC man in Igbo land, they cannot say that Igbos won’t get anything.</p>
<p>I also expect that as he really wants to bring change, some of the people he would appoint would be APC members because he can find good and reliable people outside APC, the problem he is going to have by relying only on APC members is that they are going to be expecting some pay back because they put him in power.</p>
<p>They may not even want him to query them when they go wrong but he can query other people. So what I am saying is that Igbos didn’t vote for Buhari doesn’t mean anything in terms of their rights.</p>
<p>Boko Haram suspects in Anambra prisons    It doesn’t make sense sending Boko Haram suspects to Anambra Sate. I think the people have made their views known in unmistakable terms, the traders, Civil Society Organisations, the traditional rulers, the governors and other major stakeholders have said no to it.</p>
<p>Some people said it started from Jonathan but it doesn’t matter when it started, the South East may not blame Jonathan for the action, however, the question is why Ekwulobia of all places?  I learnt so many states in the North even rejected it.</p>
<p>What are they doing with the Boko Haram people? If you prove that they have been responsible for butchering thousands of people, why do you keep them? Buhari is lucky that people are already rejecting it so he has good time to look at it and avoid it. There are examples to learn from in different countries.</p>
<p>You don’t send such people to a place like Anambra. There are parts of this country away from the special areas where you can build mighty prisons and protect it even with a battalion and make sure that when they have served their terms, you rehabilitate those that you think need rehabilitation.</p>
<p>You can send them overseas if you can’t rehabilitate them in this country. Can you see the escalation in their attacks and activities even with Buhari in power? One thing they may have done is to exonerate Buhari from all the accusations that he was behind Boko Haram. I think the relocation of the Boko Haram prisoners should be well thought of.</p>
<p>By sending them to Anambra, you make the place a target for Boko Haram attack. You know how weak our security and intelligence system is in this country.</p>
<p>They have attacked so many places. They attacked fortified prisons in Kogi state using improvised devices, so if you send them to Ekwulobia, you are endangering the people, and it is like importing Boko Haram to Anambra. It should not be done.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/no-matter-where-their-votes-went-the-igbo-deserve-positions-in-apc-government/">‘No matter where  their votes went, the Igbo deserve positions in APC government’ </a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/no-matter-where-their-votes-went-the-igbo-deserve-positions-in-apc-government/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aluko seeks Buhari’s intervention in Ekiti APC crisis</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/aluko-seeks-buharis-intervention-in-ekiti-apc-crisis/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/aluko-seeks-buharis-intervention-in-ekiti-apc-crisis/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Muyiwa Adeyemi (Head South West Bureau, Ado Ekiti)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy & Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=41093</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>FORMER Senate Deputy Chief Whip, Gbenga Aluko has called on President Muhammadu Buhari to intervene in the internal crisis of the Ekiti State chapter of the All Progressive Congress (APC).</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/aluko-seeks-buharis-intervention-in-ekiti-apc-crisis/">Aluko seeks Buhari’s intervention in Ekiti APC crisis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_41094" style="width: 400px;" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Aluko.jpg"><img class="wp-image-41094 size-full" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Aluko.jpg" alt="Aluko" width="400" height="300" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Gbenga Aluko</figcaption></figure>
<p>FORMER Senate Deputy Chief Whip, Gbenga Aluko has called on President Muhammadu Buhari to intervene in the internal crisis of the Ekiti State chapter of the All Progressive Congress (APC).</p>
<p>He also warned members jostling for 2018 governorship ticket of the party to work for the interest of the platform instead of advancing their personal agenda that polarises the party.</p>
<p>Aluko, who dumped the Peoples Democratic Party (PDP) for the APC immediately Governor Ayodele Fayose clinched the party’s ticket last year said he had no regret because “the state deserves better than what they are presently getting from Fayose.</p>
<p>We need peace not crisis”. Aluko, who was on Buhari’s entourage to the United States, being a Director in American Chevron Oil, said President Barack Obama’s resolve to assist in Nigeria’s fight against corruption and sectarian crisis, had raised the hope that the war would be successful.</p>
<p>The member of the fourth Senate advised the APC to continue to seek reconciliation on the crisis surrounding emergence of Senator Bukola Saraki as Senate President, saying “based on the politics of legislature, Saraki hands were tied under the circumstance Senator Ike Ekweremadu emerged his Deputy”.</p>
<p>Speaking in a telephone interview with newsmen in Ado Ekiti, Aluko commended President Buhari for his quick response in seeking global help against corruption and insurgency, describing these as the two most dangerous ills rocking the foundation of the country and reducing its economic viability.</p>
<p>He lamented that the cankerworms of corruption and insurgency have affected every facet of the country’s economy, saying only those that are ignorant of the relevance of the world super power in taming these monsters could condemn such a good step.</p>
<p>Though, I was in Buhari’s entourage because I work with Chevron Nigeria, an American Oil firm, so I have to be there. The PDP had tried to seek America’s help during former President Olusegun Obasanjo and Goodluck Jonathan’s regime.</p>
<p>So, what President Buhari did was not out of place. “Nothing is too much for Nigeria to do to curtail corruption and Boko Haram. President Buhari’s visit was majorly on these two critical areas and the US had given the assurance to repatriate over 150 billion dollars stolen from Nigeria.</p>
<p>This, if actualized, will turn around the country for good. “In diplomatic issue, it is always very hard to get immediate assurances from US.</p>
<p>But for President Obama to have given the nod to help was even a success on its own”, he said. Aluko said the APC has a bright chance of recapturing Ekiti in 2018, urging those declaring ambitions to rather subsume their aspirations and pursue how the party can be unified before it is too late.</p>
<p>I can’t imagine members declaring governorship ambitions for an election that is coming up in 2018. As we speak now, the APC in Ekiti has about six factions and nobody is talking about unity.</p>
<p>I know that President Buhari and our national leaders will intervene, but it should not be too late. “Let all intending aspirants bury their aspirations now.</p>
<p>Let all of us subsume our intentions just for the sake of APC. Let us fight for unity and from there we can begin to say I am going to be this or that. “I decided to leave PDP because I cannot be comfortable under the atmosphere of impunity.</p>
<p>The party held power for 16 years and began to become irresponsible and I cannot continue with it. “The manner by which Fayose emerged as governorship candidate for the 2014 poll was the most unreasonable political machination ever.</p>
<p>What we want in Ekiti is a State everybody can be proud of and not a state that will be crisis-ridden”, Aluko stated.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/aluko-seeks-buharis-intervention-in-ekiti-apc-crisis/">Aluko seeks Buhari’s intervention in Ekiti APC crisis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/aluko-seeks-buharis-intervention-in-ekiti-apc-crisis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>‘I am burning with zeal to unleash Kogi’s potentials’</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/i-am-burning-with-zeal-to-unleash-kogis-potentials/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/i-am-burning-with-zeal-to-unleash-kogis-potentials/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:25:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Seye Olumide]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lead Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy & Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=41091</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>ONE thing Alhaji Yakubu Mohammed, a senior journalist who is set to contest the November 21 governorship election in Kogi State on the platform of the All Progressives Congress (APC), is sure of achieving in the state, if elected is “changing the destiny of Kogi for the better.”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/i-am-burning-with-zeal-to-unleash-kogis-potentials/">‘I am burning with zeal to unleash Kogi’s potentials’</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_41092" style="width: 400px;" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Alhaji-Yakubu-Mohammed.jpg"><img class="wp-image-41092 size-full" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Alhaji-Yakubu-Mohammed.jpg" alt="Alhaji-Yakubu-Mohammed" width="400" height="330" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Alhaji Yakubu Mohammed</figcaption></figure>
<p>ONE thing Alhaji Yakubu Mohammed, a senior journalist who is set to contest the November 21 governorship election in Kogi State on the platform of the All Progressives Congress (APC), is sure of achieving in the state, if elected is “changing the destiny of Kogi for the better.”</p>
<p>Mohammed believes that Kogi State has all it takes to do better in human and physical development more than what the state is capable of doing since its creation in 1991, “if properly governed.”</p>
<p>The co-founder and former Executive Editor of the pace-setting Newswatch Magazine has on many occasions pledged that, “if given the mandate to rule Kogi, I will fulfill the yearnings and aspirations of our people by bringing them into government as a participatory process of governance.</p>
<p>My vision for the development of the state is all encompassing.”   Clearly, from all indications, the vision and aspirations of Mohammed transcends primordial, religion and that of ethnic leanings that is allegedly the norm in the polity of Kogi. He has broad based supporters that cut across all religion and ethnic groups.</p>
<p>This is most likely to put him ahead of other contestants for the governorship job.    Unlike many politicians who are merely attracted to politics due to their greed and selfish interest, Mohammed is one rare breed, who has demonstrated in various capacities that his aspirations to govern Kogi “is mainly because of the modest contributions I have made towards the creation of the state, putting our people in strategic positions in government and attracting development projects to the state.”</p>
<p>On what he intends doing for the people of the state, the aspirant said, “I did not set out, like numerous others, to nurse the ambition to run for the governorship of Kogi state.</p>
<p>People across the state, who have absolute trust in my capabilities, invited me into this project and persuaded me for several months before I agreed to run.</p>
<p>If the voice of the people is the voice of God, then I had no choice but to hearken to the call of the people.   “I feel humbled that many prominent personalities in the state could have such implicit confidence in me to the extent of persuading me to vie for this office so as to rescue the state from apparent stagnation.</p>
<p>And I want to thank those visionary and selfless individuals, who though eminently qualified in their own rights to be governor or even president, have decided that I must be the one to give this project a shot.”   Cardinal Programmes   “Since the creation of Kogi state in 1991, I have followed its progress and most of the time, its travails – the ups and downs.</p>
<p>Whatever problems Kogi State has faced over the years are not peculiar to the state: dwindling funds for programmes and projects arising from national and global economic conditions that have negatively affected governance, infrastructural development, social services like health and education, agriculture and provision of food.</p>
<p>My participation as a member of the Think Tank set up by the Idris Wada administration in January 2012 further opened my eyes to some of the challenges faced by the state and other states in the federation.</p>
<p>To quote our report, the challenges include, ‘‘endemic failure or incapacity of government to meet the aspirations of citizens in the areas of good governance, service delivery, provision of infrastructure and social services among others.”</p>
<p>The reports stated that the challenges also include, “absence of probity, transparency and accountability. Political interference has eroded the ability of officials of government to keep its own laws and operating guidelines.   “The problem of Kogi State as many people have come to appreciate, is like the problem of Nigeria at large – it is largely and squarely the problem of leadership.</p>
<p>This is exactly where I come in. I am driven by the passion to re-engineer the state and to help unleash its potential. I am burning with the zeal to bring equity, fair play, transparency and accountability to governance to promote integrity and leadership by example.”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/i-am-burning-with-zeal-to-unleash-kogis-potentials/">‘I am burning with zeal to unleash Kogi’s potentials’</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/i-am-burning-with-zeal-to-unleash-kogis-potentials/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ondo 2016 guber race: The compass points southwards</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/ondo-2016-guber-race-the-compass-points-southwards/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/ondo-2016-guber-race-the-compass-points-southwards/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 04:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Niyi Bello]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy & Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=40907</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>WITH politicians who had gone into recess after the 2015 general elections gearing up for next year’s gubernatorial contest in Ondo State, a new wave of agitation among the people of the southern part of the state for the top job is sweeping the political landscape. Before now it was almost taken that the next [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/ondo-2016-guber-race-the-compass-points-southwards/">Ondo 2016 guber race: The compass points southwards</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_39066" style="width: 300px;" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/ONDO.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-39066" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/ONDO-300x225.jpg" alt="ONDO" width="300" height="225" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">ONDO</figcaption></figure>
<p>WITH politicians who had gone into recess after the 2015 general elections gearing up for next year’s gubernatorial contest in Ondo State, a new wave of agitation among the people of the southern part of the state for the top job is sweeping the political landscape. Before now it was almost taken that the next governor of the state should come from the northern part. This was based on the arguments that since all the three senatorial zones have had opportunities of producing governors in the current political dispensation and the position should go back to the north that started the rotation in 1999.</p>
<p>The campaign was intensified during the 2012 governorship elections during which the then Action Congress of Nigeria (ACN) zoned the position to the North with the fielding of former President of the Nigerian Bar Association (NBA), Oluwarotimi Akeredolu, SAN. As it is, the hand of the compass seems to be reading south in the build-up to the gubernatorial elections in which the All Progressive Congress (APC) and the Peoples Democratic Party (PDP) are expected to slug it out.</p>
<p>Coming mainly from residents and politicians from the South, the new agitation seemed to be gaining ground. The campaigners argue that although the zone had produced a governor in the person of late Dr. Olusegun Agagu, he was only recognized to have spent only one term. Two years into Agagu’s second term, he lost the position via a judicial pronouncement to incumbent Olusegun Mimiko who challenged his victory at the Election Petition Tribunal.</p>
<p>The southern agitators also claimed that being the area that produced a sizeable chunk of revenue for the state through oil production for which the state derives the statutory 13 percent Oil Mineral Derivation Fund, the zone has not had its fair share of leadership control. And because Agagu was an Ikale, a Yoruba sub-ethnic group that occupies two out of the six local councils in the South, the new agitation is more intense among the other groups in the zone, mainly the Ilaje and Arogbo Ijaw of the coastal Ilaje and Ese-Odo councils and the Ore/Odigbo and Ile-Oluji/Oke-Igbo axis.</p>
<p>While the APC is not expected to act differently from what its precursor, the ACN did in 2012 by zoning the position to the North because of the obvious fact that the party is stronger there, the PDP which by Mimiko’s decampment now rules the state, has more aspirants in the South. The PDP confirmed its control of the southern zone, a trend that had been visible since 1999, in the last elections when it won all the available seats in the area.</p>
<p>This is one of the strongest points of the southern agitators; that the party should pick its candidate from the zone. Although there are other formidable aspirants in the PDP like Gbenga Elegbeleye, former Director-General of the National Sports Commission (NSC) from the North, who over the years has been building a statewide structure, the preponderance of aspirants from the South could swing the pendulum in their favour.</p>
<p>Among the aspirants from the South is Dr. Pius Olakunle Osunyikanmi, the Director-General of the Directorate of Technical Aides Corps (DTAC) and former Presidential Adviser on Foreign Affairs who once headed the State Ministry of Education as the Commissioner. Osunyikanmi, a young politician from Ile-Oluji who like Elegbeleye, has used the offices he had occupied to empower a lot of youths and build a crop of enthusiastic loyalists across the state especially among the youths, is said to be warming up to succeed Mimiko, whom he had served as an aide at the dawn of the current dispensation in 1999 when the latter was Commissioner for Health in Akure and Minister of Housing and Urban Development in Abuja.</p>
<p>Seen by many as the new face of politics in the state, Osunyikanmi, a very strong grassroots politician in his Ile-Oluji/Oke-Igbo local council is believed to have a big following across the state particularly among public servants. Also on the list of aspirants from the zone is Sola Ebiseeni, a fiery lawyer from the oil-producing Ilaje local council and current Commissioner for Environment, a position he is holding for the second time after holding same during the Adebayo Adefarati regime between 1999 and 2003.</p>
<p>Ebiseeni who cut his political teeth as Chairman of the old Ilaje Ese-Odo local council that then covered the whole of the riverrine area of the State in his early thirties during the aborted Third Republic having been invited by Ilaje elites from his Lagos base, has been a recurrent decimal in the politics of the zone. The strong point of Ebiseeni is the resolve of most Ilaje, after the 2012 gubernatorial election experience, to use their strength that manifest in their being the group with the highest number of voters in the zone, to produce the next governor.</p>
<p>Another strong contender from the area is Kingsley Kuku, the immediate past Presidential Adviser on Niger Delta Affairs and Chairman of the Amnesty Programme of the Federal Government, an Ijaw from Arogbo-Ibe who was a member of the State House of Assembly between 2003 and 2007. Kuku, who headed the multi-billion-naira programme that saw to the ending of armed militancy in the once-restive Niger Delta region and management of post-crisis resettlement and rehabilitation of erstwhile militants, is believed to have been building massive consensus across the state to give his minority status the desired boost.</p>
<p>Analysts however believe that only a politician of Kuku’s status with tremendous goodwill in the Niger Delta region could make the dream of a small minority group (covering only half of a local council) becoming the governor of a state like Ondo realizable. Another strong name that has been mentioned is that of Chief Olusola Oke, the most prominent politician from the zone who decamped from the PDP, a party he helped to found and sustained for 16 years, for the APC on the eve of the last April 11 House of Assembly elections.</p>
<p>Described as the most influential living political figure in the zone particularly in his Ilaje area where he had been a political leader and head of the two intervention agencies as Commissioner in the Niger Delta Development Commission (NDDC) and Chairman of the Ondo State Oil-Producing Areas Development Commission (OSOPADEC), Oke, because of the brilliant campaigns he ran during the 2012 gubernatorial poll when he was the candidate of the PDP, is believed by many to be a governor in waiting.</p>
<p>It is however not clear if Oke, who many believe could would have taken the PDP ticket by mere asking if not for his dumping the party, an action believed to have been caused by the manner the PDP apparatus was handed over to Mimiko to the chagrin of those who toiled for the platform, would signify his intention to seek the top seat.</p>
<p>Corroborating this fact, Kuku, Oke’s co-traveler in the PDP boat since 1999 said he decided to contest the governorship seat because the absence of Oke who was also the PDP National Legal Adviser, left a huge leadership vacuum that he hoped to fill with his presence in the race. As the compass reads southwards, it now depends on the dexterity of the players to determine which one of them would succeed Mimiko in February 2017.</p>
<blockquote><p>Coming mainly from residents and politicians from the South, the new agitation seemed to be gaining ground. The campaigners argue that although the zone had produced a governor in the person of late Dr. Olusegun Agagu, he was only recognized to have spent only one term. Two years into Agagu’s second term, he lost the position via a judicial pronouncement to incumbent Olusegun Mimiko who challenged his victory at the Election Petition Tribunal. The southern agitators also claimed that being the area that produced a sizeable chunk of revenue for the state through oil production for which the state derives the statutory 13 percent Oil Mineral Derivation Fund, the zone has not had its fair share of leadership control.=</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/ondo-2016-guber-race-the-compass-points-southwards/">Ondo 2016 guber race: The compass points southwards</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/ondo-2016-guber-race-the-compass-points-southwards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>‘Buhari’s insistence on party supremacy resolved House of Reps leadership crisis’</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/buharis-insistence-on-party-supremacy-resolved-house-of-reps-leadership-crisis/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/buharis-insistence-on-party-supremacy-resolved-house-of-reps-leadership-crisis/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 02:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ADAMU ABUH]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy & Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=40597</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>National Chairman of the All Progressive Congress (APC), Chief John Odigie-Oyegun while speaking to a select group of journalists in Abuja explained how the party, with intervention from the Presidency, was able to resolve the leadership crisis in the House of Representatives. ADAMU ABUH reports</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/buharis-insistence-on-party-supremacy-resolved-house-of-reps-leadership-crisis/">‘Buhari’s insistence on party supremacy resolved House of Reps leadership crisis’</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_40598" style="width: 400px;" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Odigie-Oyegun-Copy.jpg"><img src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Odigie-Oyegun-Copy.jpg" alt="Odigie-Oyegun" width="400" height="300" class="size-full wp-image-40598" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Odigie-Oyegun</figcaption></figure><strong>National Chairman of the All Progressive Congress (APC), Chief John Odigie-Oyegun while speaking to a select group of journalists in Abuja explained how the party, with intervention from the Presidency, was able to resolve the leadership crisis in the House of Representatives. ADAMU ABUH reports</strong></p>
<p><strong>Resolution of the House leadership crisis</strong><br />
WE are glad that the misunderstandings in the House of Representatives have been amicably resolved. Thanks to the intervention of Mr. President who once again made it quite clear with everybody involved in the dispute that there is no alternative but to listen to what the party says. He emphasised the fact that all of us were what we were, what we are today because of the platform that the party provided for everybody. I think his message resonated very intensively with all the members of the House. He still did not interfere and I want to make that very clear. His parting words to us was that the presiding leadership of the House and the party should go and resolve whatever issues there are that was militating against the resolution of the problem and that exactly is what happened.<br />
   <br />
When we were leaving there I promised that within four hours the nation will be glad knowing that this issue would have been resolved and put behind us. We left there and went a few hours later into consultations and discussions with the presiding officers of the House of Representatives. Let me take this opportunity to pay tribute to their maturity to their sense of responsibility, tribute to their loyalty to the party and above all tribute to their sense of general good, meaning the patriotism displayed by the Speaker and his Deputy. It did not take long before the necessary concessions that had to be made were made. The very next day I think you all witnessed the general jubilation that greeted the final resolution of what was proven to be an intractable problem. We have been able to put one behind us; it is still one to go. Everybody has ended up being happy with the solution that was proffered to the problem of party position primarily being upheld.</p>
<p><strong>The presidential intervention</strong><br />
Easily one can say that presidential prestige came to play. That means a lot and it counts for a lot but I won’t want to elaborate further on it. But I want to make it quite clear that we emphasised the fact that the people had not gotten his message before, he was re-emphasising it, that in this political system that we are operating, the party is number one and everybody derives whatever he becomes from the party. I think that finally resonated. <br />
 <br />
<strong>Allegations of marginalization by South East lawmakers</strong><br />
The sharing process is not over and I want everybody to get that very clear. Even in the House of Representatives it is not yet over. All these will be taken into consideration when other positions in the House are being distributed. I have no doubt. Here we are talking of real life, in real life there is no perfection, in real life there are pluses and minuses, in real life there are ups and downs, in real life there are valleys and there are peaks, what is important is that the system functions, the system went out of gear with the very first election that was made. So the planning of the party was disrupted. So you have to walk back and resolve it as best as possible in the circumstances. In human affairs there is no perfection.<br />
 <br />
<strong>APC leadership did not instigate the National Assembly crisis</strong> <br />
We organised primaries for selecting our candidates who wanted to contest for public office, specifically presidential and what happened there was that all the aspirants cooperated. All the aspirants contested and a winner was declared and everybody agreed to work with the winner. In this case for whatever reasons what you called as a mock polls could as well pass as a primary election. But if some candidates say they won’t honour the primary, you can discipline them, of course according to the party regulations. What the party planned is exactly what you are seeing. </p>
<p>Indeed for our elections to select better candidates for the various offices we had to take the step. Human feelings and being what they are in a situation where the voting is limited, very limited. Everybody knows everybody and of course people reacted differently, it was not like our primaries where you have thousands of people forming the electorate, in the Senate we have 59 and in the House we have 220 members as the electorate. </p>
<p>So you can understand why what happened the way it did. Simple, in the case of the House that we have just dealt with it, we got to the bridge but have not crossed it. They had not named any principal officers, so obviously it was a lot easier to handle. The Senate has named its principal officers and by their rules they can only be removed either when they voluntarily resign or when you command a two-third majority to vote them out. So the approaches obviously will be totally different in the sense that, in the Senate also I hear there is a court process underway, that make a lot of issues sub-judicial so it changes the picture. What happened in the House is not enough for us and we are also watching how to engage the Senate and by God’s grace it will also be resolved.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Saraki and Dogara cannot work against the party’s ‘change agenda’</strong><br />
I don’t see how the change agenda will be affected. I will be very sorry for any member of the House who demonstrates objection to any measures or proposed laws which are directed towards the change agenda. Someone will stand up and say he likes corruption to thrive? somebody who will stand up and say we don’t need to do what we need to do to restore peace, that is to defeat the insurgency there, anybody who will stand up to say that the power sector should not be made functional, anybody who will stand to say we should not ask for any billions or trillions of dollars that have been stolen to be refunded or retrieved, that is the change agenda. I don’t think that will happen on both sides of the divide. I do not see that happening in the National Assembly. I don’t see that happening.<br />
 <br />
<strong>EFCC probe of Saraki’s wife</strong><br />
I want to assure you without any doubt that the APC absolutely has nothing to do with it; she is not on trial by the way. You saw all the speculation in the media, as a matter of fact this could have been triggered by the opposition party itself, its branch in Kwara. They have to be nudged to make a denunciation that they were not the originators of the petition or whatever triggered this investigation. We are totally, completely, absolutely, innocent of it. What we have not done like in the PDP days is to rush and say and interfere with the processes of the EFCC which our president has made quite clearly, everybody should be ready to carry out its legitimate functions without interference. The EFCC is doing what it thinks it has to do.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Probing only the Jonathan administration</strong><br />
I am aware that the president knows that he has only 4 years minus 2 months. So it is not 4 years anymore and if he wants to probe Nigeria where does he stop? 16 years? 50 years? Where do you stop when you want to do that kind of probe? What is important is that the level of impunity in the last 6 years has been very monumental. The level of rot in the last 6 years, the extent to which the economy of this nation has been damaged in the last 6 years is phenomenal, absolutely phenomenal. I can’t speak for the President, neither can I speak for the Presidency but I’m not aware there is going to be a formal probe meaning the High Court Judge with a few people sitting with him, but these things are there even if you don’t want to see them, they are sitting right in front of you. The impunity of the corruption is looking at you in the eyes. People were not bothered about hiding anymore, so when talking about probe, you cannot turn without seeing the damage, the theft, massive theft. That is the way I interpret it.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/buharis-insistence-on-party-supremacy-resolved-house-of-reps-leadership-crisis/">‘Buhari’s insistence on party supremacy resolved House of Reps leadership crisis’</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/buharis-insistence-on-party-supremacy-resolved-house-of-reps-leadership-crisis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aisha Buhari laments decline in elected female lawmakers</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/aisha-buhari-laments-decline-in-elected-female-lawmakers/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/aisha-buhari-laments-decline-in-elected-female-lawmakers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 11:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NAN]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy & Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=40503</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Wife of the President, Mrs Aisha Buhari, has expressed concern over decline in the number of female legislature in the 8th Assembly. Aisha spoke on Sunday in Abuja at a reception organised by the Committee of Friends in honour of former Gov. Rotimi Amaechi of Rivers She said that for the nation to attain the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/aisha-buhari-laments-decline-in-elected-female-lawmakers/">Aisha Buhari laments decline in elected female lawmakers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Aisha-Buhari.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-15499" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Aisha-Buhari.jpg" alt="Aisha Buhari" width="409" height="351" /></a>Wife of the President, Mrs Aisha Buhari, has expressed concern over decline in the number of female legislature in the 8th Assembly.</p>
<p>Aisha spoke on Sunday in Abuja at a reception organised by the Committee of Friends in honour of former Gov. Rotimi Amaechi of Rivers</p>
<p>She said that for the nation to attain the 35 per cent affirmative action by 2019, men must encourage and support women to occupy key elective positions in the country.</p>
<p>&#8220;Supporting women to contest elective positions has become imperative as the number of female legislators have declined because some of them lost their seats during the last general elections.</p>
<p>&#8220;As the number of female legislature decline, we wish the men in Nigeria will support the women to attain the 35 per cent affirmative action in 2019,’’ she said.</p>
<p>Aisha specifically commended Chief Bola Tinubu, a chieftain of the APC, for the support given to his wife, Sen. Oluremi, in winning a senatorial seat from Lagos.</p>
<p>She urged men, particularly those in politics,to emulate the former Lagos governor by encouraging their wives to vie for elective positions, come 2019.</p>
<p>Aisha also commended Amaechi for his courageous roles that led to the victory of the APC in this year’s general elections.</p>
<p>She said Amaechi stood firmly by the party, showed commitment, courage and patriotism in ensuring that the country attained the positive change it was yearning for.</p>
<p>The wife of the president noted that as the Director-General of the APC Campaign Organisation, Amaechi showed &#8220;doggedness, toughness and steadfastness’’.</p>
<p>Speaking at the event, the Vice President, Prof. Yemi Osinbajo, described Amaechi as &#8220;a man of tremendous courage, who stood the wrongs in the PDP, even when he was a member of the Party’’</p>
<p>He said that Amaechi’s role in the last election, stood out, and that accounted for why he was being celebrated.</p>
<p>&#8220;One thing I personally admire about him is his forthrightness; his ability to say it like it is, and we have never been in doubt about where he stands on any issue at all.</p>
<p>&#8220;He has the capacity for the big ideas. Any state governor that will build a railway is a man of big ideas,’’ he said.</p>
<p>Osinbajo said that Amaechi’s education policy as governor in Rivers, had given new hope to children, adding that he would not only be remembered by these children, but also by generations to come.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/aisha-buhari-laments-decline-in-elected-female-lawmakers/">Aisha Buhari laments decline in elected female lawmakers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/aisha-buhari-laments-decline-in-elected-female-lawmakers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
