<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Guardian Nigeria &#187; Metro</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/news/metro/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com</link>
	<description>Breaking News and In depth News Analysis of Issues from Nigeria, Africa and around the world.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 09:37:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.2.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Benue police allegedly kill notorious armed robber</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/benue-police-allegedly-kill-notorious-armed-robber/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/benue-police-allegedly-kill-notorious-armed-robber/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 03:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joseph Wantu, Makurdi]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=41150</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>THE Benue State Police Command on Tuesday gunned down a notorious armed robber popularly called Chemical and arrested 10 other suspects in his gang</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/benue-police-allegedly-kill-notorious-armed-robber/">Benue police allegedly kill notorious armed robber</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_23508" style="width: 552px;" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/BENUE-small.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-23508" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/BENUE-small.jpg" alt="Benue state" width="552" height="230" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Benue state</figcaption></figure>
<p><em><strong>Arrest 10 suspected members of the gang </strong></em></p>
<p>THE Benue State Police Command on Tuesday gunned down a notorious armed robber popularly called Chemical and arrested 10 other suspects in his gang.</p>
<p>The Guardian gathered from police sources that the deceased and his members were said to be among those that had been terrorising the people of Sankera geo-political axis of the state.</p>
<p>Confirming the incident, the state Police Public Relations Officer, ASP Daniel Ezeani said his men, acting on a tip-off on the criminals’ hideout, trailed them and on sighting the gang, engaged them in a gun duel, killing their leader and arresting 10 others.</p>
<p>Ezeani said in the course of the action, many other gang members escaped into the bush and were still being trailed by the men of the force.</p>
<p>The PPRO, who called on members of the public to continue to avail the police with useful information about criminals living around them, further said those arrested were being investigated and would soon be charged to court.</p>
<p>It would be recalled that last weekend, an armed gang riding on motorcycles stormed a supermarket in Zaki- Biam and spread bullets on people, killing eight while several others were left with various degrees of injury.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/benue-police-allegedly-kill-notorious-armed-robber/">Benue police allegedly kill notorious armed robber</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/benue-police-allegedly-kill-notorious-armed-robber/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Court remands two men for allegedly kidnapping teenager‎</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/court-remands-two-men-for-allegedly-kidnapping-teenager%e2%80%8e/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/court-remands-two-men-for-allegedly-kidnapping-teenager%e2%80%8e/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 03:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=41147</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>A MINNA Magistrate’s Court yesterday remanded two men, Abubakar Mohammed and Usman Kwari, in prison custody as they admitted kidnapping a teenager.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/court-remands-two-men-for-allegedly-kidnapping-teenager%e2%80%8e/">Court remands two men for allegedly kidnapping teenager‎</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/appeal-court.gif"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-7210" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/appeal-court.gif" alt="appeal-court" width="400" height="300" /></a>A MINNA Magistrate’s Court yesterday remanded two men, Abubakar Mohammed and Usman Kwari, in prison custody as they admitted kidnapping a teenager.</p>
<p>The two were arraigned in court on a two-count charge of criminal conspiracy and kidnapping, contrary to sections 97 and 273 of the Penal Code, the News Agency of Nigeria (NAN) reports.</p>
<p>The prosecutor, Inspector Alfred Auta, told the court that one Alhaji Aliyu reported the matter at the Tegina Police Station on July 27, 2015. Auta said the complainant alleged that the accused persons conspired and invaded his compound and kidnapped his 16-year-old son. The prosecutor said the accused persons were, however, arrested on their way out of town.</p>
<p>When the charges were read to them, they pleaded guilty and begged the court for leniency. The prosecutor told the court that investigation into the matter was still ongoing, and asked for an adjournment to enable the police conclude their investigation.</p>
<p>In her ruling, Magistrate Mariam King ordered the accused persons to be remanded in prison custody and adjourned the case till Aug. 17 for sentencing.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/court-remands-two-men-for-allegedly-kidnapping-teenager%e2%80%8e/">Court remands two men for allegedly kidnapping teenager‎</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/court-remands-two-men-for-allegedly-kidnapping-teenager%e2%80%8e/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bayelsa Police arrest Army deserter, 49 others</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/bayelsa-police-arrest-army-deserter-49-others/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/bayelsa-police-arrest-army-deserter-49-others/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Willie Etim, Yenagoa]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=41101</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>AUTHORITIES of the Bayelsa State Police Command yesterday dismissed as “untrue” the claims by the Civil Liberties Organisation (CLO) that policemen engaged in indiscriminate arrest of innocent people in the State, noting that the routine raids and stop and search operations have led to the arrest of a military deserter and 49 other persons over alleged involvement in armed robbery and other violent crimes in the state.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/bayelsa-police-arrest-army-deserter-49-others/">Bayelsa Police arrest Army deserter, 49 others</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_22204" style="width: 400px;" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/arase-twitter.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-22204" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/arase-twitter.jpg" alt="Solomon Arase" width="400" height="300" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Arase</figcaption></figure>
<p>AUTHORITIES of the Bayelsa State Police Command yesterday dismissed as “untrue” the claims by the Civil Liberties Organisation (CLO) that policemen engaged in indiscriminate arrest of innocent people in the State, noting that the routine raids and stop and search operations have led to the arrest of a military deserter and 49 other persons over alleged involvement in armed robbery and other violent crimes in the state.</p>
<p>According to the spokesman of the Police Command, Mr. Astimin Butswat, the military deserter, identified as 28-year-old Yenabo Presido from the Kolokuma/Opokuma Local Council of the State and his accomplice, 22-year- old ThankGod Victor from Ogoni area of Rivers State, were arrested along the Sani Abacha way of the Bayelsa State capital.</p>
<p>According to Butswat, the army deserter reportedly confessed that the assault rifle found in his possession was stolen from a Boko Haram camp in the North Eastern State where he had served.</p>
<p>Also found in his possession was aToyota Highlander SUV stolen from Port Harcourt, Rivers State. On the alleged indiscriminate arrest of persons in Bayelsa State capital, the Police spokesman said though the Command’s attention has been drawn to the claims that some policemen in the Command engage in illegal arrest and detention of persons through unwholesome practices, the raids are operational strategies deployed to combat crime in the state.</p>
<p>According to him: “The Police Command has recorded successes in the recent past through raiding. For instance, policemen from Yenagoa Division, on the July 31, 2015 at about 9:45pm, arrested one Godsgift Isaac,  while conducting intensive raids along DSP Alamieyesegha Road, Yenagoa.</p>
<p>The suspect is a member of a six-man armed robbery gang, who had earlier robbed and shot one Abiodun Dauda, under his forearm and inflicted machete cuts on his forehead on the July 29, 2015,at about 7pm,along Harbour Road, Yenagoa.” “The victim, Abiodun Dauda, who was robbed of N35, 000 and two handsets, identified the suspect and the suspect admitted to the crime.</p>
<p>The suspect identified other members of the gang as one Hunchback Nodfeh, one ThankGod, surname unknown and upon interrogation, one Owei Prince aka ‘Fela’ and Joel Seibokuro were arrested at a criminal hideout, while one Akpoi is still at large.” “These feats couldn’t have been easily achieved without raids.</p>
<p>As at now the Command has a total number of 50 armed robbery suspects, who were on the wanted list, but were arrested through raiding and six suspected rapist who were on the run, but were later apprehended through raiding.</p>
<p>The Command has equally warned policemen to desist from extorting money from members of the public in the course of discharging their official duties. Members of the public are advised to channel complaints of Police excesses to these dedicated phone numbers: 07034578208; 08032789712,” he said.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/bayelsa-police-arrest-army-deserter-49-others/">Bayelsa Police arrest Army deserter, 49 others</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/bayelsa-police-arrest-army-deserter-49-others/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Police arrest two suspects in murder of bouncer in Owerri</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/police-arrest-two-suspects-in-murder-of-bouncer-in-owerri/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/police-arrest-two-suspects-in-murder-of-bouncer-in-owerri/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 04:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles Ogugbuaja, Owerri]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=40903</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>THE Imo State Police Command has arrested two suspects while two others are still at large, in connection with the death of a security man in Owerri, the state capital last Saturday. The popular self -styled, muscular security attaché of a sprawling night club, Orange Room, located in World Bank area of Owerri, Marvellous Emmanuel [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/police-arrest-two-suspects-in-murder-of-bouncer-in-owerri/">Police arrest two suspects in murder of bouncer in Owerri</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/hand-cuff-1.png"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-12811 alignleft" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/hand-cuff-1-300x209.png" alt="hand cuff 1" width="300" height="209" /></a>THE Imo State Police Command has arrested two suspects while two others are still at large, in connection with the death of a security man in Owerri, the state capital last Saturday.</p>
<p>The popular self -styled, muscular security attaché of a sprawling night club, Orange Room, located in World Bank area of Owerri, Marvellous Emmanuel (30), nick-named “Incredible” was fatally shot by an unidentified gunman in the premises of the club in the early hours of Saturday.</p>
<p>Emmanuel, according to sources, was the only son of his family and still single before he met his untimely death that fateful day.</p>
<p>The Guardian gathered that the deceased had worked as a security man popularly referred to as “bouncer” in two hotels in Owerri, Emmaculate, situated in Ikenegbu Layout and Orange Room, at World Bank axis, outskirts of Owerri metropolis.</p>
<p>The heavily-built young man was known to have executed his bouncing job at the two hotels with the finesse required from his employers.</p>
<p>He used to forcefully carry away anyone, who had not met with the requirements of enjoying the services of the night clubs in the hotels.</p>
<p>In the early hours of last Saturday, a man had driven into the premises of Orange Room, unsuspectingly armed and went straight to the club’s bar. He did not enter with his gun and nobody suspected that he had any fire- arm on him. Anyone who entered the club’s room was frisked and he scaled through the hurdle. The young man, according to sources, had boasted he came from Thailand.<br />
He was reported to have requested for some expensive drinks and bottles of wine, which ranged between N25,000 and N40,000. No one suspected that he could not pay his bills at the counter as required by the management of the club.</p>
<p>Not knowing all his antics, the young man consumed the drinks with those he considered his instant friends piling up a N150, 000 debt. He was asked to pay after the bill was submitted to him by the bar man. He insisted to either pay with a cheque, according to sources, or pay through electronic means. All these options were turned down by the bar man.</p>
<p>After efforts to get him to pay cash failed, “Incredible” was called in to force the debtor to pay and he urged the bouncer to follow him to collect the money from his car in the car park.</p>
<p>He was said to have searched his car’s pigeon hole and instead of bringing out cash, brought out a pistol, released some bullets on the wall of the club, apparently to scare the bouncer away, but Incredible, was said to have remained adamant, holding on to the debtor. He then pushed and released some bullets on the bouncer’s body, leading to his death.</p>
<p>Other night clubbers were said to have taken to their heels. The gunman and his friends fled, too, while two of them were arrested.</p>
<p>Speaking on the incident on yesterday, the Imo State Police Public Relations Officer (PPRO), Mr. Andrew Enwerem, a Deputy Superintendent of Police (DSP), told The Guardian, that two persons had been arrested in connection with the incident, while two others were at large.</p>
<p>He said: “Two persons have been arrested in connection with that. Two are at large and investigations are still on. The bouncer known as “Incredible’ is Marvellous Emmanuel, 30 years old.”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/police-arrest-two-suspects-in-murder-of-bouncer-in-owerri/">Police arrest two suspects in murder of bouncer in Owerri</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/police-arrest-two-suspects-in-murder-of-bouncer-in-owerri/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>‘Don’t shield our brother’s killer’</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/dont-shield-our-brothers-killer/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/dont-shield-our-brothers-killer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 04:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwaseun Akingboye, Akure]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=40904</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Family of man killed by telecommunication firm’s truck in Ondo task police on justice THE bereaved family of an auto-mechanic, Sunday Oladokun, who was allegedly crushed to death in a fatal accident at the Olu-foam, along Ilesha-Owo Expressway, have tasked Ondo State Police Command for justice. Oladokun’s relatives made the plea while reacting to the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/dont-shield-our-brothers-killer/">‘Don’t shield our brother’s killer’</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><strong><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Ola-Copy.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-40906 alignleft" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Ola-Copy-300x225.jpg" alt="Ola-Copy" width="300" height="225" /></a>Family of man killed by telecommunication firm’s truck in Ondo task police on justice<br />
</strong><br />
THE bereaved family of an auto-mechanic, Sunday Oladokun, who was allegedly crushed to death in a fatal accident at the Olu-foam, along Ilesha-Owo Expressway, have tasked Ondo State Police Command for justice.</p>
<p>Oladokun’s relatives made the plea while reacting to the death of the breadwinner and father of four, after the fateful incident last Saturday, accusing security agents of an attempt to pervert justice.</p>
<p>According to reports gathered by The Guardian, the 40-year-old Oladokun‎ closed from work at about 7:30pm and headed home from his office around Agbogbo Junction on the Ilesha-Benin Expressway axis, which is a few kilometres drive away from his Olu-foam residence.</p>
<p>He, however, had no inkling that death was lurking around the corner as he drove home in his blue old model car, which he bought less than two months ago on installmental payment and was yet to complete the payment till his demise.</p>
<p>An eyewitness, who identified himself as Ayomide Akingbade, said he and another friend had barely flagged down Oladokun for the usual free ride home, but before the batting of an eyelid, a diesel tanker driver made a reckless overtaking and crushed him in a head-on collision.</p>
<p>Another eyewitness, Tobi Dara, a colleague of Oladokun, said it took spirited efforts from the people at the scene to extricate the remains of the deceased from the wreck of his newly bought Volkswagen Passat.</p>
<p>Speaking for the relatives, his sibling, Seun Oladokun and another friend, Tajudeen Lawal, accused the police and Federal Road Safety Corps (FRSC) of complicity and trying to pervert justice in favour of the telecommunications firm, which owns the diesel tanker.</p>
<p>According to them, the police were already trying to destroy the exhibits they would use to prosecute their case in the court of law.</p>
<p>The bereaved family and relatives insisted that justice will possibly help alleviate the sufferings of the widow and four kids of the late auto-mechanic popularly known as “Sunday Rewire.” The children aged between two and 11 years.</p>
<p>But the State Police Commissioner, Isaac Eke, remarked that it was too early to conclude who was at fault since it was a case of a fatal accident.</p>
<p>He assured them that all those found culpable in the incident would be brought to book and punished after the appropriate department of the Command must have finished its investigation.</p>
<p>The fatal accident occurred less than 48 hours after the National Association of Nigerian Students (NANS) protested nationwide against the incessant deaths of people on the highway by truck and trailer drivers, urging the government at all levels to restrict their movement from 7:00am to 6:00 pm daily. ‎</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/dont-shield-our-brothers-killer/">‘Don’t shield our brother’s killer’</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/dont-shield-our-brothers-killer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Church holds 2015 Superfest</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/church-holds-2015-superfest/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/church-holds-2015-superfest/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 04:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=40902</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This year’s edition of ‘Superfest,’ an yearly inter-denominational conference of the Abundant Life Gospel Church, Agege, Lagos, holds on Friday August 7 to Thursday, August 13, 2015 at Peace Arena, Abundant Life Gospel Church, 69, Iju Road, Agege, Lagos. The first session of the conference, which will feature teachings, spiritual impartation among others, comes up [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/church-holds-2015-superfest/">Church holds 2015 Superfest</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15826" style="width: 300px;" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/church-donjuanbeachresort.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-15826" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/church-donjuanbeachresort-300x225.jpg" alt="church- image source donjuanbeachresort" width="300" height="225" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">church- image source donjuanbeachresort</figcaption></figure>
<p>This year’s edition of ‘Superfest,’ an yearly inter-denominational conference of the Abundant Life Gospel Church, Agege, Lagos, holds on Friday August 7 to Thursday, August 13, 2015 at Peace Arena, Abundant Life Gospel Church, 69, Iju Road, Agege, Lagos.</p>
<p>The first session of the conference, which will feature teachings, spiritual impartation among others, comes up at 9am to 4pm to be handled by anointed Ministers of God including the Bishop of The Redeemed Evangelical Mission, Mike Okonkwo, Apostle O.S.A. Aiyemo, Dr. Mike Francen, Bishop David Adeoye and Rev. Segun Johnson.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/church-holds-2015-superfest/">Church holds 2015 Superfest</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/church-holds-2015-superfest/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rehabilitation begins  on Ikotun-Ejigbo road</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/rehabilitation-begins-on-ikotun-ejigbo-road/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/rehabilitation-begins-on-ikotun-ejigbo-road/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 04:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=40901</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>RESIDENTS of Ikotun-Ejigbo, Oke Afa and Ago palace way in Okota will soon have cause to smile as rehabilitation work has commenced on the long stretch of the road linking Ikotun-Ejigbo in Alimosho Local Government to Cele Bus-Stop. The Lagos State Public Works Corporation (LSPWC) is undertaking the repair. The Governor, during a recent visit [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/rehabilitation-begins-on-ikotun-ejigbo-road/">Rehabilitation begins  on Ikotun-Ejigbo road</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_14005" style="width: 300px;" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/Free-roads.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-14005" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/Free-roads-300x225.jpg" alt="Along a  Lagos road" width="300" height="225" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Along a Lagos road</figcaption></figure>
<p>RESIDENTS of Ikotun-Ejigbo, Oke Afa and Ago palace way in Okota will soon have cause to smile as rehabilitation work has commenced on the long stretch of the road linking Ikotun-Ejigbo in Alimosho Local Government to Cele Bus-Stop.</p>
<p>The Lagos State Public Works Corporation (LSPWC) is undertaking the repair.</p>
<p>The Governor, during a recent visit to the area pledged to fix the road and the ongoing work is a fulfillment of that promise.</p>
<p>Also, the Lagos State Public Works Corporation has commenced the desilting of drainages along Oke-Afa and Ejigbo area to ensure free flow of floodwater in the area.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/rehabilitation-begins-on-ikotun-ejigbo-road/">Rehabilitation begins  on Ikotun-Ejigbo road</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/rehabilitation-begins-on-ikotun-ejigbo-road/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>LAFROGRAMS Class of ’95 reunites, donates to alma mater</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/lafrograms-class-of-95-reunites-donates-to-alma-mater/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/lafrograms-class-of-95-reunites-donates-to-alma-mater/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 04:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Ijeoma Opara]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=40896</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Students, family and friends gathered at the Olayide Adeoluwa Memorial Hall in the premises of the Lagos African Church Grammar School (LAFROGRAMS), Ifako-Ijaiye, recently, as the Class of 1995 of the school held a reception to mark their 20th year anniversary. The gathering, which was the first of its kind for the old students, could [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/lafrograms-class-of-95-reunites-donates-to-alma-mater/">LAFROGRAMS Class of ’95 reunites, donates to alma mater</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_40900" style="width: 300px;" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/REUNION-Copy.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-40900" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/REUNION-Copy-300x225.jpg" alt="Some members of the class at the event" width="300" height="225" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Some members of the class at the event</figcaption></figure>
<p>Students, family and friends gathered at the Olayide Adeoluwa Memorial Hall in the premises of the Lagos African Church Grammar School (LAFROGRAMS), Ifako-Ijaiye, recently, as the Class of 1995 of the school held a reception to mark their 20th year anniversary.</p>
<p>The gathering, which was the first of its kind for the old students, could be mistaken by a visitor as an occasion for marking the country’s independence as the celebrating students were attired in green and white. The President of Class ’95, Mrs. Juliet Kojo-Onwueze, said the event was necessitated by the need to identify with their Alma Mata that has shaped them to who they are today.</p>
<p>“It is important for people to always remember their roots and where they are coming from and that is why we are gathered here today to give back to our Alma Mata by donating 50 chairs and tables for the school. We will not stop at this, we will continue to give our best to the school that made us useful in the society,” she said. She disclosed that it took almost five years to plan the reunion because not all of them reside in Lagos, as many of the students came, not only from distant parts of the country but also from abroad. “We are so happy reuniting after a very long time and sharing good old memories,” she said.</p>
<p>The General Secretary of the group, Mrs. Yinka Ibidunni, while expressing her joy at the reunion said: “Although it has been a long time, we still remember some events that happened in our school days, even those I wasn’t in good terms with back then in the school showed me warm affection and friendship today. We totally forgot all that happened then.”</p>
<p>The school principal of the Class of ’95, Mrs. Annette Adeoba, noted that it was challenging catering for the over 3, 000 students in the school with very little facilities, adding that her administration and teachers stood as a family and were able to inculcate good morals and education into the children, which have helped them to be who they are today.</p>
<p>While commenting on the declining standard of education, she said the reading culture among students has been diminished by the advert of the social media and the use of electronic devices that were not available in the 90s. “Students are now more interested in social media platforms (Facebook, twitter, BBM, What Sapp, Instagram) than reading their books,” the principal said</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/lafrograms-class-of-95-reunites-donates-to-alma-mater/">LAFROGRAMS Class of ’95 reunites, donates to alma mater</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/lafrograms-class-of-95-reunites-donates-to-alma-mater/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Former education commissioner tasks youths on  reputation, character</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/former-education-commissioner-tasks-youths-on-reputation-character/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/former-education-commissioner-tasks-youths-on-reputation-character/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 04:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gbenga Akinfenwa]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=40898</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>A FORMER Lagos State Commissioner of Education, Saidat Olayinka Oladunjoye, has advised youths in the country to guard their character jealously, noting that such would determine how far they progress in their chosen profession. Oladunjoye, who spoke at the 2015 graduation ceremony of Halifield School, Lagos, counselled the graduating students to aspire for greater heights in life. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/former-education-commissioner-tasks-youths-on-reputation-character/">Former education commissioner tasks youths on  reputation, character</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/HALIFIELD-Copy.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-40899" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/HALIFIELD-Copy-300x225.jpg" alt="HALIFIELD--Copy" width="300" height="225" /></a>A FORMER Lagos State Commissioner of Education, Saidat Olayinka Oladunjoye, has advised youths in the country to guard their character jealously, noting that such would determine how far they progress in their chosen profession. Oladunjoye, who spoke at the 2015 graduation ceremony of Halifield School, Lagos, counselled the graduating students to aspire for greater heights in life.</p>
<p>She also encouraged them to always strive to give back to the school that produced them. She also emphasised the need for decent attitude and healthy character from the outgoing students, to excel in life, adding that they should continue to shine, as they were the trailblazers.</p>
<p>The head of school, Mrs. Y. O. Awofuwa stated clearly that the trailblazers would be attending schools of their first choice in countries such as Canada, the United States and other countries across the globe.</p>
<p>While wishing them manifold successes as they become alumni, she expressed her desire and prayer that the graduating Halifield pupils would keep in touch with the school’s activities through their space on the website. She admonished them to strive to step up the ladder and continue in their quest for knowledge, as learning is a continuous process.</p>
<p>Awofuwa extended a warm appreciation to the staff; parents and all others who have in so many positive ways helped bring the children to their enviable position. Also speaking, a technologist entrepreneur and Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of Andela, Mr. Iyin Aboyeji counselled the graduating students on self-discovery.</p>
<p>“You should take time to know who you are, discover your true identity, be honest with yourself and never indulge yourself in fantasies,” Aboyeji advised. “To be successful, you need to follow your passion and work harder than the average minds. While pursuing your personal goals in life, you should always remember that there would never be true success in life without service to others.</p>
<p>Your talents, skills, training and experience must be channeled towards lifting the less-privileged out of their predicaments,” he said. The peak of the event was the exceptional display of the pupils, which added colour to the occasion.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/former-education-commissioner-tasks-youths-on-reputation-character/">Former education commissioner tasks youths on  reputation, character</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/former-education-commissioner-tasks-youths-on-reputation-character/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weeds, debris clog  Ladipo canal</title>
		<link>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/weeds-debris-clog-ladipo-canal/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/weeds-debris-clog-ladipo-canal/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 04:12:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Isaac Taiwo]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/?p=40895</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>THE dreadful prediction for heavy rains and attendant floods this year by the Lagos State Ministry of the Environment notwithstanding; and the advice to Lagosians to take appropriate measures to ensure that drains around their homes are well cleaned and maintained to allow for easy flow of storm waters so as  to prevent flooding and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/weeds-debris-clog-ladipo-canal/">Weeds, debris clog  Ladipo canal</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Ladipo-Carnal-Copy.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-40897 alignleft" src="http://newngrguardiannewscom.c.presscdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Ladipo-Carnal-Copy-300x225.jpg" alt="Ladipo-Carnal---Copy" width="300" height="225" /></a>THE dreadful prediction for heavy rains and attendant floods this year by the Lagos State Ministry of the Environment notwithstanding; and the advice to Lagosians to take appropriate measures to ensure that drains around their homes are well cleaned and maintained to allow for easy flow of storm waters so as  to prevent flooding and the breeding of mosquitoes (malaria causing parasite), the Ladipo canal that is a major drainage channel in the mainland has been overgrown with bulrushes, maize and pawpaw trees.</p>
<p>To worsen the state of the place, old bottles, empty sachets of pure water and all sorts of cans are dumped into the carnal with the rings under the two bridges on Apapa-Oshodi Expressway and the one at Ladipo market almost filled to its edges.</p>
<p>Right now, instead of the water to flow, all the particles as well as the weeds have combined to block the passage and the water in the canal is stagnated, thus making the long stretch of the drainage channel to become a breeding place for mosquitoes and leeches.</p>
<p>With the condition of the carnal, any heavy rainfall may pose a danger to traders who have their shops along the banks of the canal as well as people living nearby.</p>
<p>The President, Ladipo Auto Spare parts Market, Kingsley Ogbonna, disagreed with the claim that the refuse in the place were thrown in by the traders but that they were washed by flood from elsewhere.</p>
<p>He added that the task of clearing the canal was beyond the traders because to clear the place requires heavy-duty equipment, which is not within the reach of the traders. He called for the assistance of the Ministry of the Environment to put the place in a decent order.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/weeds-debris-clog-ladipo-canal/">Weeds, debris clog  Ladipo canal</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ngrguardiannews.com">The Guardian Nigeria</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ngrguardiannews.com/2015/08/weeds-debris-clog-ladipo-canal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
