<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>LATEST NIGERIAN NEWS BREAKING HEADLINES NEWSPAPERS</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com</link>
	<description>LATEST NIGERIAN NEWS BREAKING HEADLINES NEWSPAPERS</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 09:00:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.2.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>NYSC Soon To Be Optional For Nigerian Graduates &#8211; DG</title>
		<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/06/nysc-soon-to-be-optional-for-nigerian-graduates-dg/</link>
		<comments>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/06/nysc-soon-to-be-optional-for-nigerian-graduates-dg/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 09:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwadara Kasali]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NYSC Soon To Be Optional For Nigerian Graduates - DG]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?p=56684</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Director-General of National Youth Service Corps (NYSC), Brigadier-General Johnson Olawumi, yesterday 5th of August, said the Federal government is set to make the youth service programme optional for Nigerian graduates. Speaking at a meeting with President Buhari on Wednesday, Olawumi said there were plans to make the scheme voluntary and reduce the corps population [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/NYSC-DG-Brigadier-General-Johnson-Olawumi_2_510x350.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-43855 size-full" src="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/NYSC-DG-Brigadier-General-Johnson-Olawumi_2_510x350.jpg" alt="NYSC DG Brigadier-General-Johnson Olawumi_2_510x350" width="510" height="350" /></a></p>
<p>The Director-General of National Youth Service Corps (NYSC), Brigadier-General Johnson Olawumi, yesterday 5th of August, said the Federal government is set to make the youth service programme optional for Nigerian graduates.</p>
<p>Speaking at a meeting with President Buhari on Wednesday, Olawumi said there were plans to make the scheme voluntary and reduce the corps population to make the programme more sustainable and effective in its course.</p>
<p>Moreover, Permanent Secretary of the Federal Ministry of Youth Development, Mrs. Rabi Jimeta had said that the annual enrolment of corps participants from 2,364 at establishment in 1974 had increased to 229,016 in 2014.</p><div class="wpInsert wpInsertInPostAd wpInsertMiddle" style="margin: 5px; padding: 0px;"><p style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2;" ><a href="http://pricepadi.com" target="_blank"><font color="FF3300" size="3">Don't waste money. Check PRICES of Phones, Electronics, Fashion & Appliances on PricePadi.com</font></a> </p>

<div style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2; padding-top:7px;">
<script async src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script>
<!-- Sidebar Ad 1 -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:inline-block;width:300px;height:250px"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-2460597205856998"
     data-ad-slot="4203160441"></ins>
<script>
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
</div></div>
<p>Mrs Jimeta said: &#8220;Given the increasing number of tertiary institutions, our projection is that the number of corps participants may rise to 300,000 by year 2020.&#8221;</p>
<p>President Buhari assured that his administration will ensure the continuity and the betterment of the NYSC service scheme.</p>
<p>He said: &#8220;I firmly believe in NYSC and I think it should remain a national programme to promote integration. Whenever I go home to Daura, I look out for corps members from Lagos, Aba and other parts of the country.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I am always thrilled to learn that except for the NYSC, some of them have never left their states of origin to visit other cities in the country,&#8221; the President added.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/06/nysc-soon-to-be-optional-for-nigerian-graduates-dg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNILAG Lecturer Rapes 18 Year-old Admission Seeker</title>
		<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/06/unilag-lecturer-rapes-18-year-old-admission-seeker/</link>
		<comments>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/06/unilag-lecturer-rapes-18-year-old-admission-seeker/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 08:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwadara Kasali]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UNILAG Lecturer Rapes 18 Year-old Admission Seeker]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?p=56683</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A lecturer at the University Of Lagos (UNILAG), Afeez Baruwa, has been arrested for allegedly raping an 18-year-old girl, identified as Caroline in the Yaba areaof Lagos. According to reports, the lecturer and Caroline’s father belonged to the same landlords’ association at Abesan, Ipaja. It was gathered that the victim’s father had allowed her daughter [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/UNILAG-entrance-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-17825" src="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/UNILAG-entrance-2-300x187.jpg" alt="UNILAG-entrance 2" width="500" height="313" /></a><br />
A lecturer at the University Of Lagos (UNILAG), Afeez Baruwa, has been arrested for allegedly raping an 18-year-old girl, identified as Caroline in the Yaba areaof Lagos.</p>
<p>According to reports, the lecturer and Caroline’s father belonged to the same landlords’ association at Abesan, Ipaja. It was gathered that the victim’s father had allowed her daughter to follow the lecturer on July 23, to UNILAG for an admission process.</p>
<p>Speaking to correspondent, the Director of the Office of the Public Defender, Mrs. Omotola Rotimi said: &#8220;the victim’s father wanted the lecturer to assist with his daughter’s admission. On the fateful day, the girl left with the lecturer as early as 5.30am, and they got to the school at about 7am.&#8221;No one had arrived at the hall except a woman. While the exams had yet to start, It was learnt that Baruwa allegedly took the girl inside one of the study halls, bolted the door, and raped her.</p>
<p>She went home, and the father found out that her daughter had been raped. He took her to the Mirabel Centre, which then informed the OPD. The centre also contacted the police at the Surulere and Isokoko divisions, and the suspect was arrested.&#8221;</p><div class="wpInsert wpInsertInPostAd wpInsertMiddle" style="margin: 5px; padding: 0px;"><p style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2;" ><a href="http://pricepadi.com" target="_blank"><font color="FF3300" size="3">Don't waste money. Check PRICES of Phones, Electronics, Fashion & Appliances on PricePadi.com</font></a> </p>

<div style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2; padding-top:7px;">
<script async src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script>
<!-- Sidebar Ad 1 -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:inline-block;width:300px;height:250px"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-2460597205856998"
     data-ad-slot="4203160441"></ins>
<script>
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
</div></div>
<p>Mrs Rotimi said the OPD would write a letter to the UNILAG Vice-Chancellor on the incident, so as to avoid a reoccurrence.</p>
<p>A Police official said the lecturer &#8220;confessed to the act, but his claim is that the sex was by mutual consent.&#8221;</p>
<p>Baruwa claims to be a part-time lecturer, but not an employee of the University of Lagos, according to the Lagos State Police Public Relations Officer, DSP Patricia Amadin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/06/unilag-lecturer-rapes-18-year-old-admission-seeker/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SHOCKING PHOTO: Woman Delivers Baby Without A Face In Abia</title>
		<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/06/shocking-photo-woman-delivers-baby-without-a-face-in-abia/</link>
		<comments>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/06/shocking-photo-woman-delivers-baby-without-a-face-in-abia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 07:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anu Odusote]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photo News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Woman Delivers Baby Without A Face In Abia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?p=56685</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Pandemonium broke out in Aba when a faceless baby was reportedly delivered at a hospital in Ogbor Hill, Aba, Abia State yesterday, according to eye witnesses. Find photo below &#160;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/06/shocking-photo-woman-delivers-baby-without-a-face-in-abia/faceless-baby/" rel="attachment wp-att-56687"><img class=" size-full wp-image-56687 aligncenter" src="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/faceless-baby.jpg" alt="faceless baby" width="607" height="341" /></a>Pandemonium broke out in Aba when a faceless baby was reportedly delivered at a hospital in Ogbor Hill, Aba, Abia State yesterday, according to eye witnesses.</p>
<p>Find photo below</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://africanspotlight.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/2710464_20150805202745_jpeg3b0e1daa24ec9049e0d0632aeb732ae0.jpg"><img class=" size-full wp-image-246516 aligncenter" src="http://africanspotlight.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/2710464_20150805202745_jpeg3b0e1daa24ec9049e0d0632aeb732ae0.jpg" alt="Woman delivers baby without face in Aba1" width="604" height="453" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/06/shocking-photo-woman-delivers-baby-without-a-face-in-abia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buhari Orders ‘Quick Action’ On Establishment Of New National Airline</title>
		<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/06/buhari-orders-quick-action-on-establishment-of-new-national-airline/</link>
		<comments>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/06/buhari-orders-quick-action-on-establishment-of-new-national-airline/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 07:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anu Odusote]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national airline]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?p=56680</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[President Muhammadu Buhari on Wednesday, August 5, 2015, ordered the Ministry of Aviation to expedite action on the establishment of a new national airline. Buhari gave the order at the Presidential Villa when he was briefed by officials of the Aviation Ministry led by the Permanent Secretary, Binta Bello. Erstwhile national carrier, Nigeria Airways, established [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/05/17/buhari-to-drop-general-title-from-may-29-see-his-official-portrait/buhariportrait/" rel="attachment wp-att-49193"><img class=" size-full wp-image-49193 aligncenter" src="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/BuhariPortrait.png" alt="BuhariPortrait" width="428" height="428" /></a>President Muhammadu Buhari on Wednesday, August 5, 2015, ordered the <span id="IL_AD7" class="IL_AD">Ministry</span> of Aviation to expedite action on the establishment of a new national airline.</p>
<p>Buhari gave the order at the Presidential Villa when he was briefed by officials of the Aviation Ministry led by the Permanent Secretary, Binta Bello.</p>
<p>Erstwhile national carrier, Nigeria Airways, established in 1958, was liquidated in 2003 in under heavy debts, mismanagement, inefficiency and corruption.</p>
<p>Addressing State House correspondents after the briefing, Bello said the President was actually worried about Nigeria not having a national air carrier, hence the <span id="IL_AD6" class="IL_AD">instruction</span> to re-establish one.</p>
<p>The ministry officials also briefed Buhari on the challenges domestic airlines were facing despite Federal Government’s N300 billion intervention fund to enable them boost their operations.</p><div class="wpInsert wpInsertInPostAd wpInsertMiddle" style="margin: 5px; padding: 0px;"><p style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2;" ><a href="http://pricepadi.com" target="_blank"><font color="FF3300" size="3">Don't waste money. Check PRICES of Phones, Electronics, Fashion & Appliances on PricePadi.com</font></a> </p>

<div style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2; padding-top:7px;">
<script async src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script>
<!-- Sidebar Ad 1 -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:inline-block;width:300px;height:250px"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-2460597205856998"
     data-ad-slot="4203160441"></ins>
<script>
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
</div></div>
<p>Bello disclosed that the airlines were incidentally hugely indebted to regulatory agencies under the Aviation Ministry, among other issues that have left some of the airlines still struggling to maintain optimum operational capabilities.</p>
<p>The Permanent Secretary announced that the four state-of-the-art airport terminals across the country being constructed with a Chinese Bank loan will be ready by the first quarter of 2016.</p>
<p>She stressed that the facilities under construction and expansion would be big and modern enough to accommodate large <span id="IL_AD4" class="IL_AD">aircraft</span> like the Airbus 380 aeroplanes as obtains in the largest international airports.</p>
<p>The President also instructed the ministry to begin the process of relinquishing airspace and radar control of neighbouring countries as they now have the <span id="IL_AD1" class="IL_AD">capacity</span> to cover their own airspace.</p>
<p>Bello reassured Nigerians and the international community that Nigeria’s airspace ?is safe and has just recorded a score of over 90 per cent by the International Civil Aviation <span id="IL_AD8" class="IL_AD">Organisation</span> (ICAO).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/06/buhari-orders-quick-action-on-establishment-of-new-national-airline/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>You Wouldn&#8217;t Believe What This 20-Yr-Old Man Did To His Niece After Stealing Her School Fees</title>
		<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/you-wouldnt-believe-what-this-20-yr-old-man-did-to-his-niece-after-stealing-her-school-fees/</link>
		<comments>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/you-wouldnt-believe-what-this-20-yr-old-man-did-to-his-niece-after-stealing-her-school-fees/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 20:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anu Odusote]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?p=56666</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A 20-year-old student of the College of Education in Oyo State, Olajide Ajayi, has been arrested by the state Police Command for attempting to murder his niece, Opeyemi Ajala, by cutting her throat after he deceived her and stole her school fees. According to the police, the suspect was said to have collected Ajala&#8217;s ATM [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/05/13/girl-stabs-brother-to-death-in-warri-over-this-ridiculous-reason/blood_stainedknife/" rel="attachment wp-att-48807"><img class=" size-full wp-image-48807 aligncenter" src="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Blood_StainedKnife.jpg" alt="Blood_StainedKnife" width="500" height="332" /></a>A 20-year-old student of the College of Education in Oyo State, Olajide Ajayi, has been arrested by the state Police Command for attempting to murder his niece, Opeyemi Ajala, by cutting her throat after he deceived her and stole her school fees.</p>
<p>According to the police, the suspect was said to have collected Ajala&#8217;s ATM card with the intention of withdrawing the sum of N47,000 to help her pay her school fees which he instead used to buy clothes and spend on his girlfriend.</p>
<p>When the niece, also a student of the institution, asked him for the teller with which he paid in the money, he began to develop a plan to kill her when he could no longer bear the pressure from her.</p>
<p>In a bid to cover up his theft, on the night of  the incident, Ajayi went to Ajala&#8217;s house with a knife, sneaked into her room where she was sleeping, and proceeded to slit her throat with the knife where he left her for dead.</p><div class="wpInsert wpInsertInPostAd wpInsertMiddle" style="margin: 5px; padding: 0px;"><p style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2;" ><a href="http://pricepadi.com" target="_blank"><font color="FF3300" size="3">Don't waste money. Check PRICES of Phones, Electronics, Fashion & Appliances on PricePadi.com</font></a> </p>

<div style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2; padding-top:7px;">
<script async src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script>
<!-- Sidebar Ad 1 -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:inline-block;width:300px;height:250px"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-2460597205856998"
     data-ad-slot="4203160441"></ins>
<script>
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
</div></div>
<p>Unfortunately for him, Ajala lady did not die and she managed to alert her neighbours who rushed her to the University College of Hospital, Ibadan, and reported the case to the police.</p>
<p>During his interrogation, Ajayi confessed to his crime.</p>
<blockquote class="tr_bq"><p>“I collected the money, but I spent it. When the pressure from her was too much, and there was no way I could get the money to pay her back, I decided to kill her. One night, I went to her house with a sharp knife to kill her.<br />
I got to her house at about 8 pm; when I entered the room, I locked the door and pinned her head down on the bed. I did not allow her to shout. Then, I brought out the knife and slit her throat. When blood started gushing out and she was unconscious, I thought she was dead and I escaped.”</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/you-wouldnt-believe-what-this-20-yr-old-man-did-to-his-niece-after-stealing-her-school-fees/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Would Rather Burn In Hell Than Worship A Monster Called God – Nigerian Transgender</title>
		<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/i-would-rather-burn-in-hell-than-worship-a-monster-called-god-nigerian-transgender/</link>
		<comments>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/i-would-rather-burn-in-hell-than-worship-a-monster-called-god-nigerian-transgender/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 20:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwadara Kasali]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I Would Rather Burn In Hell Than Worship A Monster Called God – Stephanie Rose]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?p=56605</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Nigerian transgender Stephanie Rose, is full of hatred for the Lord our God and is coming out again to insult him and call him a monster. Stephanie, who was born a man named Dapo Adaralegbe, was expelled from the Obafemi Awolowo University, Ife, where she was studying Law due to her homosexuality. She later underwent [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Stephanie-Rose-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-56606" src="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Stephanie-Rose-2-600x400.jpg" alt="Stephanie-Rose-2" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>Nigerian transgender Stephanie Rose, is full of hatred for the Lord our God and is coming out again to insult him and call him a monster.<br />
Stephanie, who was born a man named Dapo Adaralegbe, was expelled from the Obafemi Awolowo University, Ife, where she was studying Law due to her homosexuality. She later underwent surgery to become a woman.</p>
<p>In her latest rant, she has taken to her Facebook page to share a post by an avowed atheist, Amenhotep Kingsagreed, where she thinks that God is the devil himself.</p>
<p>Read what she says about God and why she believes God is the devil as she quotes from the Bible. (This is when one of those sayings &#8220;even devil know Bible pass any man&#8221;, comes into play).  See her Biblical claims  below:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8220;I’m amazed that people who claim to read and worship the words of the bible tend to be so ignorant about just what the bible says. I wonder how many of them know that god is quoted many times in the bible admitting that he is in fact evil. I will list those passages below.</em></p>
<p><em>Isaiah 45:7 I form the light, and create darkness: I make peace, and create evil: I the LORD do all these things.</em></p>
<p><em>Exodus 32:14 And the LORD repented of the evil which he thought to do unto his people.</em></p>
<p><em>Joshua 23:15 Therefore it shall come to pass, that as all good things are come upon you, which the LORD your God promised you; so shall the LORD bring upon you all evil things.</em></p>
<p><em>Judges 9:23 Then God sent an evil spirit</em></p>
<p><em>1 Samuel 16:14 But the Spirit of the LORD departed from Saul, and an evil spirit from the LORD troubled him.</em></p>
<p><em>2 Samuel 12:11 Thus saith the LORD, Behold, I will raise up evil against thee out of thine own house</em></p>
<p><em>1 Kings 9:9 …therefore hath the LORD brought upon them all this evil.</em></p>
<p><em>1 Kings 14:10 Therefore, behold, I will bring evil upon the house of Jeroboam</em></p>
<p><em>2 Kings 6:33 …Behold, this evil is of the LORD;</em></p>
<p><em>2 Kings 21:12 Therefore thus saith the LORD God of Israel, Behold, I am bringing such evil upon Jerusalem and Judah, that whosoever heareth of it, both his ears shall tingle.</em></p>
<p><em> 2 Kings 22:16 Thus saith the LORD, Behold, I will bring evil upon this place</em></p>
<p><em>Nehemiah 13:18 Did not your fathers thus, and did not our God bring all this evil upon us, and upon this city?</em></p><div class="wpInsert wpInsertInPostAd wpInsertMiddle" style="margin: 5px; padding: 0px;"><p style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2;" ><a href="http://pricepadi.com" target="_blank"><font color="FF3300" size="3">Don't waste money. Check PRICES of Phones, Electronics, Fashion & Appliances on PricePadi.com</font></a> </p>

<div style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2; padding-top:7px;">
<script async src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script>
<!-- Sidebar Ad 1 -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:inline-block;width:300px;height:250px"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-2460597205856998"
     data-ad-slot="4203160441"></ins>
<script>
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
</div></div>
<p><em>Jeremiah 4:6 Set up the standard toward Zion: retire, stay not: for I will bring evil from the north, and a great destruction.</em></p>
<p><em>Jeremiah 6:19 Hear, O earth: behold, I will bring evil upon this people.</em></p>
<p><em>Jeremiah 11:11 Therefore thus saith the LORD, Behold, I will bring evil upon them.</em></p>
<p><em>Jeremiah 25:29 For, lo, I begin to bring evil.</em></p>
<p><em>Jeremiah 35:17 Therefore thus saith the LORD God of hosts, the God of Israel; Behold, I will bring upon Judah and upon all the inhabitants of Jerusalem all the evil that I have pronounced against them:</em></p>
<p><em>Jeremiah 44:2 Thus saith the LORD of hosts, the God of Israel; Ye have seen all the evil that I have brought upon Jerusalem, and upon all the cities of Judah</em></p>
<p><em>Jeremiah 45:5 …behold, I will bring evil upon all flesh, saith the LORD</em></p>
<p><em>Jeremiah 49:37 …I will bring evil upon them, even my fierce anger, saith the LORD; and I will send the sword after them, till I have consumed them</em></p>
<p><em>Micah 1:12 …. evil came down from the LORD</em></p>
<p><em>Micah 2:3 Therefore thus saith the LORD; Behold, against this family do I devise an evil.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>So as you can see, Jehovah god admits that it is he that does all evil, not some &#8216;fallen angel&#8217; who gets the blame. The reason Satan gets the blame is solely so that the Christians can convince themselves that it’s not god doing it. But if you claim that god is not capable of committing evil acts then you are &#8216;giving false witness&#8217; and committing &#8216;blasphemy&#8217; against god and his character.</p>
<p>Now I ask you, why do you feel that this “god” is deserving of worship? Even if you believe that he does exist, after all he has done and all he admits, why would you want to devote your life to him? Of all the men who have lived not one of them can come close to the evil that this god is. No one has caused as much death and destruction that this god claims to have done.</p>
<p>It’s funny, the relationship that people have with this god reminds me of battered wife syndrome. He’ll beat you into submission, threaten you with terrible punishments if you don’t comply, convince you that you deserve that horrible treatment because your bad deep inside, then tell you he only does it because he loves you. Actually it’s not funny after all. It’s pretty damn sad.</p>
<p>Which &#8216;other uncontrollable devil&#8217; is humanity searching for when the creator and inventor of evil has declared itself? The position of evil can not be checked because the same God is the creator and inventor of all evil.</p>
<p>Evil started from the same hopeless and foolish God because such useless and senseless God is evil. They do not go to Heaven and they do not go to Hell fire, the same God is the exact devil that deceived all religions about an untrue Heaven and untrue Hell fire!</p>
<p>Hell fire is a fallacy of imagination. NO BODY GOES TO HELL FIRE.”</p>
<p>Rose also has a book she has written titled: &#8220;NO BODY GOES TO HEAVEN BECAUSE NO BODY GOES TO HELL FIRE.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/i-would-rather-burn-in-hell-than-worship-a-monster-called-god-nigerian-transgender/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>[PHOTOS] Politician Kneels Down To Beg Speaker Of Delta State Assembly. You Wouldn&#8217;t Believe Why</title>
		<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/photos-politician-kneels-down-to-beg-speaker-of-delta-state-assembly-you-wouldnt-believe-why/</link>
		<comments>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/photos-politician-kneels-down-to-beg-speaker-of-delta-state-assembly-you-wouldnt-believe-why/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 19:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anu Odusote]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photo News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mr Ejaife Odebala]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mr Monday Igbuya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politician Kneels Down To Beg Speaker Of Delta State Assembly]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?p=56647</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Photos of a Local government area Chairman in Delta State, Mr Ejaife Odebala caught kneeling down before the Delta State House of Assembly Speaker, Mr Monday Igbuya has surfaced and has got people talking. However, according to Secret Reporters, Odebala has come out to explain his reasons for the action and  dismissed the notion that he went [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?attachment_id=56650" rel="attachment wp-att-56650"><img class=" size-full wp-image-56650 aligncenter" src="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/delta-politician-kneels-down.jpg" alt="delta politician kneels down" width="640" height="360" /></a>Photos of a Local government area Chairman in Delta State, Mr Ejaife Odebala caught kneeling down before the Delta State House of Assembly Speaker, Mr Monday Igbuya has surfaced and has got people talking.</p>
<p>However, according to Secret Reporters, Odebala has come out to explain his reasons for the action and  dismissed the notion that he went to Igbuya to save his political seat from impeachment by the councilors.</p>
<p>He said…</p>
<blockquote><p>I have no issue with anybody. How can the councilors impeach me? I offended by elder brother and leader and went to apologise to him. Is there anything wrong in that?</p>
<p>Igbuya is my elder brother and the leader of my party in the area. He is the governor of Sapele being the Speaker of the Assembly and number three man in the State. My kneeling down to beg him is for personal issues not political. I offended him and there is nothing wrong with a younger brother apologizing to his elder brother.</p><div class="wpInsert wpInsertInPostAd wpInsertMiddle" style="margin: 5px; padding: 0px;"><p style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2;" ><a href="http://pricepadi.com" target="_blank"><font color="FF3300" size="3">Don't waste money. Check PRICES of Phones, Electronics, Fashion & Appliances on PricePadi.com</font></a> </p>

<div style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2; padding-top:7px;">
<script async src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script>
<!-- Sidebar Ad 1 -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:inline-block;width:300px;height:250px"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-2460597205856998"
     data-ad-slot="4203160441"></ins>
<script>
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
</div></div>
<p>He affirmed that his Chairmanship seat is safe from any impeachment saga as being rumored in Delta State.</p>
<p>Odebala was a former two time member of the State House of Assembly and also contested for the gubernatorial race with former governor Emmanuel Uduaghan, an action which is believed wrecked him financially.</p></blockquote>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-121850" src="http://i0.wp.com/www.sugardaily.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/IGBUYA-2.jpg?resize=600%2C338" alt="IGBUYA 2" width="600" height="338" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/photos-politician-kneels-down-to-beg-speaker-of-delta-state-assembly-you-wouldnt-believe-why/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buhari’s Anti-Corruption Scheme Is Mere Noise-Making – Governor Fayose</title>
		<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/buharis-anti-corruption-scheme-is-mere-noise-making-governor-fayose/</link>
		<comments>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/buharis-anti-corruption-scheme-is-mere-noise-making-governor-fayose/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 19:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwadara Kasali]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buhari’s Anti-Corruption Scheme Is Mere Noise-Making – Governor Fayose]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?p=56649</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Outspoken Ekiti State Governor, Ayodele Fayose, on Wednesday swerved at the Federal Government anti-corruption stance, describing it as mere noise-making, witch-hunt and diversionary tactic to hoodwink the public into overlooking the seeming failure of the government to deliver on its electoral promises. Speaking through his Special Assistant on Public Communications and New Media, Lere Olayinka, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Ayodele-Fayose-360x225.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-10469 aligncenter" src="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Ayodele-Fayose-360x225-300x187.jpg" alt="Ayodele-Fayose-360x225" width="500" height="313" /></a><br />
Outspoken Ekiti State Governor, Ayodele Fayose, on Wednesday swerved at the Federal Government anti-corruption stance, describing it as mere noise-making, witch-hunt and diversionary tactic to hoodwink the public into overlooking the seeming failure of the government to deliver on its electoral promises.</p>
<p>Speaking through his Special Assistant on Public Communications and New Media, Lere Olayinka, the Governor said: &#8220;You don’t announce a process to the public. Rather, you announce the results because that is what is of interest to the people. It is like you are announcing that you know where armed robbers reside, won’t they change their location?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;What the All Progressives Congress (APC) spin-doctors and their collaborators in the Presidency are doing is simple. It is such that when there is nothing to tell the people as per the rising Boko Haram attacks, Dollar and other foreign currencies exchange rates, petrol pump price and other seeming failed promises of the APC federal government, they will accuse former President Goodluck Jonathan and his men of corruption, insult Peoples Democratic Party (PDP) and make noise about fighting corruption.&#8221;</p><div class="wpInsert wpInsertInPostAd wpInsertMiddle" style="margin: 5px; padding: 0px;"><p style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2;" ><a href="http://pricepadi.com" target="_blank"><font color="FF3300" size="3">Don't waste money. Check PRICES of Phones, Electronics, Fashion & Appliances on PricePadi.com</font></a> </p>

<div style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2; padding-top:7px;">
<script async src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script>
<!-- Sidebar Ad 1 -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:inline-block;width:300px;height:250px"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-2460597205856998"
     data-ad-slot="4203160441"></ins>
<script>
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
</div></div>
<p>Governor Fayose maintained that: &#8220;If President Muhammadu Buhari knows exactly where the stolen funds are kept and who looted the funds, he does not need all these public announcements. Rather, he should make public names of the looters and bring back the purported stolen funds, location of which he has identified. It is when he is able to bring back the money that he should make announcements of recovered funds.&#8221;</p>
<p>Challenging Buhari to start the anti-corruption fight from his party, starting with those that aided the President during his campaign, Fayose said: &#8220;Some of those who sponsored the President’s election have not done any other jobs apart from holding public offices. Yet, they provided private jets and funds with which the President campaigned across the length and breadth of Nigeria. He should let Nigerians know where they got money to buy private jets and the several billions of naira spent on his election.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Mr President and his men should know that these planned efforts to brand PDP as a party of corrupt people and supress the giant strides of the Jonathan administration won’t work because Nigerians know that APC is peopled with more corrupt people and the President must treat the issue of corruption without looking at political parties,&#8221; the Ekiti state governor added.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/buharis-anti-corruption-scheme-is-mere-noise-making-governor-fayose/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>EFCC Arrests Ex-Banker For Stealing This Amount From Customer&#8217;s Account</title>
		<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/efcc-arrests-ex-banker-for-stealing-this-amount-from-customers-account/</link>
		<comments>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/efcc-arrests-ex-banker-for-stealing-this-amount-from-customers-account/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 18:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwadara Kasali]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EFCC Arrests Ex-Banker For Stealing This Amount From Customer's Account]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?p=56636</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Economic and Financial Crimes Commission (EFCC) on Monday arraigned a Bawa Momodu before Justice I. E. Ekwo of the Federal High Court sitting in Port Harcourt, Rivers State. Bawa who, until the incident, was an employee at Sterling Bank has been accused of stealing N27 million from a customer’s account. He is faced with [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Bawa-Momodu.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-56638" src="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Bawa-Momodu.png" alt="Bawa Momodu" width="500" height="357" /></a><br />
The Economic and Financial Crimes Commission (EFCC) on Monday arraigned a Bawa Momodu before Justice I. E. Ekwo of the Federal High Court sitting in Port Harcourt, Rivers State. Bawa who, until the incident, was an employee at Sterling Bank has been accused of stealing N27 million from a customer’s account. He is faced with a 16-count charge bordering on forgery, uttering and stealing to the tune of N27 million.</p>
<p>According to the Head on Media and Publicity to the anti-graft agency commission, Wilson Uwujaren, the accused allegedly forged the signature of the said account holder and fraudulently withdrew the money from the bank.</p>
<p>&#8220;Investigations further revealed that the said amount was transferred to the Sterling Bank account of one Emilia Ugwandu, who is now at large, in a bid to hide the source of the stolen funds,&#8221; Uwujaren said.</p><div class="wpInsert wpInsertInPostAd wpInsertMiddle" style="margin: 5px; padding: 0px;"><p style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2;" ><a href="http://pricepadi.com" target="_blank"><font color="FF3300" size="3">Don't waste money. Check PRICES of Phones, Electronics, Fashion & Appliances on PricePadi.com</font></a> </p>

<div style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2; padding-top:7px;">
<script async src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script>
<!-- Sidebar Ad 1 -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:inline-block;width:300px;height:250px"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-2460597205856998"
     data-ad-slot="4203160441"></ins>
<script>
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
</div></div>
<p>However, Momodu pleaded not guilty to the charges preferred against him. In view of his plea, the prosecution counsel, A. Olatunji, asked for a date for the commencement of trial.</p>
<p>Consequently, the defence counsel, Allen Nwogwama, prayed the court to grant his client bail. Ekwo granted the accused bail in the sum N7 million and one surety in like sum. The surety must be a responsible member of the society with landed property worth the bail sum, to be verified by the court registrar and the prosecution.</p>
<p>The accused is also to be reporting at the EFCC office on the last day of every month.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/efcc-arrests-ex-banker-for-stealing-this-amount-from-customers-account/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>[PHOTO] Daughter Of New NNPC Boss, Nkem Delivers Baby Boy</title>
		<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/photo-daughter-of-new-nnpc-boss-nkem-delivers-baby-boy/</link>
		<comments>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/photo-daughter-of-new-nnpc-boss-nkem-delivers-baby-boy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 18:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anu Odusote]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dr Emmanuel Ibe Kachikwu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new nnpc gmd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nkem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nnpc boss]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?p=56652</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[New NNPC boss, Dr Emmanuel Ibe Kachikwu is surely starting on a good and happy note as his daughter, Nkem has given a grandchild just few hours after he was confirmes as the new head of the parastatal. few days after his pronouncement as the new NNPC chief.She gave birth to a bouncing baby boy. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?attachment_id=56654" rel="attachment wp-att-56654"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-56654" src="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/kachikwu.jpg" alt="kachikwu" width="502" height="278" /></a></p>
<p>New NNPC boss, Dr Emmanuel Ibe Kachikwu is surely starting on a good and happy note as his daughter, Nkem has given a grandchild just few hours after he was confirmes as the new head of the parastatal. few days after his pronouncement as the new NNPC chief.She gave birth to a bouncing baby boy.</p>
<p>See the photo of the baby after the cut:</p>
<p><img class="img aligncenter" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xEF5fmGUVCg/VcH27G8Ya-I/AAAAAAAABiA/8I5VejdcdpY/s320/ee.jpg" alt="" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/photo-daughter-of-new-nnpc-boss-nkem-delivers-baby-boy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>[VIDEO] “Mikel Obi Should No Longer Be In The Super Eagles Team” &#8211; Rev. Fr. Mbaka</title>
		<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/video-mikel-obi-should-no-longer-be-in-the-super-eagles-team-rev-fr-mbaka/</link>
		<comments>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/video-mikel-obi-should-no-longer-be-in-the-super-eagles-team-rev-fr-mbaka/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 17:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anu Odusote]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Trending Nigeria]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?p=56668</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Controversial man of God who gained much prominence few months before the end of Jonathan&#8217;s tenure, Rev Fr Mbaka has again made some shocking statements about the state of Nigerian national team known as the Super Eagles.But the one which caught the attention of people was where he clamoured that Mikel Obi should not longer [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?attachment_id=56669" rel="attachment wp-att-56669"><img class=" size-full wp-image-56669 aligncenter" src="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/mbaka-1.jpg" alt="mbaka (1)" width="640" height="400" /></a>Controversial man of God who gained much prominence few months before the end of Jonathan&#8217;s tenure, Rev Fr Mbaka has again made some shocking statements about the state of Nigerian national team known as the Super Eagles.But the one which caught the attention of people was where he clamoured that Mikel Obi should not longer be part of the national team.</p>
<p>Watch the video below</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vgZU7DtwXTg" width="480" height="360" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/video-mikel-obi-should-no-longer-be-in-the-super-eagles-team-rev-fr-mbaka/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breaking: New NNPC GMD, Ibe Kachikwu Sacks All NNPC’s  Group Executives</title>
		<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/breaking-new-nnpc-gmd-ibe-kachikwu-sacks-all-nnpcs-group-executives/</link>
		<comments>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/breaking-new-nnpc-gmd-ibe-kachikwu-sacks-all-nnpcs-group-executives/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 17:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anu Odusote]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ibe Kachikwu Sacks All NNPC’s Group Executives]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?p=56677</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Don't waste money. Check PRICES of Phones, Electronics, Fashion &#038; Appliances on PricePadi.com The 8 Group Executive Directors (GED) of the Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation, NNPC, have been relieved of their appointment in the corporation by the newly-appointed GMD, Dr. Ibe Kachikwu. The GEDs who were relieved of their duties are: Mr. Ian Udoh, Group [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2013/02/15/vandals-why-we-killed-three-nnpc-officials-at-arepo/nnpc-logo-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-5717"><img class=" size-full wp-image-5717 aligncenter" src="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/NNPC-logo1.jpg" alt="NNPC-logo" width="335" height="270" /></a></p><div class="wpInsert wpInsertInPostAd wpInsertMiddle" style="margin: 5px; padding: 0px;"><p style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2;" ><a href="http://pricepadi.com" target="_blank"><font color="FF3300" size="3">Don't waste money. Check PRICES of Phones, Electronics, Fashion & Appliances on PricePadi.com</font></a> </p>

<div style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2; padding-top:7px;">
<script async src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script>
<!-- Sidebar Ad 1 -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:inline-block;width:300px;height:250px"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-2460597205856998"
     data-ad-slot="4203160441"></ins>
<script>
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
</div></div>
<p>The 8 Group Executive Directors (GED) of the Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation, NNPC, have been relieved of their appointment in the corporation by the newly-appointed GMD, Dr. Ibe Kachikwu. The GEDs who were relieved of their duties are: Mr. Ian Udoh, Group Executive Director, Refining &amp; Petrochemicals, Mr. Adebayo Ibirogba, Group Executive Director, Engineering and Technical; Dr David Ige, Group Executive Director, Gas&amp; Power and Dr. Attahir Yusuf, Group Executive Director, Business Development. Others are: Dr.Dan Efebo, Group Executive Director, Corporate Services; Mr. Bernard Otti, Group, Executive Director, Finance &amp; Accounts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/breaking-new-nnpc-gmd-ibe-kachikwu-sacks-all-nnpcs-group-executives/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>[PHOTOS] Oby Ezekwesili And Husband Spotted At Ongoing RCCG Convention</title>
		<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/photos-oby-ezekwesili-and-husband-spotted-at-ongoing-rccg-convention/</link>
		<comments>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/photos-oby-ezekwesili-and-husband-spotted-at-ongoing-rccg-convention/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 17:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anu Odusote]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photo News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oby Ezekwesili And Husband]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RCCG annual Convention]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?p=56673</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Former minister of Education and Bring Back Our Girls Convener, Oby Ezekwesili was spotted alongside her husband, Pastor Chinedu at a Bible College graduation which held during the ongoing RCCG’s annual convention some hours ago. They were also seen at one of the church’s major activities that took place on Tuesday (yesterday). See more photos [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/photos-oby-ezekwesili-and-husband-spotted-at-ongoing-rccg-convention/oby-ezekwesili-and-husband-1/" rel="attachment wp-att-56674"><img class=" size-full wp-image-56674 aligncenter" src="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/oby-ezekwesili-and-husband-1.jpg" alt="oby ezekwesili and husband 1" width="705" height="454" /></a>Former minister of Education and Bring Back Our Girls Convener, Oby Ezekwesili was spotted alongside her husband, Pastor Chinedu at a Bible College graduation which held during the ongoing RCCG’s annual convention some hours ago.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-41626" src="http://stargist.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/oby-ezekwesili-and-husband-1-300x193.jpg" alt="oby ezekwesili and husband 1" width="500" height="322" /></p>
<p>They were also seen at one of the church’s major activities that took place on Tuesday (yesterday).<br />
See more photos below</p>
<p><img class=" aligncenter" src="http://stargist.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/oby-ezekwesili-and-hubby-rccg-convention-300x199.jpeg" alt="oby ezekwesili and hubby rccg convention" width="455" height="302" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-41628" src="http://stargist.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/oby-and-husband-2-300x199.jpeg" alt="oby and husband 2" width="500" height="331" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-41629" src="http://stargist.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/oby-and-husband-3-300x155.jpeg" alt="oby and husband 3" width="500" height="259" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/photos-oby-ezekwesili-and-husband-spotted-at-ongoing-rccg-convention/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tanker Crushes Police Officer In Lagos</title>
		<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/tanker-crushes-police-officer-in-lagos/</link>
		<comments>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/tanker-crushes-police-officer-in-lagos/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 17:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwadara Kasali]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tanker Crushes Police Officer In Lagos]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?p=56642</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A Police Sergeant attached to the Taskforce for dismantling tanker traffic in Apapa area of Lagos was on Tuesday crushed to death by a tanker. Confirming the incident to the News Agency of Nigeria (NAN) on Wednesday, was the spokesperson for the Lagos State Police Command, DSP Patricia Amadin. DSP Amadin, who identified the deceased [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Nigerian-Police.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-20189 aligncenter" src="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Nigerian-Police.jpg" alt="Nigerian Police" width="506" height="310" /></a></p>
<p>A Police Sergeant attached to the Taskforce for dismantling tanker traffic in Apapa area of Lagos was on Tuesday crushed to death by a tanker. Confirming the incident to the News Agency of Nigeria (NAN) on Wednesday, was the spokesperson for the Lagos State Police Command, DSP Patricia Amadin.</p>
<p>DSP Amadin, who identified the deceased officer as Lukas Abashi, disclosed that the driver of the vehicle with Reg. No. ANC 66 XA escaped after the accident. She said the police officer died on the spot after the tanker ran him over.</p><div class="wpInsert wpInsertInPostAd wpInsertMiddle" style="margin: 5px; padding: 0px;"><p style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2;" ><a href="http://pricepadi.com" target="_blank"><font color="FF3300" size="3">Don't waste money. Check PRICES of Phones, Electronics, Fashion & Appliances on PricePadi.com</font></a> </p>

<div style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2; padding-top:7px;">
<script async src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script>
<!-- Sidebar Ad 1 -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:inline-block;width:300px;height:250px"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-2460597205856998"
     data-ad-slot="4203160441"></ins>
<script>
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
</div></div>
<p>The police image maker said the driver attempted to escape with the vehicle, but for the intervention of other members of the taskforce who used motorcycles to pursue him.</p>
<p>Speaking further, she said the policeman was on official duty as at the time of the mishap, adding further details that the tanker had an inscription of TOTAL on it.</p>
<p>Amadin said the body had been deposited in the morgue while the tanker was taken to a police station in Apapa with investigations ongoing to trail the criminal.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/tanker-crushes-police-officer-in-lagos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Governor Ambode Swears In New Permanent Secretaries</title>
		<link>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/governor-ambode-swears-in-new-permanent-secretaries/</link>
		<comments>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/governor-ambode-swears-in-new-permanent-secretaries/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 16:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwadara Kasali]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Governor Ambode Swears In New Permanent Secretaries]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/?p=56644</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Lagos State Governor, Mr. Akinwunmi Ambode, on Wednesday 5th of August, swore in the 19 new Permanent Secretaries, charging them to guide against anything that could compromise standard of government in the course of their duties. The brief ceremony which was held at the State House, Ikeja, was witnessed by family members, friends and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Akinwunmi-Ambode.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-52458" src="http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Akinwunmi-Ambode-300x201.jpg" alt="Akinwunmi-Ambode" width="500" height="335" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Lagos State Governor, Mr. Akinwunmi Ambode, on Wednesday 5th of August, swore in the 19 new Permanent Secretaries, charging them to guide against anything that could compromise standard of government in the course of their duties.</p>
<p>The brief ceremony which was held at the State House, Ikeja, was witnessed by family members, friends and associates of the new permanent secretaries.</p>
<p>The Governor in his address said the quality of service delivered by the government would be measured on daily basis, stressing that &#8220;any ministry where the quality of service is compromised, the permanent secretary, as Accounting Officer, would be held liable.&#8221;</p><div class="wpInsert wpInsertInPostAd wpInsertMiddle" style="margin: 5px; padding: 0px;"><p style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2;" ><a href="http://pricepadi.com" target="_blank"><font color="FF3300" size="3">Don't waste money. Check PRICES of Phones, Electronics, Fashion & Appliances on PricePadi.com</font></a> </p>

<div style="text-align: center; background:#F6F2F2; padding-top:7px;">
<script async src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script>
<!-- Sidebar Ad 1 -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:inline-block;width:300px;height:250px"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-2460597205856998"
     data-ad-slot="4203160441"></ins>
<script>
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
</div></div>
<p>&#8220;I expect nothing but excellence in this centre of excellence,&#8221; Governor Ambode said.</p>
<p>Speaking on behalf of her colleagues, Mrs Adebunmi Adekanye, Permanent Secretary, Office of Civic Engagement, pledged that they will work hard to deliver quality service to move Lagos to the next level, while encouraging cooperation from all to effectively discharge their responsibilities.</p>
<p>The other inaugurated Permanent Secretaries and their portfolio ministries are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Folarin Adeyemi (Information and Strategy)</li>
<li>Olabode Agoro (Lands Bureau),</li>
<li>Ayodele Amosu (Teachers Establishment and Pension Office)</li>
<li>Abiola Anifowoshe (Education District VI),</li>
<li>Olabisi Ariyo (Education)</li>
<li>Caster Bade-Adebowale (Office of the Chief of Staff)</li>
<li>Boladele Dapo-Thomas (Women Affairs and Poverty Alleviation)</li>
<li>Adebisi Kadiri (Economic Planning and Budget)</li>
<li>Olorunfemi Mustapha (Science and Technology).</li>
<li>Adesina Odeyemi (Public Service Office)</li>
<li>Arinola Odulana (Office of Overseas Affairs and Investment)</li>
<li>Adesola Odunlami ( Justice)</li>
<li>Olusola Odupitan (Audit Service Commission)</li>
<li>Olanike Oduwole (Wealth Creation and Employment)</li>
<li>Adesina Onisarotu (Environment)</li>
<li>Dr. Nuriat Sodeinde, (Special Duties and Inter-Governmental Relations).</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.nigerianmonitor.com/2015/08/05/governor-ambode-swears-in-new-permanent-secretaries/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
