<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Punch - Nigeria&#039;s Most Widely Read Newspaper &#187; &#187; News</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.punchng.com/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.punchng.com</link>
	<description>Breaking News, information and opinion in Nigeria</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 01:11:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.2.3</generator>
					
	<item>
		<title>Man arrested over Mexican photojournalist&#8217;s murder</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/man-arrested-over-mexican-photojournalists-murder/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/man-arrested-over-mexican-photojournalists-murder/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 08:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341396</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" />A man with a violent criminal past has been arrested as a suspect in the death of news photographer Ruben Espinosa, who was killed in a gory five-victim murder, Mexican prosecutors said. The male suspect, whose name was not immediately made public, was identified by investigators with a fingerprint search that turned up a criminal...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/man-arrested-over-mexican-photojournalists-murder/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" /><p style="text-align: justify;">A man with a violent criminal past has been arrested as a suspect in the death of news photographer Ruben Espinosa, who was killed in a gory five-victim murder, Mexican prosecutors said.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The male suspect, whose name was not immediately made public, was identified by investigators with a fingerprint search that turned up a criminal record for rape and assault, prosecutor Rodolfo Rios told reporters on Wednesday.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">&#8220;Investigating officers have located him [the suspect] and he is making a statement to their office about his possible involvement in this crime,&#8221; Rios said.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Espinosa, who fled Veracruz in June after receiving threats, was tied up, tortured and shot in the head at an apartment in Mexico City on Friday.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The attackers also killed his friend, Nadia Vera, two of her roommates &#8211; a 19-year-old aspiring makeup artist and a woman believed to be from Colombia &#8211; as well as their 40-year-old housekeeper.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Vera had been active in organising protests for various causes in Veracruz.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Late last year, she had posted a video warning that if anything happened to her, it would be the fault of Governor Javier Duarte.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">On Tuesday, authorities released security camera footage that appeared to show three men near the building where the killings took place.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">They are seen leaving the scene calmly, and are believed to be suspects.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/man-arrested-over-mexican-photojournalists-murder/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" height="90" />			</item>
					
	<item>
		<title>Hundreds feared dead after migrant boat capsizes off Libya</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/hundreds-feared-dead-after-migrant-boat-capsizes-off-libya/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/hundreds-feared-dead-after-migrant-boat-capsizes-off-libya/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 06:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341375</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" />Hundreds of migrants trying to reach across the Mediterranean from Libya are feared to have drowned after their fishing boat capsized off the North African country. Statements on Twitter by UNHCR officials suggest that 399 people have been rescued so far and another 25 confirmed dead out of an estimated 600 migrants on the boat....&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/hundreds-feared-dead-after-migrant-boat-capsizes-off-libya/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" /><p>Hundreds of migrants trying to reach across the Mediterranean from Libya are feared to have drowned after their fishing boat capsized off the North African country.</p>
<p>Statements on Twitter by UNHCR officials suggest that 399 people have been rescued so far and another 25 confirmed dead out of an estimated 600 migrants on the boat.</p>
<p>Karl Stagno-Navarra, a journalist based in Valletta, Malta, told Al Jazeera that an Irish navy vessel confirmed that the boat capsized when the people on board rushed to one side when the LE Niamh got close to it.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Irish vessel LE Niamh was present in the area, as part of the EU-sponsored operations dealing with migration at sea,&#8221; he said, adding that it approached the migrant boat after picking up a distress signal. </p>
<p>The Italian coastguard, a vessel of the Malta-based Migrant Offshore Aid Station and representatives of Doctors Without Borders (MSF) are also present at the scene participating in the operation, Stagno-Navarra said.</p>
<p>&#8220;There have tragically been many deaths, but [the MSF] does not have figures at this stage,&#8221; MSF said on Twitter.</p>
<p>Stagno-Navarra said: &#8220;This is an extremely difficult operation as many migrants do not know how to swim and the conditions are reported to be windy and stormy.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/hundreds-feared-dead-after-migrant-boat-capsizes-off-libya/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" height="90" />			</item>
					
	<item>
		<title>Abandoning Iran nuclear deal could mean war &#8211; Obama</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/abandoning-iran-nuclear-deal-could-mean-war-obama/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/abandoning-iran-nuclear-deal-could-mean-war-obama/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 05:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341374</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" />US President Barack Obama has defended the international nuclear agreement with Iran and warned the US Congress that blocking the pact could spark a war in the Middle East. Obama&#8217;s speech at a Washington university came after Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu launched a campaign on Wednesday to mobilise Jewish Americans to urge the Republican-led...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/abandoning-iran-nuclear-deal-could-mean-war-obama/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" /><p style="text-align: justify;">US President Barack Obama has defended the international nuclear agreement with Iran and warned the US Congress that blocking the pact could spark a war in the Middle East.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Obama&#8217;s speech at a Washington university came after Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu launched a campaign on Wednesday to mobilise Jewish Americans to urge the Republican-led Congress to thwart the historic agreement.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">&#8220;It is a very good deal,&#8221; Obama said.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">&#8220;Every nation in the world that has commented publicly with the exception of the Israeli government has expressed support,&#8221; Obama said.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">&#8220;I recognise (Israeli) Prime Minister Netanyahu disagrees, disagrees strongly &#8211; I do not doubt his sincerity &#8211; but I believe he is wrong.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Under the agreement reached between Iran and a group of six world powers known as the P5+1, the countries agreed to lift economic sanctions against Iran in return for curbs on its nuclear programme.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Obama warned that abandoning the July 14 pact could accelerate Tehran&#8217;s path to a bomb and America&#8217;s credibility around the world would be seriously damaged if it refused to abide by the terms of the deal in lifting sanctions against Iran.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/abandoning-iran-nuclear-deal-could-mean-war-obama/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" height="90" />			</item>
					
	<item>
		<title>Fraudsters solicit money  in Lagos dep gov’s name</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/fraudsters-solicit-money-in-lagos-dep-govs-name/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/fraudsters-solicit-money-in-lagos-dep-govs-name/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341325</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" /> Sesan Olufowobi The Deputy Governor of Lagos State, Mrs. Idiat Adebule, had raised the alarm on the activities of some fraudsters in the state who have been using her name and particulars on the social media, especially the Facebook. Adebule on Wednesday lamented that the fraudsters had been using her name to defraud some innocent...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/fraudsters-solicit-money-in-lagos-dep-govs-name/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" /><p style="text-align: justify;"> Sesan Olufowobi</p>
<p>The Deputy Governor of Lagos State, Mrs. Idiat Adebule, had raised the alarm on the activities of some fraudsters in the state who have been using her name and particulars on the social media, especially the Facebook.<br />
Adebule on Wednesday lamented that the fraudsters had been using her name to defraud some innocent members of the public, urging them to be wary of the fraudsters in order not to fall victims.<br />
The deputy governor, in a statement, said one of the fraudsters  recently “linked me with one deceptive Federal Government Empowerment Scheme which was advertised on the Facebook in a bid to defraud the public.”<br />
The statement read in part, “We wish to bring to your attention, the activities of cyber fraudsters and some impostors impersonating Mrs. Idiat Adebule, the Deputy Governor of Lagos State, via social media platforms, including the Facebook, with the intention of defrauding unsuspecting citizens.<br />
“They are attempting to capitalise on her goodwill to defraud members of the public, particularly her associates and members of her religious organisation.”<br />
The statement added that efforts were on the top gear to apprehend those behind this mischievous act in due course.<br />
Adebule urged her friends, associate and family members to disregard any financial appeal via social media, saying she had neither made the appeal in person nor through any agent.<br />
She advised that such scam should be reported to the appropriate law enforcement agencies to ensure that the perpetrators were brought to book.<br />
The deputy governor said, “I have suspended all my social media activities, while the public will be duly informed on the platforms to use in sharing ideas and opinions on government policies and programmes with me in the near future.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/fraudsters-solicit-money-in-lagos-dep-govs-name/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" height="90" />			</item>
		<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Mr.-Akinwunmi-Ambode-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Lagos State Governor, Mr. Akinwunmi Ambode" />	<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Mr.-Akinwunmi-Ambode-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Lagos State Governor, Mr. Akinwunmi Ambode" />		
	<item>
		<title>Lagos releases 11bn for pension payment</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/lagos-releases-11bn-for-pension-payment/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/lagos-releases-11bn-for-pension-payment/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341328</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Mr.-Akinwunmi-Ambode-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" />The Lagos State Government has released N11bn to offset pension liabilities in arrears in the state since 2010. The government said the move was to bring succour to all retirees in the Lagos State Public Service. The Head of Service, Mrs. Folashade Jaji, on Wednesday in Alausa, Ikeja, said the state Governor, Akinwunmi Ambode, had...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/lagos-releases-11bn-for-pension-payment/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Mr.-Akinwunmi-Ambode-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" /><p style="text-align: justify;">The Lagos State Government has released N11bn to offset pension liabilities in arrears in the state since 2010.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The government said the move was to bring succour to all retirees in the Lagos State Public Service.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Head of Service, Mrs. Folashade Jaji, on Wednesday in Alausa, Ikeja, said the state Governor, Akinwunmi Ambode, had directed that the sum should be used to pay the pension liabilities of the Lagos State Government mainstream retirees and the retirees in local governments areas and parastatal organisations.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Jaji said, “The development is part of efforts put in place by the present administration to find a holistic solution to the issue of payment of pension entitlements to retirees under the pay-as-you-go pension scheme which was discontinued in April 2007, as well as outstanding accrued pension rights due to retirees under the contributory pension scheme.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Head of Service said the government had developed a comprehensive payment plan to resolve all outstanding pension issues in the short, medium and long terms.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">She said, “The short or immediate term plan is for pension payments to ministries, departments and agencies and parastatals, including local government areas and SUBEB, which will be made monthly commencing from August, 2015.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Jaji said the efforts were the outcome of painstaking deliberations by the Public Service Pensions Office, the Lagos State Pensions Commission, the Head of Service and the governor to “reduce, if not totally clear,” the outstanding liabilities due to retirees in the mainstream public service, LGAs and parastatals in the state.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/lagos-releases-11bn-for-pension-payment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Mr.-Akinwunmi-Ambode-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" />			</item>
		<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Lagos-perm-secs-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Some of the newly appointed Perm-Secs" />	<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Lagos-perm-secs-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Some of the newly appointed Perm-Secs" />		
	<item>
		<title>Ambode warns perm secs against compromise</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/ambode-warns-perm-secs-against-compromise/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/ambode-warns-perm-secs-against-compromise/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341326</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Lagos-perm-secs-360x223.jpg" width="360" height="223" />The Lagos State Governor, Akinwunmi Ambode, has warned civil servants, especially the permanent secretaries, in the state against compromise in the discharge of their duties to the people. The governor said he would hold the permanent secretary liable in any ministry found to have compromised in the state. Ambode spoke on Wednesday at the Lagos...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/ambode-warns-perm-secs-against-compromise/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Lagos-perm-secs-360x223.jpg" width="360" height="223" /><p style="text-align: justify;">The Lagos State Governor, Akinwunmi Ambode, has warned civil servants, especially the permanent secretaries, in the state against compromise in the discharge of their duties to the people.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The governor said he would hold the permanent secretary liable in any ministry found to have compromised in the state.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Ambode spoke on Wednesday at the Lagos House, Ikeja, during the swearing-in of 19 new permanent secretaries.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He reminded the new accounting officers of the state ministries that the quality of service delivered by this government would be measured through them on daily basis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He said, “Any ministry where the quality of service is compromised, the permanent secretary, as the accounting officer, would be held liable. I expect nothing but excellence in this centre of excellence.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“I expect you to apply the best tenets of the civil service in your roles as accounting officers of your ministries, making excellent service and the common good of all Lagosians your watchwords.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“Your appointments, from a pool of equally competent and qualified directors, were as a result of a careful selection based on merit, professionalism and proven track record of service to the state.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The governor said during his inaugural address, he promised to carry out public sector reforms, adding that such could be seen in the merging and realignment of ministries and agencies, as well as the creation of new ones.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He said, “We have established the Ministry of Wealth Creation and Employment, the Ministry of Overseas Affairs and Investment, and the Office of Civic Engagement to run an inclusive government and create better opportunities for our people.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Ambode said the next phase was the constitution of cabinet to consolidate on the foundation that had been laid in the last 60 days.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Earlier, the Head of Service, Mrs. Folashade Jaji, who presented the new appointees to the governor, stated that the governor used exemplary performance and merit as core criteria for elevation into higher posts in the state public service.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“There is no doubt in my mind that with these appointments, a strong message has been sent across in the state public service by His Excellency that diligence, dedication, commitment, loyalty and hard work will ultimately be rewarded,” she said.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Speaking on behalf of others, Mrs. Adebunmi Adekanye, Permanent Secretary, Office of Civic Engagement, pledged that she and her colleagues would work to deliver quality service to move the state to the next level.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Other permanent secretaries and their portfolio ministries are: Folarin Adeyemi, Information and Strategy; Olabode Agoro, Lands Bureau; Ayodele Amosu, Teachers Establishment and Pension Office; Abiola Anifowoshe, Education District VI; Olabisi Ariyo, Education; Caster Bade-Adebowale, Office of the Chief of Staff; Boladele Dapo-Thomas, Women Affairs and Poverty Alleviation; Adebisi Kadiri, Economic Planning and Budget; Olorunfemi Mustapha, Science and Technology; Adesina Odeyemi, Public Service Office; Arinola Odulana, Office of Overseas Affairs and Investment; Adesola Odunlami, Justice; Olusola Odupitan, Audit Service Commission; Olanike Oduwole, Wealth Creation and Employment; Adesina Onisarotu, Environment and Nuriat Sodeinde, Special Duties and Inter-Governmental Relations.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">
<p style="text-align: justify;">
<p style="text-align: justify;">
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/ambode-warns-perm-secs-against-compromise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Lagos-perm-secs-360x223.jpg" width="360" height="223" />			</item>
		<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Mr.-Ehidiamhem-Okoyomon-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Mr. Ehidiamhem Okoyomon" />	<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Mr.-Ehidiamhem-Okoyomon-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Mr. Ehidiamhem Okoyomon" />		
	<item>
		<title>Court summons comptroller over refusal to produce ex-Mint boss</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/court-summons-comptroller-over-refusal-to-produce-ex-mint-boss/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/court-summons-comptroller-over-refusal-to-produce-ex-mint-boss/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 23:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341283</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Mr.-Ehidiamhem-Okoyomon-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" />A High Court of the Federal Capital Territory in Apo, Abuja, on Wednesday ordered the Deputy Comptroller of Prison, Kuje, Abuja, Musa Tanko, to appear in court on August 12 for refusing to produce detained former Managing Director of the Nigerian Security Printing and Minting Company, Emmanuel Okoyomon. Justice Valentine Ashi had, by an ex...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/court-summons-comptroller-over-refusal-to-produce-ex-mint-boss/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Mr.-Ehidiamhem-Okoyomon-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" /><p style="text-align: justify">A High Court of the Federal Capital Territory in Apo, Abuja, on Wednesday ordered the Deputy Comptroller of Prison, Kuje, Abuja, Musa Tanko, to appear in court on August 12 for refusing to produce detained former Managing Director of the Nigerian Security Printing and Minting Company, Emmanuel Okoyomon.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Justice Valentine Ashi had, by an ex parte order upon an application by Okoyomon, directing the defendants in the suit – Deputy Comptroller in Charge of Medium Security Prison, Kuje, and Attorney General of the Federation – to produce him in court and show cause why he should not be granted bail.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">But rather than obey the court’s order, the prison boss wrote directly to the judge, stating that Okoyomon was being held in Kuje prison by virtue of a remand order by the Court of Appeal.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The prison officer insisted that Okoyomon could only be produced in any court with the permission of the court that ordered his remand.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Justice Ashi, who got angry with the prison official’s position, described the conduct as a contempt of court and disobedience to a valid court order.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“The procedure adopted by the 1st respondent (Deputy Comptroller in Charge of Medium Security Prison, Kuje) is reprehensible and contemptuous of the court,” the judge said.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">He added that the decision by the prison officer to write directly to him (the judge) was disrespectful of the institution of the court.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">He then ordered the prison official to attend court on the next adjourned date to show the reason why he should not be imprisoned for contempt of court.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Lawyer to the AGF, Muslim Hassan, however apologised on behalf of the prison official and assured that the defendants held the court in high esteem.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Justice Evoh Chukwu of the Federal High Court, Abuja, had on May 4, 2015 granted an application by the AGF for the extradition of Okoyomon to the United Kingdom, where he is wanted for bribery allegation involving officials of the Central Bank of Nigeria and Securency International Pty of Australia between 2006 and 2008.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Okoyomon appealed the High Court decision at the Court of Appeal, Abuja.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">He also applied to the court for bail and stay of execution of the decision by Justice Chukwu.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">But, in its ruling on June 26, the appellate court rejected the bail application on the ground that it was unmeritorious.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The appellate court however granted Okoyomon’s request for stay of execution of the judgment of the Federal High Court, Abuja, directing the Federal Government to proceed with his extradition.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Okoyomon then approached the FCT High Court again challenging his continued detention.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The Office of the Attorney General has faulted his new suit and accused him of misleading Justice Ashi into assuming jurisdiction over the case.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">In the counter-affidavit and notice of preliminary objection filed for the AGF, it was argued that Okoyomon, having been detained on the order of the Court of Appeal, ought to either proceed to the Supreme Court or pursue his pending appeal. It urged the court to dismiss the case for lacking the jurisdiction to hear it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The judge adjourned the case till August 12 for the hearing of the objection filed by the AGF and for the prison official to attend court and show cause why he should not be imprisoned for contempt.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">
<p style="text-align: justify">
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/court-summons-comptroller-over-refusal-to-produce-ex-mint-boss/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Mr.-Ehidiamhem-Okoyomon-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" />			</item>
		<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/President-Muhammadu-Buhari3-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="President Muhammadu Buhari" />	<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/President-Muhammadu-Buhari3-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="President Muhammadu Buhari" />		
	<item>
		<title>Buhari fires eight NNPC group executive directors</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/buhari-fires-eight-nnpc-group-executive-directors/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/buhari-fires-eight-nnpc-group-executive-directors/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 23:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business & Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341293</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/President-Muhammadu-Buhari3-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" />Twenty-four hours after the Federal Government replaced the Group Managing Director of the Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation, it announced the sacking of all the eight executive directors of the corporation. This was confirmed by the Group General Manager, Group Public Affairs Division, NNPC, Mr. Ohi Alegbe, in a statement on Wednesday night in Abuja. Alegbe...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/buhari-fires-eight-nnpc-group-executive-directors/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/President-Muhammadu-Buhari3-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" /><p style="text-align: justify">Twenty-four hours after the Federal Government replaced the Group Managing Director of the Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation, it announced the sacking of all the eight executive directors of the corporation.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">This was confirmed by the Group General Manager, Group Public Affairs Division, NNPC, Mr. Ohi Alegbe, in a statement on Wednesday night in Abuja.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Alegbe said in the statement, “The Federal Government has approved the retirement of all eight group executive directors of the NNPC with immediate effect.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“The affected group executive directors are Mr. Bernard Otti, GED, Finance and Accounts; Dr. Timothy Okon, acting GED, Exploration and Production, who also doubled as the Coordinator, Corporate Planning &amp; Strategy; Mr. Adebayo Ibirogba, Engineering and Technology; Dr. David Ige, Gas and Power; Ms. Aisha Abdurrahman, Commercial and Investment; Dr. Dan Efebo, Corporate Services; Mr. Ian Udoh, Refining &amp; Petrochemicals; and Dr. Attahiru Yusuf, Business Development.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The statement noted that the new Group Managing Director of the NNPC, Dr. Ibe Kachikwu, personally conveyed the Federal Government’s decision to the GEDs.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">He expressed gratitude to them for their services to the corporation and wished them success in their future endeavours.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">No replacements were named, but our correspondent gathered that four new group executive director positions had been created and that some names were already being considered by President Muhammadu Buhari to fill them.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Sources at the corporation gave the new directorates as of Refining and Engineering, Exploration and Production, Commercial and Investment, and Finance.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Buhari had a week ago, pledged to fix the oil sector, rid the industry of rot and recover money stolen by operators in the sector.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">On Tuesday, he relieved Dr. Joseph Dawha of his appointment as the GMD of the national oil firm, replacing him with Kachikwu, who until his appointment was the Executive Vice Chairman and General Counsel of Exxon-Mobil (Africa).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The President had in late June dissolved the NNPC board.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The Federal Government, through the NNPC, regulates and participates in the country’s petroleum industry.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The NNPC was established on April 1, 1977 as a merger of the Nigerian National Oil Corporation and the Federal Ministry of Mines and Steel.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The law that created the firm permits it to manage the joint ventures between the Federal Government and some foreign multinational corporations, including Shell, Agip, ExxonMobil, Chevron and Total.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Through the collaboration with the companies, the Federal Government conducts petroleum exploration and production.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">But industry observers had on several occasions complained that the corporation lacked supervision, stressing that it had degenerated to a rent-collector for the government with less attention to transparency and accountability.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">On Tuesday, the New York-based Natural Resources Governance Initiative canvassed the need to overhaul the management of the country’s oil sales process by the NNPC as top priority for the Buhari-led administration to stem waste and loss of billions of dollars in revenue.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The international watchdog said in one of its latest reports that the NNPC’s approach to oil sales was suffering from high corruption risks and had failed to maximise returns for the nation.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The authors of the NRGI report, led by Aaron Sayne, said, “We find that management of the NNPC’s oil sales has worsened in recent years, and particularly since 2010. The largest problems stem from the rising number of ad hoc, makeshift practices the corporation has introduced to work around its deeper structural problems.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The NNPC receives about one million barrels of oil per day, or almost half of the country’s total production, part of which is sold to its subsidiary, Pipelines and Product Marketing Company, for the country’s refineries, while a larger volume is sold to traders.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">
<p style="text-align: justify">
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/buhari-fires-eight-nnpc-group-executive-directors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/President-Muhammadu-Buhari3-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" />			</item>
		<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Rivers-State-Governor-Nyesom-Wike-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Rivers State Governor, Nyesom Wike" />	<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Rivers-State-Governor-Nyesom-Wike-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Rivers State Governor, Nyesom Wike" />		
	<item>
		<title>Tribunal dismisses four petitions against Wike’s election</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/tribunal-dismisses-four-petitions-against-wikes-election/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/tribunal-dismisses-four-petitions-against-wikes-election/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 23:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341275</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Rivers-State-Governor-Nyesom-Wike.jpg" width="260" height="227" />Ade Adesomoju, Abuja The Rivers State Governorship Election Petitions Tribunal sitting in Abuja has dismissed four out of the five petitions filed to challenge the election of Chief Nyesom Wike of the Peoples Democratic Party as the governor of the state. The only surviving petition challenging the declaration of Wike as the winner of the...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/tribunal-dismisses-four-petitions-against-wikes-election/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Rivers-State-Governor-Nyesom-Wike.jpg" width="260" height="227" /><p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Ade Adesomoju, Abuja</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The Rivers State Governorship Election Petitions Tribunal sitting in Abuja has dismissed four out of the five petitions filed to challenge the election of Chief Nyesom Wike of the Peoples Democratic Party as the governor of the state.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The only surviving petition challenging the declaration of Wike as the winner of the April 11 election is the one filed by the All Progressives Congress and its governorship candidate, Dr. Dakuku Peterside.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Though, one of the four petitions marked EPT/RV/GOV/05/2015 was voluntarily withdrawn by the petitioner, Kemka Elenwo, who was KOWA Party’s governorship candidate in the election, the three others were dismissed on technical grounds based on the application by Wike and the PDP.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The Justice Mu’azu Pindiga-led tribunal on Wednesday dismissed the fourth petition marked EPT/RV/GOV/03/2015 which was filed by Minaibim Harry of the Social Democratic Party on the grounds that the petition was incompetent.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The tribunal held that it lacked the jurisdiction to entertain the petition since the two grounds on which it was anchored were defective because they were not in strict compliance with the provisions of Section 138(1) (a) to (d) of the Electoral Act.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The said provision of the Electoral Act prescribes the grounds on which an election petition can be filed.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Other petitions that have been dismissed by the tribunal include the one filed by the Labour Party (EPT/RV/GOV/01/2015) and another by the All Progressive Grand Alliance and its candidate, Charles Harry, (EPT/RV/GOV/02/2015).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">In its ruling on July 31, Justice Pindiga, who dismissed the petition by the Labour Party which fielded Tonye Princewill in the April 11 election, held that the party did not have a candidate for the election having not complied with the requirement under Section 85(1) of the Electoral Act (EA) 2010.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">It noted that the notice given by the petitioner to INEC of its intention to conduct a primary election from which the petitioner’s candidate purportedly emerged “is less than the mandatory 21 days required by Section 85(1) of the Electoral Act.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“By implication, the effect of this non-compliance, is that no valid primary election was conducted and held by the petitioner and its purported candidate.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The tribunal also found that the petitioner did not comply with the required procedure for applying for the issuance of pre-hearing notice, a default which rendered the petition inconsequential.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">
<p style="text-align: justify">
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/tribunal-dismisses-four-petitions-against-wikes-election/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Rivers-State-Governor-Nyesom-Wike.jpg" width="260" height="227" />			</item>
		<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/CBN-Governor-Mr.-Godwin-Emefiele-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="CBN Governor, Mr. Godwin Emefiele" />	<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/CBN-Governor-Mr.-Godwin-Emefiele-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="CBN Governor, Mr. Godwin Emefiele" />		
	<item>
		<title>Senate summons CBN governor over naira depreciation</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/senate-summons-cbn-governor-over-naira-depreciation/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/senate-summons-cbn-governor-over-naira-depreciation/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 23:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business & Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341289</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/CBN-Governor-Mr.-Godwin-Emefiele-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" />The Senate on Wednesday passed a motion directing the Governor of the Central Bank of Nigeria, Mr. Godwin Emefiele, to appear before it to brief members on the state of the nation’s economy, especially the alarming naira depreciation. The upper chamber gave the directive after an exhaustive debate on a motion moved by Senator Nazfiz...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/senate-summons-cbn-governor-over-naira-depreciation/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/CBN-Governor-Mr.-Godwin-Emefiele-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" /><p style="text-align: justify">The Senate on Wednesday passed a motion directing the Governor of the Central Bank of Nigeria, Mr. Godwin Emefiele, to appear before it to brief members on the state of the nation’s economy, especially the alarming naira depreciation.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The upper chamber gave the directive after an exhaustive debate on a motion moved by Senator Nazfiz Suleiman (Bauchi North) entitled: ‘The state of the economy: Naira depreciation and its implications’.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The senators also urged the Federal Government to step up efforts to diversify the nation’s economy to depend on taxation, agriculture, manufacturing, international tourism and solid mineral prospecting. Suleiman had in his lead debate noted with serious concern the state of the nation’s economy as it affected the continuous depreciation of the naira.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">He expressed worry that naira had depreciated in the last few months at a much faster rate than it appreciated over the last two years.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The senator further argued that the depreciation was the consequence of the negative cash flow, which he said resulted from the downward trend of oil prices.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">He added that the situation had been worsened by speculations in the foreign exchange market.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Suleiman also observed that the foreign exchange needs of various sectors of the economy were not being made available, while Nigeria’s commitments in the global economy had dwindled.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The senator also expressed concern that the Nigerian banking industry might be currently defaulting in the global economy, stressing that the situation had been sending a wrong signal about the state of the economy.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Suleiman also said the speculation caused by the situation was resulting in a huge capital flight, with the attendant inflationary consequence, which he said would affect an average Nigerian on the street.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“The illicit fund flows and money laundering going through Nigerian financial system contribute in weakening the value of the naira, which has made the recent decisions of CBN to increase its vigilance to ensure that Nigeria banks are not used as conduit for illicit fund flow and money laundering in foreign currencies,” he said.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">He stressed the need to regulate the demand and supply of foreign exchange by the CBN with various options in order to curtail naira depreciation and discourage speculation.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">In his contribution, the Minority Whip, Senator Philip Aduda, blamed the downward slide in the value of naira on the inability of the Federal Government to put in place stable economic policies.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Senator Gbolahan Dada (Ogun West) said if the situation must be effectively tackled, Nigeria must define its economic policies and make laws that would address fraud.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">He lamented that the country’s dependence on imported items without tangible production had been the bane of a stable naira exchange rate.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Senate President, Bukola Saraki, said all powers must be deployed to defend the naira and that the influx of foreign items into the country must be adequately curtailed in a way that the activities of currency speculators would be brought under control.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">
<p style="text-align: justify">
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/senate-summons-cbn-governor-over-naira-depreciation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/CBN-Governor-Mr.-Godwin-Emefiele-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" />			</item>
		<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Enugu-State-Governor-Ifeanyi-Ugwuanyi-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Enugu State Governor, Ifeanyi Ugwuanyi" />	<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Enugu-State-Governor-Ifeanyi-Ugwuanyi-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Enugu State Governor, Ifeanyi Ugwuanyi" />		
	<item>
		<title>Enugu approves three-week paternity leave</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/enugu-approves-three-week-paternity-leave/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/enugu-approves-three-week-paternity-leave/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 23:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341278</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Enugu-State-Governor-Ifeanyi-Ugwuanyi.jpg" width="210" height="236" />The Enugu State Government has amended its Civil Service rules to grant six months maternity leave to nursing mothers. Interestingly, husbands whose wives might put to bed were also given a ‘paternity leave’, but it would only be for just three weeks. The paternity leave was meant to give such husbands the opportunity to support...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/enugu-approves-three-week-paternity-leave/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Enugu-State-Governor-Ifeanyi-Ugwuanyi.jpg" width="210" height="236" /><p style="text-align: justify;">The Enugu State Government has amended its Civil Service rules to grant six months maternity leave to nursing mothers.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Interestingly, husbands whose wives might put to bed were also given a ‘paternity leave’, but it would only be for just three weeks.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The paternity leave was meant to give such husbands the opportunity to support their nursing wives, according to the state government.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Before, female workers who gave birth were entitled to three months maternity leave while the men whose wives delivered babies were not exempted from work.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Similarly, the state government also resolved that henceforth, nursing mothers were free to breast-feed their babies in offices during work hours.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The state Commissioner for Health, Dr. Sam Ngwu, who disclosed these in Enugu on Wednesday, said the new policy would strengthen the family as a social unit and also promote mother and child welfare.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Unveiling plans to mark the 2015 Breast Feeding Week in the state, Ngwu explained that the extension of the maternity leave would encourage nursing mothers in the state to engage in the internationally recommended four to six months exclusive breast feeding of newborn babies.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The commissioner, who was represented by the Permanent Secretary in the Ministry of Health, Dr. Moses Otiji, noted that the state has been marking ‘’the Breast Feeding Week’’ every year in order to galvanise support for nursing mothers.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Ngwu further explained that the theme of this year’s Breast Feeding Week &#8211; ‘Breast feeding and work, let’s make it happen’, was in line with the state government’s commitment to the needs of nursing mothers and newborns.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He said nursing mothers should be allowed to continuously breast feed their babies anywhere they work, whether in the private or public sector.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">According to him, lectures would be organised for nursing mothers in the course of the breast feeding week to enable them learn more about exclusive breast feeding.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“The week is dedicated to draw the attention of the public on the need for exclusive breast feeding.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“The breast contains yellow milk that contains most of the vital ingredients for healthy growth of the baby.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“It protects the baby from diseases and promotes bonding between mother and child,” he added.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">
<p style="text-align: justify;">
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/enugu-approves-three-week-paternity-leave/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Enugu-State-Governor-Ifeanyi-Ugwuanyi.jpg" width="210" height="236" />			</item>
		<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/A-cross-section-of-NYSC-members-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="A cross-section of NYSC members" />	<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/A-cross-section-of-NYSC-members-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="A cross-section of NYSC members" />		
	<item>
		<title>Buhari rules out scrapping of NYSC scheme</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/buhari-rules-out-scrapping-of-nysc-scheme-2/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/buhari-rules-out-scrapping-of-nysc-scheme-2/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 23:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341265</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/A-cross-section-of-NYSC-members-360x219.jpg" width="360" height="219" />President Muhammadu Buhari on Wednesday ruled out the possibility of scrapping the National Youth Service Corps as being suggested in some quarters. This was just as the NYSC management was considering the option of making the scheme voluntary in order to reduce the intake of corps members. There had been calls for the scrapping of...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/buhari-rules-out-scrapping-of-nysc-scheme-2/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/A-cross-section-of-NYSC-members-360x219.jpg" width="360" height="219" /><p style="text-align: justify">President Muhammadu Buhari on Wednesday ruled out the possibility of scrapping the National Youth Service Corps as being suggested in some quarters.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">This was just as the NYSC management was considering the option of making the scheme voluntary in order to reduce the intake of corps members.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">There had been calls for the scrapping of the scheme since the outbreak of insurgency in parts of the country.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Insurgency had claimed the lives of some corps members in the northern parts of the country.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Proponents of the scrapping of the scheme had been arguing that the NYSC had outlived its usefulness.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">But a statement by the Special Adviser to the President on Media and Publicity, Mr. Femi Adesina, quoted Buhari as pledging that his administration would take all necessary actions to maintain and improve the scheme as a functional vehicle for the promotion of national unity and integration.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Adesina said the President gave the assurance after receiving a briefing from officials of the Ministry of Youth Development led by the Permanent Secretary of the ministry, Mrs. Rabi Jimeta.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The President was said to have affirmed his confidence and trust in the programme, saying that the objective for which the scheme was established in 1973 was still very relevant for national development.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“I firmly believe in the NYSC and I think it should remain a national programme to promote integration.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“Whenever I go home to Daura, I look out for corps members from Lagos, Aba and other parts of the country.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“I am always thrilled to learn that except for the NYSC, some of them have never left their states of origin to visit other cities in the country,” the President told the ministry’s officials.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Jimeta told the President that the increasing number of NYSC participants posed a challenge to the scheme due to the dwindling revenue from the national budget to cater for their needs.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">She told the President that the annual enrolment of participants in the scheme had increased from 2,364 at inception in 1974 to 229,016 in 2014.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“Given the increasing number of tertiary institutions, our projection is that the number of corps participants may rise to 300,000 by year 2020,’’ she said.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Adesina also quoted the Director General of the NYSC, Brig.-Gen. Johnson Olawumi, as telling the President that there were plans to make the scheme voluntary.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">This, he said, Adewunmi explained was meant to reduce the corps population in order to make the programme more sustainable.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">
<p style="text-align: justify">
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/buhari-rules-out-scrapping-of-nysc-scheme-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/A-cross-section-of-NYSC-members-360x219.jpg" width="360" height="219" />			</item>
		<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/PDP-National-Secretary-Prof.-Wale-Oladipo-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="PDP National Secretary, Prof. Wale Oladipo" />	<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/PDP-National-Secretary-Prof.-Wale-Oladipo-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="PDP National Secretary, Prof. Wale Oladipo" />		
	<item>
		<title>PDP crisis: Workers vow not to apologise</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/pdp-crisis-workers-vow-not-to-apologise/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/pdp-crisis-workers-vow-not-to-apologise/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 23:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341274</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/PDP-National-Secretary-Prof.-Wale-Oladipo-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" />Aggrieved workers of the Peoples Democratic Party have vowed not to tender letters of apology as demanded by members of the National Working Committee of the party before discussions on how to end the ongoing crisis between them and members of the NWC would begin. It was gathered that the members of the NWC at...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/pdp-crisis-workers-vow-not-to-apologise/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/PDP-National-Secretary-Prof.-Wale-Oladipo-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" /><p style="text-align: justify">Aggrieved workers of the Peoples Democratic Party have vowed not to tender letters of apology as demanded by members of the National Working Committee of the party before discussions on how to end the ongoing crisis between them and members of the NWC would begin.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">It was gathered that the members of the NWC at their weekly meeting on Wednesday reportedly directed the angry workers to write individual letters of apology and show remorse for their action before they could be listen to by the NWC.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">One of the workers, who spoke to journalists on condition of anonymity said, “We we have been directed to write letters of apology and copy the Chairman, PDP Board of Trustees; the National Executive Committee and the Chairman, PDP Governors’ Forum before they could listen to us.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“The NWC members said they were sad that we have caused the party a lot of embarrassment; they complained that we ought to have channelled our grievances through the Director of Administration, who, in turn, will pass it through the National Secretary to the NWC &#8211; without our making the whole matter public.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">It was learnt that the NWC took the decision after its meeting with the management staff of the party, which was held at the Legacy House, Maitama, Abuja.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Since the crisis started, the NWC members have been avoiding the party’s national secretariat, located at Zone 5, Abuja.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Representatives of the workers who were at the meeting with the NWC members took their report to their colleagues at an emergency meeting held inside the NEC hall at the party’s secretariat.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">At the meeting, which lasted about 30 minutes, the workers said there was no need to apologise.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">A source at the meeting stated that, “The Director of Administration, Bawa Gurama, counselled that we should sheathe our sword and comply with the NWC directives and await further action from the NWC.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Findings revealed that though the angry workers admitted that they could be blamed for externalising the crisis, they, nevertheless, maintained that “they stand by the reply to the memo issued by the National Secretary, Prof. Wale Oladipo, to them.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The source said, “We are not to be blamed for making the issue a public matter. It was the memo which the NWC leaked to the public through the National Secretary that led to our reaction.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“We will not apologise because we are not to blame for how it became a public issue. Therefore, we stand by the content of the reply to the National Secretary.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">It will be recalled that Oladipo had in a memo dated July 29, and directed to all directors and “PS/DD/HOD/SAs/PAs and Establishment Staff” of the party in Abuja, said the party was going to sack 50 per cent of its workers.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/pdp-crisis-workers-vow-not-to-apologise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/PDP-National-Secretary-Prof.-Wale-Oladipo-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" />			</item>
		<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Naira-and-dollar-notes-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Naira and dollar notes" />	<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Naira-and-dollar-notes-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Naira and dollar notes" />		
	<item>
		<title>CBN bans cash deposits into domiciliary accounts</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/cbn-bans-cash-deposits-into-domiciliary-accounts/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/cbn-bans-cash-deposits-into-domiciliary-accounts/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 23:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business & Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341291</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Naira-and-dollar-notes-360x235.jpg" width="360" height="235" />The Central Bank of Nigeria has banned the payment of cash into domiciliary accounts in the country, TheCable reports. In a circular released on Wednesday and signed by the Director of Trade and Exchange, CBN, Olakanmi Gbadamosi, the central bank said its action followed recent statements by individual banks suspending the payment of foreign currencies...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/cbn-bans-cash-deposits-into-domiciliary-accounts/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Naira-and-dollar-notes-360x235.jpg" width="360" height="235" /><p style="text-align: justify">The Central Bank of Nigeria has banned the payment of cash into domiciliary accounts in the country, <em>TheCable</em> reports.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">In a circular released on Wednesday and signed by the Director of Trade and Exchange, CBN, Olakanmi Gbadamosi, the central bank said its action followed recent statements by individual banks suspending the payment of foreign currencies into domiciliary accounts.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Gbadamosi wrote, “The Central Bank of Nigeria has considered the recent statements by Deposit Money Banks concerning the large volume of foreign currencies in their vaults and the decision to stop accepting foreign currency cash deposits into customers’ domiciliary accounts as a welcome development.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“Therefore, in its continued efforts to stop illicit financial flows in the Nigerian banking system which aligns with the anti-money Laundering stance of the Federal Government, the CBN hereby prohibits from the date of this circular the acceptance of foreign currency cash deposits by DMBs.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“For foreign currency cash lodgements made prior to the date of this circular, the account holder has the option to either withdraw his or her foreign currency cash or the Naira equivalent. For the avoidance of doubt, only wire transfers to and from Domiciliary Accounts are henceforth permissible.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“The CBN advises individuals that wish to source foreign currency for eligible and legitimate purposes such as BTA, PTA medical, mortgage, school fees, goods etc. to do so through recognised channels with the use of Form ‘A’ for “invisible” and Form ‘M’ for ‘visible’ transactions. By this circular, those who deposited foreign currencies into their accounts before the directive will now have to withdraw the cash as they are not going to be allowed to transfer the funds.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/cbn-bans-cash-deposits-into-domiciliary-accounts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Naira-and-dollar-notes-360x235.jpg" width="360" height="235" />			</item>
		<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/President-Muhammadu-Buhari6-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="President Muhammadu Buhari" />	<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/President-Muhammadu-Buhari6-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="President Muhammadu Buhari" />		
	<item>
		<title>Aviation debt profile worries Buhari</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/?p=341251</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/?p=341251#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 23:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341251</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/President-Muhammadu-Buhari6-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" />President Muhammadu Buhari on Wednesday raised concern over the enormous debt profile of Nigeria’s aviation sector, promising that his administration would act quickly to redress the situation. Special Adviser to the President on Media and Publicity, Mr. Femi Adesina, said this in a statement made available to journalists in Abuja. Adesina said Buhari spoke after...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/?p=341251">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/President-Muhammadu-Buhari6-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" /><p style="text-align: justify;">President Muhammadu Buhari on Wednesday raised concern over the enormous debt profile of Nigeria’s aviation sector, promising that his administration would act quickly to redress the situation.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Special Adviser to the President on Media and Publicity, Mr. Femi Adesina, said this in a statement made available to journalists in Abuja.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Adesina said Buhari spoke after receiving a briefing from officials of the Ministry of Aviation in the Presidential Villa, Abuja.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The President was quoted as saying, ‘‘I am concerned about the enormous debt profile in the aviation sector. The Federal Government has to do something quickly because safety, security and international respectability are involved here.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“Our airports are the windows through which people see our country. Anybody coming into the country will likely come through the airports.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“If we cannot secure and maintain our infrastructure, it will reflect very badly on us.’’</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He also directed the ministry to speed up all processes and projects relating to the safety and security of Nigeria’s air transport system and that counterpart funding for the upgrading of the international airports in Lagos, Abuja, Kano, Port Harcourt and Enugu, be captured in the 2016 budget.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Permanent Secretary in the ministry, Mrs. Binta Bello, told the President that the five new international airport terminal buildings were designed to meet the best international standards.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The terminals, she said, could cater for 62 million passengers annually when completed in the first quarter of 2016, with Lagos moving from seven million passengers’ capacity to 25 million, Abuja moving from five to 16 million, while Kano, Port Harcourt and Enugu, will have the capacity for seven million passengers each.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Meanwhile, the Presidency said on Wednesday that the total amount expended on the recent United States trip by Buhari was less than 10 per cent of the N2.2bn being speculated in the media.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Senior Special Assistant to the President on Media and Publicity, Garba Shehu, disclosed this in a statement.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Shehu was reacting to an editorial published by a newspaper (not <em>The PUNCH</em>) in which the total cost of Buhari’s trip was estimated at N2.2 bn.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The presidential aide said contrary to the newspaper’s assertions, the total cost of the trip to the Nigerian taxpayer was “at the most minimal” in line with the policy of the present administration to cut waste and extravagance.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He said, “In point of fact, the total amount expended on the trip by the Office of the President amounted to nothing near 10 per cent of the speculated figure.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“Owing to the free accommodation provided by the host government, all the personal staff who accompanied the President on the trip received reduced allowances.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“His son, Yusuf, received neither allowances nor estacode. The five governors on the trip each paid his own way.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“Permanent Secretaries who travelled on the delegation did so in accordance with extant rules and none of them exceeded their estacode entitlements.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Shehu also said it was wrong to claim that the trip achieved nothing, saying the Nigerian-US relations had suffered severely over the past few years but that the relationship had been restored.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He said the benefits of the symbiotic relationship would become more evident as the Buhari administration continued to tackle the challenges of corruption, security and the economy.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“Some of the more immediate benefits of the President’s trip to the US include the proposed $2.1bn fund from the World Bank for the re-development of the North-East battered by Boko Haram; $5bn from the US investors in Nigeria’s agricultural sector; $1.5bn investment in the Nigerian health sector; and another $5bn investment from the US in our country’s power sector.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“Also, as things stand at the moment, the embargo on the sale of weapons to Nigeria is in the process of being removed.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“The trip to the US by President Buhari was definitely very successful and beneficial to Nigeria.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“Only those rabidly determined to find faults unnecessarily will cook up falsehood in a futile effort to rake up murk where none exists.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">
<p style="text-align: justify;">
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/?p=341251/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/President-Muhammadu-Buhari6-360x225.jpg" width="360" height="225" />			</item>
					
	<item>
		<title>Duke headlines The Interview roll-out</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/duke-headlines-the-interview-roll-out/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/duke-headlines-the-interview-roll-out/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 23:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341264</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" />A new magazine focused on leading professionals and politicians will be in circulation by Monday, August 10. The magazine, called The Interview, will be a monthly, with the major stories rendered in Q &amp; A format and published by Banc &amp; All, an Abuja-based content and publishing company. The maiden edition headlines among other premium...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/duke-headlines-the-interview-roll-out/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" /><p style="text-align: justify">A new magazine focused on leading professionals and politicians will be in circulation by Monday, August 10.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The magazine, called The Interview, will be a monthly, with the major stories rendered in Q &amp; A format and published by Banc &amp; All, an Abuja-based content and publishing company.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The maiden edition headlines among other premium content, an interview with former Governor Donald Duke in which he shed new light on two former Nigerian presidents – Umaru Yar’Adua and Goodluck Jonathan – and sounds a note of warning to the governing APC.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">It also features a no-holds-barred interview with the CEO of Channels TV, Mr. John Momoh; the brave new world of virtual and augmented reality; and Nigeria Icon List.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">A statement by the Managing Director/Editor-In-Chief, Mr. Azu Ishiekwene, said, “The Interview will provide answers and solutions to the questions that affect the lives, well-being and aspirations of its readers and consumers in a style and language that fit their busy lifestyles.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“It will be a magazine that consumers, especially young professionals, can connect with and to which they can look to for answers to burning questions. Our aim is to be retailers of premium content and a strong catalyst for sharing.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">In a pre-roll out comment, journalism professor at Bradley University, Peoria, Illinois and Nigeria’s number one satirist, Olatunji Dare, said the magazine, “deserves to be well received.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Journalist, former publisher of Citizen magazine and leading columnist, Mohammed Haruna, described the debut, as “simply great.” He commended the quality of the interviews and the columns.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The Founder/CEO of Cable Newspaper Ltd, Mr. Simon Kolawole, said, “The Interview has arrived on the scene in time to douse the growing belief that there is no more room in the ‘Inn’.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em>“With its creative layout, fluid writing, quality interviews and exciting subject mix. </em>The Interview<em>, in my opinion, offers the best chance to revive the sagging interest in our magazine industry. It’s a combination of beauty and brains.”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/duke-headlines-the-interview-roll-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" height="90" />			</item>
		<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Director-General-Lagos-Chamber-of-Commerce-and-Industry-Mr.-Muda-Yusuf-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Director-General, Lagos Chamber of Commerce and Industry, Mr. Muda Yusuf" />	<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Director-General-Lagos-Chamber-of-Commerce-and-Industry-Mr.-Muda-Yusuf-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Director-General, Lagos Chamber of Commerce and Industry, Mr. Muda Yusuf" />		
	<item>
		<title>Unveil your economic plan now, LCCI urges Buhari</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/unveil-your-economic-plan-now-lcci-urges-buhari/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/unveil-your-economic-plan-now-lcci-urges-buhari/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 23:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business & Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341290</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Director-General-Lagos-Chamber-of-Commerce-and-Industry-Mr.-Muda-Yusuf.jpg" width="210" height="212" />The Lagos Chamber of Commerce and Industry says it is not comfortable with the present approach of the Federal Government to economic issues, which has continued to diminish investors’ confidence. It, therefore, demanded an immediate release of the economic blueprint of the President Muhammadu Buhari administration, just as the council urged the government to constitute...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/unveil-your-economic-plan-now-lcci-urges-buhari/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Director-General-Lagos-Chamber-of-Commerce-and-Industry-Mr.-Muda-Yusuf.jpg" width="210" height="212" /><p style="text-align: justify">The Lagos Chamber of Commerce and Industry says it is not comfortable with the present approach of the Federal Government to economic issues, which has continued to diminish investors’ confidence.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">It, therefore, demanded an immediate release of the economic blueprint of the President Muhammadu Buhari administration, just as the council urged the government to constitute an economic team to facilitate the new policy direction.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">These were the highpoints of the LCCI’s resolutions at its meeting held in Lagos on Wednesday, according to a communique signed by its Director-General, Mr. Muda Yusuf.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The meeting, which was presided over by its Chairman, Mr. Remi Aluko, deliberated on the state of the economy, the business and the economic conditions, and the fiscal outlook of the country.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">It noted that there was no clarity yet in the policy direction of the government in relations to the economy, which it described as a major factor in investors’ confidence.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“The uncertainty that began in January this year seems to have lingered. Council urged the Buhari administration to make a clear pronouncement with respect to its fiscal policy, foreign exchange policy, tax policy, subsidy policy, trade policy, reform of oil and gas sector (upstream and downstream), the power sector, the 2015 budget, the auto policy, sectoral policies, etc. All these are necessary for investors to have a clear insight into the policy direction of the government and take strategic investment decisions,” it stated.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Although the LCCI acknowledged the efforts of the Central Bank of Nigeria to protect the foreign reserves and stabilise the exchange rate, it disagreed with the bank’s strategies.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">It said, “The current model of foreign exchange management by the CBN has profound negative consequences for investors’ confidence and the stability of the foreign exchange market.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“Council, therefore, calls for a more strategic framework for the management of the foreign exchange market. Council urged the President of the Federal Republic of Nigeria to quickly set up an economic team that will interface with the CBN, the organised private sector and the key economic ministries to come up with a sustainable model for the management of the foreign exchange market.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The LCCI, which expressed concern over the weak capacity of state and local governments to meet their financial obligations, however, commended the recent intervention of the Federal government in mitigating the conditions.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“The current situation underscores the imperative of economic diversification and prudent management of state resources,” it stated.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">It also commented on the new administration’s efforts at blocking all fiscal leakages and recovering looted funds, saying these were commendable and urged that appropriate structures and institutions “should be put in place at all levels of government to sustain the integrity and transparency of public sector transactions.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">
<p style="text-align: justify">
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/unveil-your-economic-plan-now-lcci-urges-buhari/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Director-General-Lagos-Chamber-of-Commerce-and-Industry-Mr.-Muda-Yusuf.jpg" width="210" height="212" />			</item>
		<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Festus-Odimegwu-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Festus Odimegwu" />	<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Festus-Odimegwu-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Festus Odimegwu" />		
	<item>
		<title>Court strikes out arrest warrant against Odimegwu</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/court-strikes-out-arrest-warrant-against-odimegwu/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/court-strikes-out-arrest-warrant-against-odimegwu/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 23:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341292</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Festus-Odimegwu-360x393.jpg" width="360" height="393" />An Imo State high court sitting in the Orlu division of the state has set aside an arrest warrant earlier issued by an Orsu Magistrate’s court against the former Chairman of the National Population Commission, Festus Odimegwu, saying he was never an accused in the matter for which a warrant of arrest was issued. An...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/court-strikes-out-arrest-warrant-against-odimegwu/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Festus-Odimegwu-360x393.jpg" width="360" height="393" /><p style="text-align: justify">An Imo State high court sitting in the Orlu division of the state has set aside an arrest warrant earlier issued by an Orsu Magistrate’s court against the former Chairman of the National Population Commission, Festus Odimegwu, saying he was never an accused in the matter for which a warrant of arrest was issued.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">An Orsu Chief Magistrate’s court presided over by Mr. G.C. Okoli had issued a warrant of arrest on the former chairman of National Population Commission for allegedly refusing to appear before the court to answer charges bordering on conspiracy and stealing.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">However, delivering judgment in the suit HOR/33/2015 between Festus Odimegwu and the Imo State Commissioner of Police and Other, Hon. Justice L.C .Azama Said, “In this case the applicant has prayed this Court to quash the proceedings of the Orsu Magistrate Court sitting at Awo Idemili over the Order of that Court for the arrest of the applicant on the ground that the said court acted ultra vires its powers in that the person of the applicant against whom the said order for arrest was directed, was not made an accused person before the said order was made over a matter he knew next to nothing about. Applicant exhibited his application Exhibit B, which is the charge sheet before the Magistrate which contains the names of the following persons namely: Moses Okafor, Ichie Ezenwata Peter Obidike, Innocent Edom, Orji Boniface.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“All of which have nothing to do with the identity of the applicant whose names are given as Eze Festus Odimegwu. It was also shown that not even the Police thought it fit to invite the applicant over any allegation of crime against him let alone arresting him for same before the court below came into the matter to do what the police did not see fit to do.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Justice Azuama further ruled that “an order for arrest is not an invitation, it has a coercive effect and power and capable of abridging the fundamental right of a citizen and to make such order without the opportunity given to the person effected or to be effected or by it to be heard on the matter before it is made runs against the dictate of natural justice and constitution of the Federal Republic of Nigeria as amended.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">
<p style="text-align: justify">
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/court-strikes-out-arrest-warrant-against-odimegwu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Festus-Odimegwu-360x393.jpg" width="360" height="393" />			</item>
					
	<item>
		<title>Gulf of Guinea: Buhari orders takeover of Nigeria’s airspace</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/gulf-of-guinea-buhari-orders-takeover-of-nigerias-airspace/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/gulf-of-guinea-buhari-orders-takeover-of-nigerias-airspace/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 23:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341260</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" />President Muhammadu Buhari on Wednesday ordered the Ministry of Aviation to immediately take over the process of securing the management of the airspace over the Gulf of Guinea from Ghana. He also directed the ministry to look into the possibility of getting a national carrier for the country as soon as possible. The ministry’s Permanent...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/gulf-of-guinea-buhari-orders-takeover-of-nigerias-airspace/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" /><p style="text-align: justify">President Muhammadu Buhari on Wednesday ordered the Ministry of Aviation to immediately take over the process of securing the management of the airspace over the Gulf of Guinea from Ghana.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">He also directed the ministry to look into the possibility of getting a national carrier for the country as soon as possible.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The ministry’s Permanent Secretary, Mrs. Binta Bello, told State House correspondents that Buhari handed down the directives when she and her team briefed him of their activities at the Presidential Villa, Abuja.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Bello said Ghana had been maintaining the airspace over the Gulf of Guinea since 1945.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">She said the President’s directive for the takeover by Nigeria came at a time when some other neighbouring countries were making moves to take over their own airspace too.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“We have a directive by the President to start the process of securing the management of the Nigerian airspace over the Gulf of Guinea which Ghana has been maintaining since 1945 and there is a move on the ground by Togo and Republic of Benin to take over their own airspace from Ghana,” Bello said.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">She added that the President also raised concerns over the country’s inability to have a national carrier.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">To that end, Bello said Buhari directed her ministry to look at the possibility of having a national carrier as soon as possible.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“The President is quite concerned about lack of a national carrier for now and he has directed the ministry to look into the possibility of having a national carrier as soon as possible,” she added.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The Permanent Secretary added that she briefed the President on the four international terminal buildings that were being constructed across the country.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">She said the buildings would be ready for inauguration at the end of the first quarter of 2016.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">She said, “We briefed the President on the four international terminal buildings that are being constructed using the China NEXIM Bank loan.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“They are very big projects that are 100 per cent being funded by China NEXIM Bank and DMO. Work is progressing very well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“The terminals will be ready for inauguration at the end of the first quarter of 2016. At the completion of the projects, Nigerians will appreciate the works that have been put into them.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">“The capacity of the terminal would have been expanded to contain big aircraft such as the A380 Air Bus and there will be a lot of commercial activities that are obtainable in other international airports.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Bello added that she also briefed Buhari on the challenges domestic airlines were facing despite the Federal Government’s N300bn intervention fund.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">She regretted that despite the intervention, many of the airlines were still heavily indebted to regulatory agencies.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em>She reassured Nigerians and the international community that Nigeria’s airspace was safe and had recorded a score of over 90 per cent from the International Civil Aviation Organisation.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/gulf-of-guinea-buhari-orders-takeover-of-nigerias-airspace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/App-logo.png" width="90" height="90" />			</item>
		<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/arrested-boko-haram-members-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Suspected Boko Haram members arrested by Civilian JTF in Kodunga, Borno State" />	<img width="100" height="100" src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/arrested-boko-haram-members-100x100.jpg" class="attachment-categoryimage wp-post-image" alt="Suspected Boko Haram members arrested by Civilian JTF in Kodunga, Borno State" />		
	<item>
		<title>Boko Haram kill seven in Borno communities</title>
		<link>http://www.punchng.com/news/boko-haram-kill-seven-in-borno-communities/</link>
		<comments>http://www.punchng.com/news/boko-haram-kill-seven-in-borno-communities/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 23:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.punchng.com/?p=341266</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/arrested-boko-haram-members-360x223.jpg" width="360" height="223" />Seven people were killed in fresh attacks on four communities by the Boko Haram terrorist sect in Borno State. A security source told our correspondent that the murderous sect attacked Malari community and three other neighbouring communities in Konduga Local Government Area in central Borno. A soldier, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said the...&nbsp;<a href="http://www.punchng.com/news/boko-haram-kill-seven-in-borno-communities/">[Read More...]</a>]]></description>
		
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/arrested-boko-haram-members-360x223.jpg" width="360" height="223" /><p style="text-align: justify;">Seven people were killed in fresh attacks on four communities by the Boko Haram terrorist sect in Borno State.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A security source told our correspondent that the murderous sect attacked Malari community and three other neighbouring communities in Konduga Local Government Area in central Borno.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A soldier, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said the attacks which occurred on Monday night left several persons injured.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Also speaking on condition of anonymity, a member of a vigilance group in one of the communities said that the insurgents first attacked Malari and Kaleri before moving to other communities</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The vigilance member said, “The casualty was minimal because people fled as soon as they heard about the Malari attack. That is why the casualty figure is seven.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">‘Our men counted the corpses when they went to evacuate the injured ones after the Monday attack.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A politician from the area, Mr. Bukar Dalori, told Governor Kashim Shettima on Wednesday during a visit to the area that about 1,000 people have been displaced by the Monday attacks.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“The attacks were coordinated against our people as Boko Haram invaded Malari, Kaleri and other places nearby,” Dalori said.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Over 600 villagers were seen at a public primary school near Malari on Wednesday during the governor’s visit.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Meanwhile, four suspected members of the terrorist group have been arrested by members of a vigilance group in a raid on suspected hideouts.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A member of the youth vigilance group, Ibrahim Modu, told our correspondent that the arrests were made on Wednesday by youths in Malari village.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He said, “All the four suspects who are indigenes of Malari village were disowned and exposed by their families when they returned to the village.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Modu revealed that upon interrogation one of the suspects revealed his affiliation with the killer group.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The suspects were paraded before the governor who visited the area.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>Copyright PUNCH.</strong></em><strong><em><br />
</em></strong><em>All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Contact: </strong><a href="mailto:editor@punchng.com"><strong>editor@punchng.com</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">
]]></content:encoded>
	
		<wfw:commentRss>http://www.punchng.com/news/boko-haram-kill-seven-in-borno-communities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
								<media:thumbnail url="http://punch.cdn.ng/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/arrested-boko-haram-members-360x223.jpg" width="360" height="223" />			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
<!-- CDN Linker <https://github.com/wmark/CDN-Linker/tags> active -->